[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
SPEAKER 1: All right.
好的。
So this is CS50, and this is week four.
所以这是 CS50，这是第四周。
And this is actually one of the weeks that
实际上，这是其中一周，
really makes CS50, CS50, insofar as we'll
真正让 CS50 成为了 CS50，因为我们将会
take an even lower level look at how computers work,
从更低的层次来了解计算机是如何工作的，
and in turn, what it is you're doing when you write code
进而了解当你编写代码时，你在做什么
toward an end of really giving you a complete mental model of what's
最终目标是给你一个完整的计算机内部运行的思维模型，以便
going on inside, so that when you run to solve some problem, when you want
当你运行代码来解决某个问题时，当你想要
to fix, solve some problem, when you want to write some code,
修复，解决某个问题时，当你想要编写一些代码时，
you actually know what those building blocks inside of the computer
你实际上会知道计算机内部的那些构建块
itself actually are.
到底是什么。
We'll, ultimately, too, take off some of the training wheels
最终，我们还会去掉一些辅助轮
that we've had on for the past few weeks, particularly in C,
我们在过去几周一直使用的，尤其是在 C 语言中，
and we'll also introduce more familiar media types.
我们还会介绍更多熟悉的媒体类型。
So files, like images are sort of everywhere.
所以，像图片这样的文件无处不在。
And we'll introduce you to exactly what's
我们会带你了解当你看到一张照片，或者一个 GIF 时，
going on when you just look at a photograph, or a GIF,
或者一个 PNG，或者你屏幕上看到的任何图像，比如这里这个。
or a PNG, or any kind of image on your screen like this one here.
到底发生了什么。
And it will become clear that, unlike Hollywood TV shows and movies,
你会发现，与好莱坞的电视剧和电影不同，
if you try to enhance a picture like this
如果你想增强像这样的图片
to look closer, and closer, and closer, in the movies typically
越来越近，越来越近，在电影中通常
trying to figure out who the bad guy is, for instance, eventually,
试图找出谁是坏人，例如，最终，
you run out of information because there's only a finite number of bits
你会发现没有更多信息，因为构成这些文件的比特数是有限的
or bytes that compose these files.
或字节。
So any time you've seen computers that you just
所以，当你看到计算机仅仅
hit a button, and boom, it's enhanced, and all of a sudden the suspect
按下按钮，砰的一声，画面就被增强了，突然之间嫌疑人
is clear, that's a lot more Hollywood than it is computer science.
就很清晰了，这比计算机科学更像好莱坞电影。
But with that said, later in the term, we
但话说回来，在本学期后期，我们会
will talk about artificial intelligence.
谈论人工智能。
And even though there might not be that information there,
即使那里可能没有那些信息，
through statistical reasoning, and modeling, and predictions,
通过统计推理、建模和预测，
can computers increasingly actually create
计算机可以越来越多地创建
information, where perhaps there was none, just based
信息，即使可能之前没有，仅仅基于
on what's most likely to be there?
最有可能存在的东西？
So more on that before long, too.
所以很快我们会详细讲解。
But you'll see that all of these dots on the screen, all of these pixels,
但你会发现屏幕上的所有这些点，所有这些像素，
so to speak, are just a grid up, down, left, right that
可以这么说，只是一张上下左右的网格，
compose these pictures.
构成这些图片。
And we're fortunate to have three volunteers on stage who
我们很幸运有三位志愿者在台上，
kindly, just before the lecture began, created their own pixel artwork,
在讲座开始前，他们很友好地创作了自己的像素艺术作品，
so to speak, on this here easel.
可以这么说，在这个画架上。
If you guys would like to spin this around,
如果你们愿意把它转过来，
let's see what it is you've been working on.
让我们看看你们一直在做些什么。
And if you'd like to introduce yourselves as our three artists
如果你愿意介绍一下你们自己，作为我们今天的三位艺术家
today, first.
首先。
SPEAKER 2: Yes, I'm Talia.
好的，我是塔莉娅。
I'm a junior at the college studying economics with a possible computer
我是一名大三学生，在大学学习经济学，可能会辅修计算机，
science secondary.
科学中学。
SPEAKER 3: Hi.
演讲者 3：你好。
My name is Bulut.
我的名字是 Bulut。
I'm from BU.
我来自 BU。
SPEAKER 1: Welcome.
演讲者 1：欢迎。
SPEAKER 4: I'm a Assalo Caesar, self-taught computer science student.
演讲者 4：我叫 Assalo Caesar，是一位自学成才的计算机科学学生。
I've been working as a software engineer since age 16.
我从 16 岁起就开始做软件工程师。
SPEAKER 1: Nice.
演讲者 1：不错。
Well, welcome to you all.
欢迎大家。
And if you would like to give us a description of what it
如果你想描述一下你
is that you built out of pixels here.
用像素构建的东西。
SPEAKER 2: So we built a firework.
演讲者 2：我们制作了一支烟花。
SPEAKER 1: OK, nice.
演讲者 1：好的，不错。
And it's very blocky because what we've given
而且它非常块状，因为我们给他们的
them is post-it notes, each of which represents one of these pixels or dots.
是便利贴，每个便利贴代表这些像素或点中的一个。
Now, typically, it might be black or white,
通常，它可能是黑色或白色，
but the post-it notes we have here are pink or blue.
但我们这里的便利贴是粉色或蓝色。
So each of these represents a dot on the screen.
所以这些中的每一个代表屏幕上的一个点。
And I gather you did one other that actually
我听说你们还做了一个，它实际上
conveys maybe a bit more information, if you want to reveal version two.
可能传递了更多信息，如果你想展示版本二。
And thus we have yet more pixel art.
因此，我们还有更多的像素艺术。
So maybe round of applause for what our volunteers were able to do using
所以，也许大家可以为我们的志愿者用
pixels alone.
像素做出的东西鼓掌。
Thank you.
谢谢。
We have, as always, limited supply of delicious Super Mario Brothers
我们，一如既往，供应有限的美味超级马里奥兄弟
Oreos for each of you.
奥利奥，每人一块。
Thank you so much for coming up.
非常感谢你们的参与。
But thank you.
但谢谢你们。
But the point here, really, is that there's
但重点是，真的，就是只有
only so much you can do when you just have dots on the screen.
在屏幕上只有点的时候，你所能做的事情有限。
Now, of course, the image that we saw a moment ago of these
当然，我们刚才看到的那个
here stress balls is much higher quality.
减压球的图片质量要高得多。
It's much higher fidelity, or more specifically, much higher resolution.
它的保真度要高得多，或者更准确地说，分辨率要高得多。
And resolution just refers to how many dots or pixels are on the screen.
而分辨率指的是屏幕上有多少个点或像素。
And the smaller they are, and the more you
它们越小，你塞得越多
cram in on the screen, the clearer, and clearer the images are.
在屏幕上，图像就越清晰。
But at the end of the day, even this here pixel art
但归根结底，即使是这像素艺术
represents what's going on your phone, your laptop, your desktop, your TV
也代表了你的手机、笔记本电脑、台式机、电视
nowadays, because all it is this grid of pixels.
现在的显示原理，因为它们都是由像素网格组成的。
Now, before we can actually write code that actually manipulates
现在，在我们实际编写代码来操作之前
these kinds of images, we need to understand,
这些类型的图像，我们需要理解，
and we need to have some new syntax for navigating files.
我们需要一些新的语法来导航文件。
So not just text, but files stored somewhere on the computer,
所以不仅仅是文本，还有存储在计算机上的文件，
somewhere on the server.
存储在服务器上。
But let's consider how we might store even information like this.
但是让我们考虑一下我们如何存储像这样的信息。
But we'll make it simpler.
但我们将把它简化。
Here is a grid of zeros and ones, clearly.
这里是一个零和一的网格，很明显。
But I would argue that each of these might as well represent
但我认为这些中的每一个也可能代表
a pixel, an individual dot.
一个像素，一个单独的点。
And if that dot is a zero, it's representing the color black.
如果那个点是零，它就代表黑色。
If that dot is a one, it's representing the color white.
如果那个点代表的是1，它代表的颜色是白色。
Given that, can anyone see what this grid is a picture of,
考虑到这一点，有人能看出来这个网格代表的图片是什么吗？
even though it's using zeros and ones and not post-it notes, like this here?
即使它使用的是零和一而不是便利贴，就像这里一样？
Yeah, in the back?
是的，在后面？
It's a smiley face.
这是一个笑脸。
How do you see that?
你怎么看出来的？
Well, in a moment it's going to be super obvious.
嗯，过一会儿就会非常明显了。
But if I actually get rid of the ones, leaving just the zeros,
但是如果我把所有的1去掉，只留下0，
there you have the zeros that were there just a moment ago.
现在你看到的这些0，就是刚才那些1的位置。
So what this translates to, typically on a screen,
所以，这通常在屏幕上显示的，
is not a pattern of zeros and ones literally on the screen,
并不是屏幕上真正显示的零和一的模式，
but a pattern of dots.
而是一系列点的模式。
So again, white might be one, and black might be--
所以，再次强调，白色可能是1，黑色可能是——
one might be white.
1可能是白色。
Zero might be black.
0可能是黑色。
But we picture it, of course, on our screens as this actual grid.
当然，我们把它们想象成我们屏幕上的实际网格。
But that's really all we need.
但这确实是我们需要的全部。
Inside of a file to store something like an image,
在一个用于存储像图像这样的东西的文件中，
we just need a pattern of zeros and ones.
我们只需要一个零和一的模式。
But of course, having more colors would be more interesting.
当然，拥有更多颜色会更有趣。
And if you actually have a larger grid, you can do even more with pixel art.
如果你真的有更大的网格，你就可以用像素艺术做更多的事情。
And in fact for fun, at the beginning of the semester,
实际上，为了好玩，在学期开始的时候，
we have a staff training with all of the teaching fellows, course assistants,
我们对所有的助教、课程助理，
teaching assistants, and we gave them all this Google spreadsheet.
助教进行了培训，并给他们每个人发了这个谷歌表格。
And we sort of resized all of the rows and columns
我们调整了所有行和列的尺寸
to just be squares instead of the default rectangles.
让它们变成正方形，而不是默认的矩形。
And then we encouraged them to create something out of this.
然后我们鼓励他们用这个表格创作一些东西。
And in fact, just a few weeks ago, here are some of this year's creations,
实际上，就在几周前，这里有一些今年的创作，
creating, essentially, images using Google Spreadsheets
用谷歌表格创建，本质上，是图片
by treating each of the cells as just a dot on the screen.
通过把每个单元格看作是屏幕上的一个点。
So here, we have a team who in a few minutes
所以，这里，我们有一个团队，他们在几分钟内
made a Super Mario World, a bigger canvas, of course,
制作了一个超级马里奥世界，当然，画布更大，
than this here easel.
比这里的画架更大。
Here we have a pixel based version of Scratch.
这里，我们有一个基于像素的Scratch版本。
Here, we had an homage to the Harvard-Yale football competition.
这里，我们对哈佛-耶鲁橄榄球比赛致敬。
And then here, we had a character of some sort.
然后，这里，我们有一个人物。
So this is what the team here did.
所以，这就是这个团队做的。
And actually, if you'd like to play along at home
实际上，如果你想在家玩
at the risk of distracting you the entirety of lecture,
冒着让你整堂课分心的风险，
if you go to this URL here, it'll actually give you
如果你访问这里这个网址，它实际上会给你
a copy of that same blank spreadsheet.
一个相同的空白表格的副本。
But let's talk about representing, not just zeros and ones,
但让我们谈谈如何表示，不仅仅是零和一，
and black and white, but actual colors.
还有黑色和白色，而是实际的颜色。
And so recall from week zero when we talked
所以，还记得我们在第零周讲到的
about how to represent information, colors among,
关于如何表示信息，包括颜色，
them we introduced RGB, which stands for red, green, blue.
我们介绍了RGB，代表红色、绿色、蓝色。
And it's just this kind of convention of using some amount of red,
它只是使用一定量的红色，的一种约定，
some amount of green, and some amount of blue mixed together to give you
绿色和蓝色的混合量，混合在一起就能得到
the actual color that you want.
你想要的实际颜色。
Well, it turns out in the world of computers,
事实证明，在计算机的世界里，
there's a standard way for describing those amounts of red, green, and blue.
有一种标准的方式来描述红、绿、蓝的这些量。
At the end of the day, it's of course just bits.
最终，它只是位。
And equivalently, it's just numbers, like 72, 73,
同样，它也只是一些数字，例如72，73，
33 was the arbitrary example we used in week zero for the color yellow.
33是我们在第零周中使用的黄色颜色示例。
But there actually tends to be a different notation by convention
但实际上，按照惯例，通常会有一种不同的表示法
for representing colors that we'll actually see today, too,
来表示我们今天要看到的颜色，
as we explore the world of memory.
当我们探索内存的世界时。
So here's a screenshot of Photoshop.
这是Photoshop的截图。
If you've never used it before, this is like the color picker
如果你以前从未使用过它，它就像颜色选择器
that you can pull up, just to pick any number of millions of colors
你可以调出来，用来选择数百万种颜色中的任意一种
by clicking and dragging, or typing in numbers.
通过单击和拖动，或者输入数字。
But notice down here.
但请注意这里。
We've picked at the moment the color black by moving
我们现在选择了黑色，方法是移动
the slider all the way down here to the bottom left hand corner.
滑块到左下角。
And what this user interface is telling us
这个用户界面告诉我们
is that there's zero red, zero green, zero blue.
这里没有红色，没有绿色，没有蓝色。
And a conventional way of writing this on a screen
在屏幕上写这个的传统方法是
would be, literally, a hash symbol, and then three pairs of digits.
字面上，一个井号，然后三对数字。
zero, zero for red, zero, zero for green, zero, zero for blue.
红色为0，0，绿色为0，0，蓝色为0，0。
If by contrast, you were to pick the color, say, white in Photoshop,
相反，如果你在Photoshop中选择白色，
it gets a little weird.
它就有点奇怪了。
Now it's a lot of red, a lot of green, a lot of blue, as you might expect,
现在它有很多红色，很多绿色，很多蓝色，正如你所料，
cranking all of those values up.
把所有这些值都调高。
But the way you write it conventionally is not using decimal,
但你通常使用的方式不是十进制，
but using letters of the alphabet, it would seem here.
而是使用字母，至少看起来是这样。
So FF for red, FF, for Green, FF for blue.
所以红色是FF，绿色是FF，蓝色是FF。
More on that in a moment.
稍后详细介绍。
When it comes to representing red, here's a lot of red, 255.
说到红色，这里有很多红色，255。
Zero green, zero blue.
绿色为0，蓝色为0。
And so the pattern is now FF0000.
所以，现在模式是FF0000。
Before I reveal what green is, what probably should it be?
在我揭示绿色是什么之前，它应该是什么？
What pattern?
什么模式？
Yeah.
是的。
Close.
接近了。
Not 0000FF, but 00FF00 because it seems to be following this pattern, indeed,
不是0000FF，而是00FF00，因为它似乎确实遵循了这种模式，
from left to right of red, green, blue.
从左到右，分别是红色，绿色，蓝色。
So zero red, 255 green, zero blue, and thus 00FF00.
所以是红色为0，绿色为255，蓝色为0，因此是00FF00。
And then lastly, if we do solid blue, it's zero red, zero green,
最后，如果我们选择纯蓝色，那就是红色为0，绿色为0，
a lot of blue, and thus 0000FF.
很多蓝色，因此是0000FF。
So somehow or other, FF is apparently representing the number 255.
所以，FF似乎以某种方式代表了数字255。
And we'll see why in just a moment.
我们会马上看到原因。
But recall that in the world of computers,
但请记住，在计算机的世界里，
they just speak zeros and ones.
它们只说0和1。
And we've seen that already in black and white form.
我们在黑白形式中已经看到了这一点。
We of course, in the real world, tend to use decimal instead of binary.
当然，在现实世界中，我们倾向于使用十进制而不是二进制。
So we have 10 digits at our disposal, zero through nine.
所以我们有 10 个数字可以使用，从零到九。
But it turns out that in the world of graphics and colors,
但事实证明，在图形和颜色领域，
turns out in the world of computer memory,
事实证明，在计算机内存领域，
it tends to be convenient not to use binary, per se, not to use decimal,
它往往更方便，不使用二进制，严格来说，也不使用十进制，
per se, but to use something called hexadecimal,
而是使用一种叫做十六进制的东西，
where as soon as you need more than 10 digits total,
当您需要超过 10 个数字时，
you start stealing from the English alphabet.
就开始从英文字母表中偷取。
So the next few numbers, or digits rather,
所以接下来的几个数字，或者更确切地说是数字，
are A, B, C, D, E, F. And there's other systems that
是 A、B、C、D、E、F。 还有其他系统，
use even more letters of the alphabet, but this is probably
使用更多字母表中的字母，但这可能是
the last we'll discuss in any detail.
我们将详细讨论的最后一个。
So in this case, we have a total of 10 plus one, two, three, four, five,
所以在这个例子中，我们总共有 10 加上 1、2、3、4、5，
six, so 16 total, a.k.a.
六，所以总共有 16 个，也就是
hexadecimal, or what we might call base 16.
十六进制，或者我们可以称之为 16 进制。
And the capitalization actually doesn't matter.
而且大小写实际上并不重要。
It's conventional to use uppercase or lowercase,
通常使用大写或小写，
so long as you're generally consistent.
只要你大体上保持一致。
So hexa, implying 16, decimal.
所以 hexa，表示 16，十进制。
So hexadecimal notation here, or otherwise known as base 16,
所以这里的十六进制表示法，或者也称为 16 进制，
for mathematical reasons that go back to our discussion in week zero.
因为数学原因，可以追溯到我们第零周的讨论。
So here's some of that same reasoning from week zero.
所以这里是一些来自第零周的相同推理。
How might we go about representing using two
我们如何使用两个
digits in hexadecimal, different numbers that you and I know as decimal?
十六进制数字，你和我所知道的不同的十进制数字？
Well, if we consider this as being the 16 to the zeros place, 16
好吧，如果我们认为这是 16 的零位，16
to the ones place, and if we do out that math, of course,
到一位，如果我们把这个算出来，当然，
that gives us the ones place and the sixteens place.
这给了我们一位和十六位。
So we've only changed the base, not the story from week zero.
所以我们只改变了进制，而不是第零周的故事。
So if we were to start representing actual values in hexadecimal,
所以如果我们开始用十六进制表示实际值，
here are two zeros.
这里有两个零。
So that's 1 times 0 plus 16 times 0, which, of course, gives us
所以这是 1 乘以 0 加上 16 乘以 0，这当然给了我们
the number you and I know is zero.
你我所知道的数字是零。
So in hexadecimal, and in binary, and in decimal, it's
所以在十六进制、二进制和十进制中，它都是
the same way to represent the number you and I know as zero.
用相同的方式表示你我所知道的数字零。
But here now is the number one in hexadecimal.
但这里现在是十六进制中的数字 1。
Here's the number two.
这里是数字 2。
Here's the number three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
这里是数字 3、4、5、6、7、8、9。
So it's identical up until this point to our world of decimal.
所以它一直到这一点都与我们的十进制世界相同。
But how do I count up to what you and I would call 10 in decimal,
但是我如何计数到我们称为十进制的 10 呢，
according to what we're seeing here thus far?
根据我们目前看到的？
Yeah.
是的。
So now it goes up to A, because A would, apparently,
所以现在它上升到 A，因为 A 显然，
represent what you and I know as 10.
表示我们所知道的 10。
B represents 11.
B 代表 11。
C represents 12, 13, 14, 15.
C 代表 12、13、14、15。
How, though, do I count up to 16?
但是，我如何计数到 16 呢？
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
正是。
So not 10, quote unquote, but one, zero because the one
所以不是 10，打引号，而是 1，0，因为这个 1
in the second column here to the left actually represents the sixteens place.
在左边第二列实际上表示十六位。
So it's 16 times 1 gives you 16, plus 1 times 0 gives you 0, so 16 in total.
所以，16 乘以 1 等于 16，加上 1 乘以 0 等于 0，总共是 16。
So this now is the way the number you and I would think of as 17,
所以，这个现在是您和我认为的 17，
18, 19, 20, 21, dot, dot, dot.
18，19，20，21，等等。
And if we go all the way up, as high up as we
如果我们一直往上走，尽可能高，
can count, well, what's the largest digit, apparently, in hexadecimal?
可以计数，那么十六进制中最大的数字是什么？
The smallest is clearly zero, and the biggest I said was F.
最小的显然是零，而我说的最大是 F。
So once you get to FF, the math gets a little annoying.
所以一旦你到了 FF，数学就有点烦人了。
But this is now 16 times 15 plus 1 times 15.
但现在是 16 乘以 15 加上 1 乘以 15。
And what that gives us, actually, is the number you and I know as 255.
而这实际上给了我们一个数字，我们知道它是 255。
So we saw it in Photoshop.
我们在 Photoshop 中看到了它。
We've seen it now in hexadecimal.
我们现在在十六进制中看到了它。
This is not math that you would ever do frequently,
这不是你经常会做的数学运算，
but indeed, it's the exact same system as week zero,
但事实上，它与第零周的系统完全相同，
just with a different base.
只是底数不同。
But why all of this additional complexity?
但为什么会有如此多的复杂性？
Why are we jumping through these hoops introducing yet another one
为什么我们要跳过这些障碍，引入另一个
to give us just some pattern like this of FF?
来给我们提供像 FF 这样的模式？
Well, it turns out that hexadecimal is just convenient.
事实证明，十六进制只是很方便。
Why?
为什么？
Well, if you have 16 digits in your alphabet,
好吧，如果你的字母表中有 16 个数字，
zero through F, how many bits, how many zeros and ones
从零到 F，你需要多少位，多少个零和一
do you need to represent 16 different values?
来表示 16 个不同的值？
It's four, right?
是四个，对吧？
Because if you've got four bits, that's two possibilities for the first times
因为如果你有四位，那就是第一个位的两种可能性乘以
2, times 2, times 2.
2，乘以 2，乘以 2。
So that's 16 possibilities.
所以有 16 种可能性。
2 to the fourth power.
2 的四次方。
And if you've got four bits represented by a single digit,
如果你用一个数字表示四位，
it's just convenient in practice for computer scientists and programmers.
对于计算机科学家和程序员来说，在实践中这只是很方便。
So F might indeed represent 1111.
所以 F 可能确实代表 1111。
But that's not a full byte, which is eight bits.
但这不是一个完整的字节，而是一个字节是八位。
And no one counts in units of four in computing.
在计算中，没有人用四位为单位计数。
It's always in units of, like, eight, or 16, or 32, or 64, or the like.
它总是以八位、十六位、三十二位或六十四位为单位。
So it turns out, though, because hexadecimal lends itself
所以事实证明，由于十六进制适合
to representing four bits at a time, well, if you just use two of them,
一次表示四位，如果你只使用两个，
you can represent eight bits at a time.
你可以一次表示八位。
And eight bits is a byte, which is a common unit of measure.
八位是一个字节，这是一个常用的计量单位。
And this is why even Photoshop uses this convention, as do color programs,
这就是为什么即使 Photoshop 也使用这种约定，颜色程序也是如此，
as does web development, more generally, of using two hexadecimal digits just
web 开发也是如此，更普遍的是，使用两个十六进制数字来表示
to represent single bytes.
单个字节。
Because the one on the left represents the first bits, the first four bits.
因为左边的那个代表第一个位，前四个位。
The one on the right represents the second four bits.
右边的那个代表第二个四个位。
So it's not a big deal, per se.
所以它本身不是什么大事。
It's just convenient, even though this might feel like a lot all at once.
这只是很方便，即使这可能感觉一下子很多。
Any questions then on hexadecimal?
那么关于十六进制还有问题吗？
Yeah, in the middle.
是的，在中间。
No.
没有。
OK, no.
好的，没有。
Questions on hexadecimal.
关于十六进制的问题。
All right.
好的。
So with this system in mind, let's go about considering where else we might
考虑到这个系统，让我们来考虑一下，我们还可以在哪里
see this in the computing world.
在计算机领域看到它。
And I would propose that we consider, as we've done in the past,
我建议我们考虑，就像我们过去所做的那样，
that our computer is really just this grid of memory, for instance,
我们的计算机实际上只是一个内存网格，例如，
where each of these squares represents a single byte.
其中每个方块代表一个字节。
And I proposed a couple of times already that, when
我已经提出过几次，当
we talk about a computer's memory, we can
我们谈论计算机的内存时，我们可以
think of them as each of these squares as having an individual location.
将它们想象成每个方块都有一个单独的位置。
Like, I spitballed back in the day that maybe this is the first byte,
就像我以前随口说的一样，也许这是第一个字节，
the second byte, the third byte.
第二个字节，第三个字节。
Maybe this is the billionth byte, so we can number
也许这是十亿字节，所以我们可以对
of the bytes inside of a computer.
计算机内的字节进行编号。
Well, it turns out, as we'll see today in code,
事实证明，正如我们今天将在代码中看到的那样，
computers typically use numbers, indeed, to represent
计算机通常使用数字，实际上，来表示
all of the bytes in their memory, and they typically
内存中的所有字节，并且它们通常
use hexadecimal notation for such by convention.
按照惯例使用十六进制表示法。
So what do I mean by that?
我的意思是什么？
Technically, if we were to start numbering these
从技术上讲，如果我们要开始对这些
and count at zero, as most programmers would,
进行编号，并且从零开始计数，正如大多数程序员会做的那样，
this is byte zero, one, two, three, dot, dot, dot.
这是字节零、一、二、三，等等。
This is byte 15.
这是字节 15。
But if I wanted to keep going, it would be then 16, 17, 18,
但如果我想继续下去，那将是 16、17、18，
but that's not the true in hexadecimal.
但这在十六进制中并不正确。
So instead in hexadecimal, once you hit the nine,
因此，在十六进制中，一旦你达到九，
you'd actually use A through F, just as I've proposed.
你实际上会使用 A 到 F，正如我提出的那样。
Meanwhile, if you kept going thereafter, you would have one zero.
同时，如果你继续下去，你将有一个零。
But as you noted, this is not 10.
但正如你指出的，这不是 10。
This is 16 here, 17, 18, 19.
这是 16，17、18、19。
And so here's where things get a little weird.
所以，事情在这里变得有点奇怪。
I'm saying 16.
我说的是 16。
I'm saying 17, and you're obviously seeing what any reasonable person would
我说的是 17，很明显，你会看到任何一个理性的人都会
read as 10 and 11.
读作 10 和 11。
So there's this dichotomy, and so we need some convention
所以，存在这种二分法，因此我们需要一些约定
for making clear to the reader that these are hexadecimal numbers, not
让读者清楚地知道这些是十六进制数字，而不是
decimal.
十进制。
Otherwise, it's completely ambiguous.
否则，它完全是模棱两可的。
And the convention there, which you might have seen in the real world,
那里的约定，你可能已经在现实世界中见过，
even though it's a bit weird, is just to prefix hexadecimal numbers with zero X.
尽管有点奇怪，但只是在十六进制数字前面加上零 X。
It's not doing anything mathematically.
它在数学上没有做任何事情。
It's not multiplication or anything like that.
它不是乘法，也不是任何类似的东西。
Just zero X means, here comes a hexadecimal number hereafter, just
只是零 X 表示，接下来将是一个十六进制数字，只是
to distinguish it from decimal.
为了将其与十进制区分开来。
And you can see that, even though we don't have enough room for 255 bytes,
你可以看到，即使我们没有足够的空间容纳 255 个字节，
you start to see patterns that we haven't even
你开始看到我们甚至没有
talked about yet because we're just using those two columns as the ones
谈论过，因为我们只是将这两列作为个位
place, the 16th place, and so forth.
位、十六位，等等。
Capital or uppercase is fine.
大写或小写都可以。
All right.
好的。
So with that said, let's actually do things more technically interesting,
也就是说，让我们做一些技术上更有趣的事情，
like looking back at some code that we've already seen
例如回顾一下我们已经看过的代码
and seeing what we can actually glean from this newfound representation
并看看我们能从这种新发现的表示中获得什么
of memory location.
内存位置。
So I'm going to go over to VS Code here, where I've opened my terminal window,
所以我要去到 VS Code 这里，我已经打开了我的终端窗口，
but no code file yet.
但还没有代码文件。
And I'm going to go ahead and create a file called addresses.c
我要创建一个名为 addresses.c 的文件
because I want to start playing around now with the addresses of information
因为我现在想开始玩弄信息的地址
in my computer.
在我的电脑里。
And to do this, let me do something super simple first.
为了做到这一点，让我先做一些超级简单的事情。
Let me include standard io.h.
让我包含标准 io.h。
Let me do an int main void, no command line arguments.
让我做一个 int main void，没有命令行参数。
And then in here, let me do exactly the line of code we just saw.
然后在这里，让我做我们刚刚看到的代码行。
Declare an int called n, set it equal to a default value of 50.
声明一个名为 n 的整型变量，将其设置为默认值 50。
And just so that the program does something noteworthy,
为了使程序做一些值得注意的事情，
let's have it actually print out %i backslash n,
让它打印出 %i 反斜杠 n，
and plug-in that value of n.
并插入 n 的值。
So this is, like, week one stuff, just creating a variable,
所以这是第一周的内容，只是创建一个变量，
and printing out its value, just to make sure that we're on the same page.
并打印出它的值，以确保我们都在同一个页面上。
So let me do make addresses in my terminal window, enter.
所以让我在我的终端窗口中输入 make addresses，然后回车。
And when I do dot slash addresses, no surprise.
当我输入点斜杠 addresses 时，不出所料。
I should indeed see the number 50.
我应该看到数字 50。
But let's consider what that actually does inside of the computer
但是让我们考虑一下它在计算机内部实际上做了什么
now by flipping over, for instance, to this same line of code,
现在，例如，翻到这一行代码，
and translating it into this same grid.
并将其翻译成相同的网格。
So here's a grid of memory, and I don't necessarily
这是一个内存网格，我不一定
know where in the computer's memory it's going to end up.
知道它会在计算机的哪个内存位置结束。
So I'm picking spots arbitrarily.
所以我随意选择了一些位置。
But I know that an int, typically, is four bytes on most systems.
但我知道在一个整型变量通常在大多数系统中是四个字节。
And so I've used one, two, three, four squares.
所以我使用了 1, 2, 3, 4 个方格。
And the first four that I assume are available are down here,
我假设可用的前四个方格在下面，
and I'm calling this n, and I'm putting the value 50 in it.
我将它命名为 n，并将其值设置为 50。
So literally, when you write that line of code, int n equals 50 semicolon,
所以实际上，当您写下那行代码，int n 等于 50 分号，
the computer's doing something like this underneath the hood.
计算机在幕后做的事情就像这样。
Might be over here, might be over there, but I've drawn it simply down there.
可能在这里，可能在那里，但我简单地把它画在了下面。
But that means that that 50 and that variable n,
但这意味着 50 和变量 n，
in particular, live somewhere in the computer's memory.
尤其是在计算机的内存中。
And where might it live?
它可能住在哪里？
Well, I don't really know.
嗯，我真的不知道。
And frankly, I'm not going to care, ultimately, after today.
坦率地说，今天之后，我最终不会在意。
But let me propose that, if all of these bytes are numbered from zero on down,
但让我假设，如果所有这些字节从零开始向下编号，
maybe this is address OX123, for the sake of discussion.
也许这个地址是 OX123，为了讨论起见。
So it's a hexadecimal number, one, two, three.
所以它是一个十六进制数，1，2，3。
It's not 123.
它不是 123。
It's one, two, three, but in hexadecimal,
它是 1，2，3，但使用十六进制，
just because it's a little easy to say.
仅仅因为它说起来容易。
But that variable n clearly must live at some address.
但很显然，变量n必须存储在某个地址。
So can we maybe see this?
所以我们能看到这个地址吗？
Well, it turns out that in C, there is a bit more syntax we can introduce today
事实证明，在C语言中，我们今天可以引入更多语法
that actually gives you access to the locations of variables
这些语法实际上可以让你访问变量的位置
inside of the computer's memory.
在计算机内存中。
The first of these is literally an ampersand,
第一个符号是“&”，
and you might pronounce that the address of operator.
你可以把它称为取地址符。
Using a single ampersand, you can actually ask the computer
使用一个“&”，你可以直接询问计算机
at what address is this variable.
这个变量的地址在哪。
And then the asterisk here might be known
然后这里的星号可能被称为
as the dereference operator, which allows you to take an address
解引用运算符，它允许你获取一个地址
and go to it, kind of like following a map.
并访问它，就像跟着地图走。
X marks the spot.
X 标记地点。
The star will take you to that location in memory,
星号将带你到内存中的那个位置，
so you can see what's actually there.
这样你就可以看到那里实际存储了什么。
So what do I mean by that?
我的意思是什么呢？
Well, let me go back over to VS Code here, and let me go ahead
好吧，让我回到 VS Code，然后我继续
and change my program to be ever so slightly different, as follows.
修改我的程序，使其略微不同，如下所示。
I'm going to still declare n, just as before, to have the value of 50.
我仍然像以前一样声明 n，使其值为 50。
But instead of printing out an integer, per se,
但我不再输出一个整数，
I'm going to print out an address.
我要输出一个地址。
And it turns out the format code for that, using printf, is %p.
事实证明，使用 printf 输出地址的格式代码是 %p。
And if I want to print out now the address of n,
如果我现在想输出 n 的地址，
recall that I have these two new capabilities, the first of which
请回忆我介绍了两种新功能，其中第一个
is germane.
至关重要。
The ampersand will get me the address of n.
“&” 会获取 n 的地址。
So let me go back now to VS Code, and let me make a change,
所以现在让我回到 VS Code，并进行一个修改，
whereby I'm going to change the %i to %p,
即将 %i 改为 %p，
which is going to show me an address, as opposed to an integer, per se.
这样就会显示地址而不是整数。
But I need to tell printf what address to show, so I don't want to print out n
但我需要告诉 printf 显示哪个地址，所以我不希望输出 n
because that's literally the number 50.
因为它实际上是数字 50。
I want to print out the address of n, like, where is it in memory.
我想要输出 n 的地址，就像，它在内存中的哪个位置。
So here I prefix it with an ampersand.
所以这里我在它前面加上“&”。
And now if I go back into my terminal window, make addresses again,
现在如果我回到我的终端窗口，再次运行 addresses 程序，
dot slash addresses.
./addresses。
I'm not going to get as lucky as seeing OX123, probably,
我可能不会像之前一样幸运地看到 OX123，
because I got even more memory than that in this computer.
因为这台计算机的内存更大。
But when I hit enter, I do indeed see OX something.
但当我按下回车键，我确实看到了 OX 开头的地址。
And if I zoom in here, enhance, if you will,
如果我放大，加强，
it happens to be at this moment in time, on this server, OX7FFC3A7CFFBC.
目前在服务器上，它恰好位于 OX7FFC3A7CFFBC。
So it's a big address.
这是一个很大的地址。
That's a really big number if we actually did all of the math.
如果我们真的算一下，这将是一个很大的数字。
But who really cares?
但谁在乎呢？
Just the fact that it exists somewhere is the only point for now.
目前唯一重要的是它存在于某个地方。
So this %p symbol that we're passing into printf as a format code is
所以，我们传递给 printf 的这个 %p 格式代码
leveraging the fact that C supports what are known as pointers.
利用了 C 语言支持指针这一事实。
So a pointer is really just an address, the address of some variable
所以指针实际上只是一个地址，某个变量的地址
that you can even store in another variable called itself a pointer.
你甚至可以将其存储在另一个名为指针的变量中。
So what do I mean by this?
我的意思是？
Well, if a pointer is an address, we can start to tinker with this same idea
如果指针是一个地址，我们可以开始修改这个想法
as follows.
如下。
Let me actually go back to VS Code once more
让我再回到 VS Code 一次
and play around with syntax like this.
然后尝试这样的语法。
So let me still declare a variable called n and set it equal to 50.
所以让我声明一个名为 n 的变量，并将其设置为 50。
But let's actually create an actual pointer,
但让我们创建一个真正的指针，
a variable whose purpose in life is not to store a boring number like 50,
一个变量，它存在的目的不是存储一个像 50 这样的无聊数字，
but the address of some value.
而是存储某个值的地址。
And so the syntax for that is admittedly weird.
这的语法不可否认地很奇怪。
If you want p to be a pointer, a variable that stores an address,
如果你想让 p 成为一个指针，一个存储地址的变量，
you literally say int star for reasons we'll sort of see.
你就得写 int star，至于为什么，我们等下会看到。
And this is different from the star I mentioned earlier for reasons
这与我之前提到的星号不同，原因
we'll also see soon.
我们很快就会明白。
But int star p means, hey compiler, give me
但 int star p 的意思是，嘿编译器，给我
a variable called p, inside of which I can store the address of an integer.
一个名为 p 的变量，我可以在其中存储一个整数的地址。
What address do you want to put in there?
你想放哪个地址？
Well, now I can borrow that same syntax from a moment ago.
好了，现在我可以借用刚才的语法。
I can use ampersand n, which is going to say, hey compiler, give me-- or hey
我可以使用 &n，它会告诉编译器，嘿，给我 - 或者嘿
computer, give me the address of n itself.
电脑，给我 n 本身的地址。
Previously, I didn't bother with a variable.
之前，我没有使用变量。
I just sent the address of n into printf directly.
我只是直接将 n 的地址发送到 printf。
But I can now play with it as follows.
但我现在可以这样玩。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到 VS Code 这里。
I'll clear my terminal window.
我会清空我的终端窗口。
And let's just play around with two variables.
让我们用两个变量玩玩。
So int star p-- so it's an asterisk, but most people would say star--
所以 int star p - 它是星号，但大多数人会说星号 -
equals the address of n.
等于 n 的地址。
And now, I can just tweak line seven ever so slightly.
现在，我可以稍微调整一下第七行。
Instead of printing out in duplicate ampersand n,
不用重复打印 &n，
I can literally just pass in p for pointer.
我可以直接传入 p 来表示指针。
So I've not done anything really that interesting, other than add a variable,
所以除了添加一个变量，我并没有做任何真正有趣的事情，
but just to show you the syntax via which
但只是为了向你展示语法，通过它
you can create a variable whose purpose in life
你可以创建一个变量，它存在的目的是
is to store one of these addresses.
存储这些地址之一。
So let me go ahead and now and do make addresses once more.
所以让我继续，现在，再次运行 make addresses。
Dot slash addresses.
./addresses
And we should see, indeed, pretty much the same idea, the address
我们应该看到，确实，基本相同的思路，n 所处的地址
at which n happens to be, now that I've recompiled and actually run my code.
现在我已经重新编译并运行了我的代码。
But it gets a little more interesting than that.
但比这更有趣。
I can do one more thing when it comes to my computer's memory.
在计算机内存方面，我还可以做一件事。
In VS Code here, let me clear my terminal again, and let me see
在 VS Code 这里，让我再次清空终端，然后让我看看
if I can perhaps reverse this process.
我是否可以反转这个过程。
If n is 50, and p is storing the address of n,
如果 n 是 50，p 存储 n 的地址，
wouldn't it be interesting if I could somehow express, go to the address of n
如果我可以通过某种方式表示，转到 n 的地址，那不是很酷吗？
and tell me what is there.
并告诉我那里有什么。
So to do that, I'm just kind of undoing all of the intellectual work
所以要做到这一点，我只是在取消所有智力工作
I'm doing here.
我在做的。
But if I want to print out an integer at some location, I can go back to %i,
但如果我想在某个位置打印一个整数，我可以回到 %i，
just print an integer as always.
像往常一样打印一个整数。
But p now is storing the address of someplace.
但现在 p 存储的是某个地方的地址。
It is the treasure map, so to speak.
可以这么说，它就是藏宝图。
So if I want to go where X marks the spot,
所以如果我想去 X 标记的地方，
the syntax for that I claimed a moment ago is star p.
我刚才提到的语法是星号 p。
So star p means go to that address.
所以星号 p 表示转到那个地址。
Don't print the address, go to that address,
不要打印地址，转到那个地址，
and show me what's inside of the computer's memory there.
然后向我展示那里计算机内存中的内容。
So now, if I go into my terminal and do make addresses,
所以现在，如果我进入我的终端并创建地址，
and do dot slash addresses, what should I see on the screen when I hit enter?
然后执行点斜杠地址，当我按下回车键时，我应该在屏幕上看到什么？
50.
50。
So I indeed see now 50.
所以我确实看到了 50。
Now, here's where it's an unfortunate choice of syntax
现在，这就是 C 语言作者几十年前不幸的选择语法
from the authors of C decades ago.
的地方。
Clearly, I'm using star in two different locations.
很明显，我在两个不同的位置使用星号。
And suffice it to say, it doesn't represent multiplication
我只能说，它并不代表乘法
in either of them.
在任何一个中。
It's being used to represent addresses somehow.
它以某种方式被用来表示地址。
When, on line six, I specify a data type like int,
当我在第六行指定一个像 int 这样的数据类型时，
and then I have a star, and then the name of a variable,
然后我有一个星号，然后是一个变量的名称，
that is the syntax for declaring a pointer, for declaring
这就是声明指针的语法，用来声明
a variable that will store an address.
一个将存储地址的变量。
What address?
什么地址？
Well, ampersand n, whatever that is, OX something.
嗯，&n，无论是什么，都是 0X 某样东西。
When you do a star and then the name of a pointer without specifying a type,
当你使用一个星号，然后是一个指针的名称，而没有指定类型时，
this just means, go there.
这只是意味着，去那里。
So the star clearly is related to addresses.
所以星号显然与地址有关。
It's unfortunate that it's the same symbol.
不幸的是，它使用的是同一个符号。
It would have been nice if they picked maybe a different symbol
如果他们选择了可能不同的符号就好了
of punctuation.
的标点符号。
But they mean slightly different things in that context.
但在那种情况下，它们的含义略有不同。
On line six, we're declaring the pointer,
在第六行，我们声明了指针，
declaring a variable called p that's going to point to an integers location.
声明一个名为 p 的变量，它将指向一个整数的位置。
But when I say star p, that means go to that actual location.
但当我使用星号 p 时，这意味着转到那个实际位置。
So just try to keep that in mind, even though it's ever so slightly subtly
所以试着记住这一点，即使它非常细微地略有不同
different.
。
So what's going on then inside of the computer's actual memory?
那么计算机的实际内存中发生了什么呢？
Well, let's consider that in pictorial form again.
好吧，让我们再次以图示形式考虑这个问题。
So even though I've written the pointer in this way,
所以尽管我以这种方式写了指针，
int then a space, then star p equals ampersand n semicolon, that
int 然后是一个空格，然后是星号 p 等于 &n 分号，那就是
is the conventional way.
传统的方法。
That's how you'll see it on most websites, most textbooks.
这就是你在大多数网站、大多数教科书上看到的方式。
Technically speaking, I will admit that it might actually
严格地说，我承认它实际上
be easier to understand if you actually move
更容易理解，如果你真的移动
the asterisk a little to the left, because this makes, visually,
星号稍微向左一点，因为这样从视觉上来说，
I think, it even more clear that int star is the type of the variable p, as
我认为，更清楚的是，int star 是变量 p 的类型，因为
opposed to the star being somehow attached to the variable name itself.
与星号以某种方式附加到变量名本身相反。
However, you might also see it written with a space on either side, which
然而，你可能也看到它在两边都用空格写，这
I don't think really helps anyone.
我认为对任何人都没有帮助。
But the point is that white space does not matter in this context.
但关键是空格在这个上下文中并不重要。
And the conventional way is to do it by prefixing
而常规的做法是用星号作为前缀
the variable's name with the star.
变量名。
And this avoids getting into trouble when you
这样可以避免你在
declare multiple variables at a time.
一次声明多个变量时遇到麻烦。
But if it helps you to think about it, you can think of it as int star
但如果你觉得这样更容易理解，你可以把它想象成 int star
as being the type.
作为类型。
It's not just an int, per se.
它不仅仅是一个 int，本身而言。
So with that said, let's consider now the canvas of computer's memory inside
因此，现在让我们考虑计算机内存的画布，其中
of which we're storing n, and now, p.
我们存储着 n，现在是 p。
So previously, I proposed that n is maybe, yeah,
所以之前，我建议 n 可能，是的，
maybe it's done in the bottom right hand corner of the screen.
可能它是在屏幕的右下角完成的。
So n is storing the number 50 here.
所以 n 这里存储着数字 50。
But technically, n lives somewhere.
但从技术上讲，n 存在于某个地方。
And for simplicity, I'm going to claim it's at OX123, rather than the bigger
为了简单起见，我将声称它在 OX123，而不是我们刚才看到的更大的
actual address we just saw.
实际地址。
But what about p?
但 p 又如何呢？
Well, p itself is another variable that I declared separately,
嗯，p 本身是另一个我单独声明的变量，
so it's got to live somewhere in the computer's memory.
所以它必须存在于计算机内存的某个地方。
And it turns out, by convention, pointers take up more space.
事实证明，按照惯例，指针占用的空间更大。
They typically use eight bytes nowadays, rather than just four.
如今，它们通常使用八个字节，而不是四个。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Well, if you've got eight bytes, you can count even higher.
嗯，如果你有八个字节，你可以数到更高的数字。
You can have even more addresses.
你可以拥有更多地址。
You can have more memory in your Mac, your PC, and phone.
你的 Mac、PC 和手机可以拥有更多的内存。
That's a good thing.
这是好事。
So pointers tend to be eight bytes, which
所以指针往往是八个字节，这
is why I've used eight squares on the screen here.
是我在这里使用屏幕上的八个方块的原因。
But what is actually p storing?
但 p 实际上存储的是什么？
Well, it's just storing a number.
嗯，它只是存储着一个数字。
Yes, it's technically an integer, but that integer
是的，从技术上讲它是一个整数，但那个整数
is itself should be thought of as the address of some other value.
本身应该被认为是某个其他值的地址。
So n is down here at OX123. p is up here at who knows what address.
所以 n 在下面的 OX123。p 在上面的某个不知道地址的地方。
Doesn't matter for the sake of discussion,
为了讨论的目的，这并不重要，
but its value, what it's storing with its pattern of 64 bits
但它的值，它用 64 位模式存储的东西
is apparently OX123.
显然是 OX123。
So how does this help us?
那么这如何帮助我们呢？
Well, if you think about this a little more abstractly, who
嗯，如果你更抽象地思考一下，谁
cares about what else is going on in the computer's memory?
关心计算机内存中其他发生了什么？
It actually tends to be helpful to think about this pictorially
实际上，用图片来思考这个问题会更有帮助
as being a little something like this.
就像这样。
At the end of the day, you and I, even when
归根结底，你和我都一样，即使
we start writing code in C that uses pointers,
我们开始用 C 语言编写使用指针的代码，
generally, you and I are never going to care about the actual addresses.
通常情况下，你和我都不会关心实际的地址。
Even though I showed you OX7 something, that's
即使我向你展示了OX7的东西，但这
not generally useful information.
并不是一般有用的信息。
It's suffices to know that it exists somewhere,
知道它存在于某个地方就足够了，
and let the computer figure out how to get there.
然后让计算机弄清楚如何到达那里。
And so very often when talking about pointers and addresses more generally,
因此，在更广泛地谈论指针和地址时，
people actually abstract them away, so to speak.
人们实际上是将它们抽象化了，可以这么说。
So instead of literally writing on the screen
所以，与其在屏幕上直接写
or the whiteboard when discussing this, OX123, what the actual address is,
或者在讨论这个问题时写在白板上，OX123，实际地址是什么，
who cares what it is?
谁在乎它是什么？
It suffices that it's a value that leads me to the other value
它是一个可以让我找到另一个值的数值就够了，
that I care about, sort of the treasure map, as I described it earlier.
我所关注的另一个值，就像我之前描述的藏宝图一样。
So let's now connect this maybe a little more metaphorically.
现在让我们用更具比喻性的方式来连接它。
So Carter, maybe here you might have noticed
所以，卡特，也许你在这里可能已经注意到
that we've had for a while now these two mailboxes on the stage.
我们现在已经有一段时间在舞台上放了这两个邮箱了。
So this white one here is labeled p to represent our pointer variable.
所以，这里这个白色的邮箱被标注为p，代表我们的指针变量。
Carter's is labeled n, representing our actual integer.
卡特那个邮箱被标注为n，代表我们的实际整数。
And what's really kind of going on here is
而这里真正发生的事情是
that, if I were to access the value inside of p,
如果我要访问p内部的值，
much like we saw it up here, that's like opening this up and figuring out
就像我们在上面看到的那样，就像打开这个邮箱并弄清楚
what the actual value is.
实际值是什么。
Now, this itself is a little arcane.
现在，这本身有点深奥。
OX123.
OX123。
And so if we actually do this a little more metaphorically,
所以，如果我们用更具比喻性的方式来做这件事，
we can maybe do this and point our way, if you don't mind.
我们也许可以这样做，并且指明我们的方向，如果你不介意的话。
So here we have a big pointer.
所以，这里有一个大指针。
Oh, forgive me.
哦，请原谅我。
I guess we'll use this one here.
我想我们会使用这个。
OK.
好的。
So we have this big pointer that's essentially
所以，我们有一个大指针，它本质上
pointing at the location in memory that we care about, be it OX123,
指向我们所关心的内存位置，无论是OX123，
or something else.
还是其他东西。
And then if we dereference this, that is, use the star notation,
然后，如果我们对它进行解引用，也就是说，使用星号符号，
star p, that's like asking Carter to go to that location,
星号p，就像让卡特去那个位置，
open up the mailbox, and voila.
打开邮箱，瞧。
What value do you have there?
你那里有什么值？
Voila.
瞧。
Maybe a big round of applause for Carter for having
也许让我们为卡特热烈鼓掌，因为
practiced this beforehand with me.
之前和我一起练习了这个。
All right.
好的。
That was mostly just an excuse to use the foam fingers today.
这基本上只是今天用泡沫手指的借口。
But with that said, that's hopefully a helpful metaphor,
但话说回来，这希望能是一个有用的比喻，
honestly, because these pointers, these addresses actually
说实话，因为这些指针，这些地址实际上
tend to be among the more arcane topics in C
在C语言中，它们往往是最深奥的话题之一，
that, even if things are kind of clicking right now, as soon as you
即使现在事情很顺利，一旦你
start writing code involving addresses, it's
开始编写涉及地址的代码，就会
easy to get lost in some of the details.
很容易迷失在一些细节中。
But metaphorically, these mailboxes are meant
但从比喻意义上说，这些邮箱的目的是
to represent, really, what's going on.
来真正地代表正在发生的事情。
Mailboxes in the physical human world have addresses.
现实世界中的邮箱都有地址。
I can go to that address, open it up, and then I can go to another address
我可以去那个地址，打开它，然后我可以去另一个地址
by following that treasure map, if you will, or pictorially here,
如果你愿意，就按照这条宝藏地图，或者这里用图来表示，
the arrow that's pointing from one location to another.
指向从一个位置到另一个位置的箭头。
So even though it's very weird syntax with ampersands, and asterisks,
所以即使它使用与符号和星号非常奇怪的语法，
and the like, it's just addresses in memory,
等等，它仅仅是内存中的地址，
much like mailboxes in the real world.
就像现实世界中的邮箱一样。
So with that said, let's maybe begin to take off certain training
所以，让我们开始移除一些训练
wheels by revisiting what strings are, as we've been using them thus far.
内容，通过重新回顾字符串是什么，因为我们一直都在使用它们。
So here's a line of code in C that we've been using since week one,
所以这里有一行 C 语言代码，我们从第一周就开始使用它，
really, where I declare a string variable called s, and set it equal to,
实际上，我声明了一个名为 s 的字符串变量，并将其设置为等于，
quote unquote, hi.
引号中的 "hi"。
Now, technically "hi" is three letters, or two letters in a punctuation symbol.
从技术上讲，“hi” 是三个字母，或者是一个标点符号中的两个字母。
But how many bytes is that string taking up?
但是这个字符串占用多少字节呢？
Is it one, two, three, or was it--
是 1、2、3，还是--
I'm seeing it here.
我在这里看到它。
It's four.
是 4。
Why?
为什么？
Yeah, there's always a null character that, even though you don't see it
是的，总有一个空字符，即使你没有看到它
on the screen, that is what terminates every string, we claimed, a while back.
在屏幕上，它就是终止每个字符串的东西，我们之前就说过。
So if I were to draw this maybe "hi" ends up
所以，如果我要画一下，也许 "hi" 最终会
in the computer's memory down here, bottom right hand corner.
出现在电脑内存的底部右下角。
But it is indeed four bytes, not just three
但它确实是 4 个字节，不仅仅是 3 个字节
because, secretly, there's always been that null character,
因为，秘密地，总是存在着那个空字符，
even though we as programmers don't often
即使我们作为程序员并不经常
have to type it explicitly ourselves.
需要显式地自己输入它。
That's what the double quotes do for us.
这就是双引号为我们做的事情。
It terminates the string with that null character.
它用空字符终止字符串。
Now, recall from week two when we talked about arrays,
现在，回想一下我们在第二周谈论数组的时候，
we started playing around with strings as really
我们开始把字符串当做
just being arrays of characters.
字符数组来处理。
So we call them a string, but we could treat them as arrays of char,
所以我们称它们为字符串，但我们可以将它们当作字符数组来处理，
so to speak.
可以说是这样。
So if the string was called s, s bracket zero would give us the first char,
所以，如果字符串叫 s，s 方括号 0 就会给出第一个字符，
s bracket one the second, s bracket two the third.
s 方括号 1 是第二个，s 方括号 2 是第三个。
And if you're really curious, s bracket three
如果你真的很好奇，s 方括号 3
would give you the last hidden null character,
会给你最后一个隐藏的空字符，
which we saw on the screen as just a zero
我们把它打印到屏幕上时，它显示为一个零
when we printed it out, while tinkering with some actual code.
在调整一些实际代码的时候。
But technically, today, logically, it would
但从技术上讲，在今天，逻辑上，它应该是
seem that it's also true that H-I exclamation
看起来，这也的确是正确的，H-I 感叹号
point and the null character must clearly live at some address.
以及空字符，显然必须存在于某个地址。
They must clearly live in their own mailbox, so to speak.
它们必须存在于它们自己的邮箱中，可以这么说。
So maybe, for the sake of discussion, this H today is at OX123.
所以，为了讨论，我们假设今天的 H 在 OX123 上。
But recall that arrays are characterized by contiguousness from left to right.
但请记住，数组的特征是从左到右的连续性。
So if H is at OX123, it must be the case that I is at OX124, I is at 125,
所以如果 H 在 OX123 上，那么 I 就必须在 OX124 上，I 在 125 上，
and the null character is at OX126 because those are one byte apart.
而空字符在 OX126 上，因为它们彼此相隔一个字节。
And I deliberately chose numbers here where,
而且我在这里故意选择了一些数字，其中，
whether it's decimal or hexadecimal, it doesn't matter.
无论是十进制还是十六进制，都没关系。
These differ by just one byte themselves.
它们本身只相差一个字节。
So that's what implies that they're indeed
所以，这暗示着它们确实是
adjacent, or contiguous in memory.
相邻的，或者在内存中连续的。
But what is s then?
但s是什么呢？
When I declared s to be a string, what is
当我声明s是一个字符串时，是什么
it that's been going in s all of this time
一直在s里面存在
if, clearly, s is actually this thing here?
如果，很明显，s实际上是这里的东西？
Well, strings have kind of been a white lie for a few weeks
好吧，字符串在过去几周里有点像一个善意的谎言
because s itself, technically, is a pointer.
因为s本身，从技术上讲，是一个指针。
s is the address of this string.
s是这个字符串的地址。
So the string is somewhere in memory, but s
所以字符串在内存中的某个地方，但s
itself is a separate variable that gives you
本身是一个单独的变量，它给你
a clue as how to find all of those characters in memory.
一个线索，告诉你如何在内存中找到所有这些字符。
So if you had to guess just intuitively now,
所以如果你现在必须凭直觉猜测，
if this is the string actually in memory, that is, this
如果这是实际上在内存中的字符串，也就是说，这个
is the array of chars in memory, what would logically
是内存中的字符数组，那么逻辑上会
make sense to put as the value of s?
有意义地作为s的值？
A pointer.
一个指针。
Specifically?
具体来说？
A pointer to h.
指向h的指针。
And how would I express that?
我该如何表达呢？
What's the actual value?
实际值是什么？
OX123 might very well suffice as the value here of s.
OX123很可能足够作为s的值。
Now, why might that be?
现在，为什么可能是这样呢？
Well, that essentially gives you enough information
好吧，这本质上给了你足够的信息
to find the beginning of the string, "hi" in this case.
来找到字符串的开头，在这种情况下是"hi"。
Now, you might think, well, wait a minute.
现在，你可能会想，等等。
How does it know about the second character and the third character?
它怎么知道第二个字符和第三个字符？
But now, if you kind of rewind in time, oh, wait a minute,
但现在，如果你倒回到过去，哦，等等，
maybe now the null character actually makes even more sense from week two.
也许现在空字符从第二周开始就更有意义了。
Why?
为什么？
Because if s technically storing the location
因为如果s从技术上讲存储了位置
of the beginning of the string, someone's
字符串开头的，有人
got to keep track of where the string ends, presumably.
必须跟踪字符串在哪里结束，大概是。
And that's effectively the string itself because humans decided decades ago,
而这实际上就是字符串本身，因为人类几十年前决定，
let's just null terminate every string with a special
让我们用一个特殊的空字符来结束每一个字符串
so character, zero, all zero bits, eight zero bits, specifically.
特殊字符，零，全是零位，八个零位，具体来说。
But and that's enough information.
但是，这足够信息了。
The sort of treasure map leads you to the beginning of the string,
这种藏宝图会把你带到字符串的开头，
and then you can use a for loop, a while loop,
然后你可以使用for循环，while循环，
or whatever to walk through the string, and that's what printf does.
或其他任何方法来遍历字符串，这就是printf所做的。
And you just stop as soon as you see that null character.
你只要看到空字符就停止。
So this then is what a string actually is.
所以这就是字符串的实际情况。
s is and has always been, since week one, a pointer, so to speak,
s从第一周开始就一直是一个指针，可以这么说，
that actually refers to the start of that array of characters.
它实际上指的是那个字符数组的开头。
And frankly, again, who cares about the OX123 specifics?
坦率地说，再次强调，谁会在乎OX123的细节？
We can abstract that away and actually just treat
我们可以将其抽象出来，实际上只是将
s as, literally, an arrow that points to the beginning of that string
s视为，从字面上说，一个指向那个字符串开头的箭头。
because it will be rare that we actually care about where this thing
因为我们很少会关心这个东西
physically is in the computer's memory.
在计算机内存中的实际位置。
Now, before we see this in code, any questions on this revelation?
现在，在我们看到代码之前，对此揭示有什么疑问吗？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: Have pointers gotten larger as computer memories
观众：指针的大小随着计算机内存的增加而增加了吗？
have increased over the decades?
在过去几十年里？
SPEAKER 1: Yes.
演讲者 1：是的。
Have pointers gotten larger as computers memory has increased over the decades?
指针的大小随着计算机内存的增加而增加了吗？
Short answer, yes.
简短的回答是，是的。
Like, back in my day, we were limited to, like, two gigabytes
就像，在我那个时代，我们被限制在 2 GB
of memory total.
的总内存。
Well, why two?
为什么是 2 GB 呢？
Well, if you had 32-bit memory, or if you use 32 bits
好吧，如果你有 32 位内存，或者如果你使用 32 位
to represent addresses, a.k.a. four bytes, as was conventional,
来表示地址，也就是 4 个字节，这是一种常规做法，
you can count recall as high as 4 billion values.
你可以计算出高达 40 亿个值。
But generally, numbers are both negative and positive, so that halves it.
但一般来说，数字既有负数也有正数，所以要减半。
So the reason decades ago, computers, PCs, Macs
所以，几十年前，电脑、个人电脑、苹果电脑
could have no more than two gigabytes of memory was because, literally,
只能拥有不超过 2 GB 的内存，是因为，从字面上来说，
the integers being used, the pointers being used
正在使用的整数，正在使用的指针
were only four bits, that is 32 bits.
只有 4 个字节，也就是 32 位。
Sorry, four bytes, that is, 32 bits long.
抱歉，是 4 个字节，也就是 32 位。
And so you literally could buy more memory.
因此，你实际上可以购买更多内存。
You could buy a third gigabyte, a fourth gigabyte,
你可以购买第三个千兆字节，第四个千兆字节，
but you literally had no way mathematically
但从数学上来说，你根本没有办法
to express all of those bigger locations.
来表示所有这些更大的位置。
So it was effectively useless, in that case.
因此，在这种情况下，它实际上是无用的。
In more modern times, computers tend now to use 64 bits, which
在更现代的时代，计算机现在倾向于使用 64 位，它
allows you to count crazy high.
允许你计算出惊人的高值。
And that's more than enough to address bigger chunks of memory.
这足以用来处理更大的内存块。
Really good question.
真是个好问题。
Others on memory thus far.
其他关于内存的疑问。
No, all right.
没有，好的。
Well, let's translate this a bit to code by going back over to VS Code here.
好吧，让我们通过回到 VS Code 中来将这段内容翻译成代码。
And let me propose now that we revisit maybe a simpler string
现在，我建议我们重新看一下一个更简单的字符串
example, as opposed to these integers.
示例，与这些整数相比。
So let me go ahead and throw away all of this integer related code.
所以，让我先把所有与整数相关的代码都删掉。
Let me go ahead and, for the moment, include CS50.h
让我先暂时包含 CS50.h
so that we have access to string and other things as in week one.
这样我们就可以像第一周一样使用字符串和其他东西了。
And let me do a string s equals quote unquote "HI" in all caps.
我定义一个字符串 s，它的值是双引号里的"HI"，全部大写。
And let me do a simple safety check %s backslash n s,
我执行一个简单的安全检查 %s 反斜杠 n s，
just to make sure everything works as it did in week one.
只是为了确保一切都像第一周那样工作。
So make addresses, dot slash addresses, and I should indeed
所以，构建地址，点斜杠地址，我应该能够看到
see "HI" on the screen.
屏幕上的"HI"。
Well, let's now kind of tinker with what's going on underneath the hood.
好吧，现在让我们来修改一下内部正在发生的事情。
And now, things can get a little more memory specific.
现在，事情会变得更具体一些，与内存有关。
So I'm still going to declare s as a string up here.
所以，我仍然要在上面声明 s 作为一个字符串。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
Instead of printing out the string itself,
与其直接打印字符串本身，
let me actually treat s as the pointer I claim it is.
不如让我把 s 当作我所说的那个指针来对待。
I claim a string is just an address, so I have this new syntax today,
我声称字符串只是一个地址，所以我今天有这种新的语法，
%p to print out pointers, to print out addresses.
%p 用于打印指针，即打印地址。
Let's see what s actually is.
让我们看看 s 实际上是什么。
Let me do make addresses again, dot slash addresses, and there it is.
让我再次执行 make addresses，然后执行 dot slash addresses，它就在那里。
It's not as simple as OX123, but it is at location OX55C670878004.
它不像 OX123 那样简单，但它位于 OX55C670878004 位置。
All right.
好的。
Who really cares, specifically?
具体来说，谁会在乎呢？
But if we poke around a bit more, things might make a bit more sense.
但如果我们再深入研究一下，事情可能就会更有意义。
Let's do this.
让我们这样做。
Let's also print out the address using %p of, how about the very first
我们还可以使用 %p 打印出... 比如第一个的地址...
character of s.
s 的字符。
So the very first character of is known as s bracket zero.
因此，第一个字符被称为 s 中括号零。
We did that in week two, treating a string as an array.
我们在第二周做过，将字符串视为数组。
But how do I get the address of a character?
但我如何获取字符的地址？
Well, I have our new symbol today, ampersand.
好吧，我今天有了我们的新符号，&。
So even though this looks like a mouthful, ampersand, s, square bracket,
所以，即使看起来很复杂，&、s、方括号，
zero, square bracket, it's just two ideas combined.
零、方括号，它只是将两个想法结合起来。
s bracket zero gives you the first character in the string, s.
s 中括号零会给你字符串 s 中的第一个字符。
And adding an ampersand at the beginning says, tell me what that address is.
在开头添加 & 表示，告诉我那个地址是什么。
So if I recompile this code, make addresses, dot slash addresses,
所以，如果我重新编译这段代码，执行 make addresses，然后执行 dot slash addresses，
even if you don't remember the value OX whatever,
即使你不记得 OX 的值是什么，
what are we going to see on the screen at a higher level?
我们在屏幕上会看到什么更高级的东西？
Perhaps the same exact thing.
也许是完全相同的东西。
Why?
为什么？
Well, s is just an address.
好吧，s 只是一个地址。
But what does that mean?
但这意味着什么？
Well, it's just the address of its first character.
好吧，它只是其第一个字符的地址。
And we saw that per our picture a moment ago.
我们刚才在图片中看到了这一点。
So can I see the contiguousness of this?
所以，我能看到这一点的连续性吗？
Well, I'm going to resort to some copy paste just for time's sake,
好吧，为了节省时间，我将使用一些复制粘贴，
even though this is going to look a little silly,
即使这看起来有点傻，
and I could certainly use a loop instead.
我当然可以使用循环代替。
But let me print out the second location, the third location, and heck,
但让我打印出第二个位置、第三个位置，还有...
even the fourth location, whoops, the fourth location of that null character.
甚至第四个位置，哎呀，那个空字符的第四个位置。
If I now do make addresses again and dot slash addresses, and zoom in,
如果我现在再次执行 make addresses，然后执行 dot slash addresses，并放大，
I don't really care about what these are, specifically.
我并不真正关心这些是什么，具体来说。
But notice the first two are indeed the same because the first represents s.
但请注意，前两个确实相同，因为第一个代表 s。
The first represents the first character of s,
第一个代表 s 的第一个字符，
which now I reveal are exactly the same idea.
现在我揭示了它们实际上是一样的。
And the next ones are literally just one byte
而接下来的几个实际上只是相差一个字节，
away, ending in five, six, and seven, respectively.
分别以五、六和七结尾。
So again, the numbers in and of themselves
所以，再次强调，这些数字本身
are not useful, actionable information, but it
不是有用的、可操作的信息，但它
does let us actually see what's going on underneath the hood.
确实让我们能够看到幕后发生了什么。
So just to rewind for a moment, let me actually go back to the original
所以，为了回顾一下，让我回到原始版本，
version, where I'm printing out the string itself, using %s.
版本，我使用 %s 打印出字符串本身。
Let me remake addresses to make sure that, OK, it still prints out "HI".
让我重新执行 make addresses 以确保... 好的，它仍然打印出 "HI"。
But what has been going on now all this time?
但是这段时间到底发生了什么呢？
Well, let me go back to our simple line of code
那么，让我回到我们简单的代码行
that we've been using since week one, which
从第一周开始我们一直在使用的代码行，它
gave us a string called s, setting it equal to the value of "HI".
给了我们一个名为s的字符串，将其设置为“HI”的值。
Let me propose now that strings were indeed this white lie.
我现在要提出，字符串其实就是一个善意的谎言。
And if I can unnecessarily dramatically say,
如果我可以用一种不必要的戏剧性方式来说，
here we take the training wheels off and reveal
现在我们摘掉了辅助轮，揭示了
that, all this time, string, string is probably, actually, what, technically?
一直以来，字符串，字符串可能，实际上，从技术上来说是什么？
Yeah.
是的。
A char star.
一个字符指针。
That was amazing.
太棒了。
Thank you for that.
谢谢你的解答。
So yeah.
所以是的。
So it's a char star, which admittedly at first glance,
所以它是一个字符指针，尽管乍一看，
just makes a simple idea look unnecessarily complicated.
它让一个简单的概念看起来不必要地复杂。
And that's why in week one, we indeed introduced these training wheels,
这就是为什么在第一周，我们确实引入了这些辅助轮，
whereby we, CS50, invented the datatype called string, just to kind of hide
通过它，我们，CS50，发明了名为字符串的数据类型，仅仅是为了隐藏
this lower level detail.
这个底层细节。
If you will, string for us is an abstraction.
如果你愿意，对我们来说字符串是一个抽象的概念。
Now, that is to say string is not a CS50 specific word.
现在，也就是说，字符串不是 CS50 特有的词。
Every programmer in the world knows what a string is.
世界上每个程序员都知道什么是字符串。
It is a sequence of characters.
它是一系列字符。
It is an array of characters.
它是一个字符数组。
But in C, technically, decades ago when it was invented,
但在 C 语言中，从技术上讲，几十年前它被发明的时候，
they didn't think, they didn't decide to create an actual data type called
他们没有想过，他们没有决定创建一个名为
string because, especially if they were among those more comfortable,
字符串的数据类型，因为，尤其是如果他们属于那些更习惯于
char star is equivalent, and it achieves the exact same thing,
字符指针的人，字符指针是等效的，它实现了完全相同的功能，
even though at a glance, we didn't want to start week one with that lower level
即使乍一看，我们不想用那个底层
detail.
细节开始第一周。
Question here in front.
前面有提问吗？
Sure.
当然。
Can I clarify how the star makes it a string?
我能解释一下星号如何使它成为一个字符串吗？
So we've, up until now, been just calling it a string
所以我们，到目前为止，一直称之为字符串
so that's s is a string.
因此，s 是一个字符串。
And that's a sufficient mental model.
这是一种足够的心理模型。
But technically, what is a string?
但从技术上讲，什么是字符串？
I claimed pictorially with my grid of memory
我用我的内存网格进行了图形化的说明
that a string is really just an address.
一个字符串实际上只是一个地址。
It's really just the address of its first character.
它实际上只是其第一个字符的地址。
I then tried to demonstrate as much in code by using percent p
然后我尝试使用百分号 p 在代码中演示这一点
and showing you, literally, s is a value, like, OX something.
并向您展示，实际上，s 是一个值，比如，OX 某个东西。
And literally, its first character is at that same address, OX something.
而且实际上，它的第一个字符位于同一个地址，OX 某个东西。
So here, when I claim that string has never really existed,
所以在这里，当我声称字符串实际上从未存在过，
except within the confines of CS50, technically, the data type of a string
除了在 CS50 的范围内，从技术上讲，字符串的数据类型
is best expressed as char star.
最好用字符指针来表示。
Why?
为什么？
Well, a string clearly can't just be a char because a char, by definition,
好吧，字符串显然不能仅仅是一个字符，因为根据定义，
is a single character.
它是一个单字符。
A string, we already know, is a sequence of characters.
我们已经知道，一个字符串是一系列字符。
But how can you represent a sequence of characters?
但是如何表示一系列字符呢？
You can call it a char star, which is a different data type that we're
你可以称之为 char star，这是我们今天第一次介绍的一种不同的数据类型。
introducing today for the first time.
我们今天第一次介绍它。
And the star just means that s itself is not a char.
而星号只是意味着 s 本身不是一个 char。
The star means that s is the address of a char.
星号意味着 s 是一个 char 的地址。
And by convention, it's the address of the first char in a string.
按照惯例，它是字符串中第一个 char 的地址。
So with that said, if I go back to my actual VS Code over here,
所以，如果我回到我这里的 VS Code，
I can change, literally, char string to char star s.
我可以改变，实际上，char string 到 char star s。
I can get rid of the CS50 library, our so-called training wheels,
我可以去掉 CS50 库，也就是我们所谓的辅助轮，
which has been the goal for the past few weeks, to put them on initially
这在过去几周一直是我们的目标，最初要安装它们
and then take them off quite quickly.
然后很快地把它们取下来。
So now this is the same program, and %s is still the same. s is still the same.
所以现在这个程序是一样的，而且 %s 还是一样的。s 还是一样的。
Everything else is still the same.
其他一切仍然相同。
All I've done is change, quote unquote, string to,
我所做的只是改变，引号里的 “string” 到，
quote unquote, char star, which obviates the need for the CS50 library.
引号里的 “char star”，这就不需要 CS50 库了。
And if I now do make addresses and dot slash addresses,
如果我现在执行 make addresses 和 dot slash addresses，
"HI" behaves exactly as it would.
“HI” 的行为完全一样。
So this is now raw native C code without any training wheels,
所以现在这是原始的 C 代码，没有任何辅助轮，
without any CS50 scaffolding, that just uses these basic building
没有任何 CS50 脚手架，它只使用这些基本的构建
blocks and primitives.
块和基本类型。
Other questions on this?
还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: Could you please clarify why we don't use the end symbol for that
听众：你能解释一下为什么我们不使用那个符号
s, as opposed to the other ones?
s，而不是其他的符号？
SPEAKER 1: Correct.
发言人 1：没错。
Why don't we use the ampersand symbol for this, though we did earlier?
为什么我们不在这里使用取地址符，虽然我们在之前用过？
So in this case, there's no reason for an ampersand
所以，在这种情况下，没有必要使用取地址符
because the ampersand tells you what the address of a variable is.
因为取地址符会告诉你一个变量的地址是什么。
I'll concede that it probably would be a little more
我承认这可能更
consistent for us to do this, which is maybe where your mind is going.
一致，也许这就是你在想的地方。
Now, never mind the fact that looks even worse, I think, syntactically.
现在，别管它看起来更糟糕了，我认为，从语法上来说。
It's a reasonable instinct, but it turns out
这是一个合理的直觉，但事实证明
that two is what the double quotes are doing for you.
双引号正在为你做的事情就是这两个。
The C compiler, called Clang, is smart enough
C 编译器，叫做 Clang，足够聪明
to realize that when it sees double quotes around a sequence of characters,
它能够意识到，当它看到围绕着一系列字符的双引号时，
it wants to put the address of that first char in the variable for you.
它会将第一个字符的地址放到变量中。
But when we had a variable like n, which we created,
但是，当我们有一个像 n 这样的变量，我们创建了它，
you have to distinguish n from its address.
你必须区分 n 和它的地址。
So that's why we prefixed n with an ampersand.
所以这就是我们用取地址符作为 n 的前缀的原因。
But the double quotes take care of it for you.
但是，双引号为你处理了这个问题。
Other questions on these here addresses?
关于这些地址还有其他问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right.
好的。
Well, beyond that, let me propose that we tinker with one other idea
除此之外，让我建议我们尝试一下另一个想法
to see how we actually invented this thing called a string.
看看我们是如何发明了这个叫做字符串的东西。
Well, I claim that string is just char star.
好吧，我声称字符串就是 char star。
You've actually seen this technique before.
你之前已经见过这种技巧了。
It was just a week ago that we tinkered with structures, custom data types
就在一周前，我们尝试了结构体，自定义数据类型。
to represent a person.
用来代表一个人。
And recall that we had a structure of a name and a number representing
回想一下，我们有一个包含姓名和数字的结构，代表着
a person.
一个人。
But more importantly, we had this keyword typedef,
但更重要的是，我们有这个关键字 typedef，
which defines your own type to be whatever you want.
它定义了你自己的类型，可以是你想要的任何类型。
Now, we used it a little more powerfully last time
现在，上次我们更强大地使用了它
to actually represent a whole structure of a person, having a name,
来真正地代表一个包含姓名、
and having a number.
以及数字的完整结构。
But at the end of the day, we really just invented our own data type
但最终，我们实际上只是发明了自己的数据类型
that we called, obviously, person.
我们很明显地把它叫做 person。
But and that represented, indeed, this structure.
而它确实代表了这个结构。
But typedef was really the enabling element there.
但是 typedef 才是真正的关键元素。
And so it turns out with typedef, you can create
所以事实证明，使用 typedef，你可以创建
any number of data types of your own.
任意数量你自己的数据类型。
For instance, if you just really can't get
例如，如果你真的无法接受
the hang of calling an integer an int, you
把整数叫做 int，你可以
can create your own data type called integer
创建一个你自己的数据类型叫做 integer
that itself is a synonym for int, because the way typedef works,
它本身是 int 的同义词，因为 typedef 的工作方式是，
even though this one's even simpler than the struct,
即使它比结构体还要简单，
is you can read it from right to left.
你可以从右到左阅读它。
This means give me a data type called integer that is actually an int.
这意味着给我一个叫做 integer 的数据类型，它实际上是一个 int。
And that's the same thing that happened a moment ago.
这和刚才发生的事情是一样的。
Give me a data type called person that is actually this whole structure.
给我一个叫做 person 的数据类型，它实际上是这个完整的结构。
But an integer is even simpler.
但整数更简单。
Now, most people wouldn't do this.
现在，大多数人不会这样做。
This really doesn't create any intellectual enhancement of the data
这实际上不会对数据类型进行任何智力上的增强，
types, but you could do it if you really wanted.
但是如果你真的想要，你可以这样做。
More commonly, and as you'll see this in code in the future,
更常见的是，你将在未来的代码中看到，
would be not just a typedef something like an integer.
不仅仅是像 integer 这样的 typedef。
But it turns out, curiously, C has no data type for a byte.
但事实证明，奇怪的是，C 语言没有表示字节的数据类型。
Like, there's no built in obvious way to represent eight bits
比如，没有内置的明显方法来表示八位
and store whatever you want in them.
并将你想要的东西存储在其中。
However, you can use what's called a uint8_t, t
但是，你可以使用所谓的 uint8_t，
which is a data type that comes with C. And frankly, those more comfortable
它是一个与 C 语言一起提供的數據類型。坦率地说，那些更熟悉
might simply use this data type once you sort of
的人可能会在你能记住它存在之后直接使用这个数据类型。
commit to memory that it exists.
记住它存在。
But honestly, for most of us, it's a lot more convenient to think of a byte
但老实说，对我们大多数人来说，将字节视为
as being its own data type.
它自己的数据类型会更方便。
When you want to write code that manipulates one or two or more bytes,
当你想要编写操作一个、两个或多个字节的代码时，
wouldn't it be nice to have a data type called byte?
拥有一个叫做 byte 的数据类型不是很好吗？
So it turns out that you can represent a byte, which is eight bits using
所以事实证明，你可以用
an unsigned integer with 8 bits.
一个 8 位的无符号整数来表示一个字节，它有八位。
And this is just a data type that's declared in some other C header file.
而这只是一个在其他 C 头文件中声明的数据类型。
But long story short, you'll see and use this before long.
但长话短说，你很快就会看到并使用它。
But it's just a synonym to make things a little more user friendly,
但它只是一个同义词，让事情更方便，
like person, like string, like byte.
就像 person，就像 string，就像 byte。
So what is in the CS50 header file, among other things?
那么 CS50 头文件中除了其他东西之外，还包含什么呢？
Literally, this line of code.
实际上，就是这行代码。
This is the single line of code that we deploy
这是我们从第一周开始部署的唯一一行代码
in week one onward that teaches Clang to think of the word string
它告诉 Clang 从第一周开始将字符串理解为
as being synonymous with char star, so that you all never have to type,
与字符指针是同义词，这样你们就永远不必输入，
or know, or think about char star until, wonderfully, today in week four,
或者知道，或者去思考字符指针，直到今天，神奇的是，我们到了第四周，
a couple of weeks later instead.
也就是几周后。
So that's all we've been doing.
这就是我们一直在做的事情。
That is the technical implementation of the training wheels.
这就是辅助轮的技术实现。
It's just using a custom data type in this way.
它只是以这种方式使用了自定义数据类型。
So how about one other maybe pair of examples here with our addresses,
那么我们用地址再举一对例子，
such that we can tinker a little bit further?
这样我们可以进一步研究一下？
It turns out that, once everything in the world
事实证明，一旦世界上所有事物
is addressable using these pointers, like using numeric addresses
都可以使用这些指针进行寻址，就像使用数字地址一样
to represent where things are in memory, you can actually
来表示事物在内存中的位置，你实际上
do something called pointer arithmetic.
可以做一些叫做指针运算的事情。
And here, too, we the programmers generally
而且这里，我们程序员通常
don't care what the specific values are, but we care that they do exist.
并不关心具体的值是什么，但我们关心它们是否存在。
And if they do exist, we can maybe do some arithmetic on them
如果它们确实存在，我们也许可以对它们进行一些运算
and add one to go to the next byte, add two to go to the next, next byte,
加一去到下一个字节，加二去到下下一个字节，
add three to go to the next, next, net byte, and so forth.
加三去到下下下一个字节，等等。
So pointer arithmetic literally refers to doing math on addresses.
因此，指针运算实际上是指对地址进行数学运算。
So how do we translate this into something actionable?
那么我们如何将其转化为可操作的东西呢？
Let me actually go back to VS Code here, and let
让我回到 VS Code，然后
me propose that we do something like the following.
我建议我们做以下事情。
I'm going to throw away my first printf here.
我将丢弃这里第一个 printf。
And I'm instead going to print out this string character by character,
我将改为逐个字符地打印这个字符串，
just like we did in week two.
就像我们在第二周做的那样。
Let me go ahead and call printf, pass in %c for a single char, backslash n,
让我继续调用 printf，传入 %c 来打印单个字符，反斜杠 n，
comma, and now I want to print out the first character in s.
逗号，现在我想要打印出 s 中的第一个字符。
Using array notation, what do I type to print the first character in s?
使用数组表示法，我应该输入什么来打印 s 中的第一个字符？
Yep, over here.
没错，在那边。
s bracket zero.
s 中括号 0。
So s bracket zero gives me the first character in s.
所以 s 中括号 0 给了我 s 中的第一个字符。
And let me copy paste just for demonstration sake
为了演示，让我复制粘贴一下
here inside of my same curly braces, and print out
在我的同一个花括号中，打印出来
the second char, and the third.
第二个字符，和第三个字符。
And I don't care about the null character.
我不关心空字符。
I just want to print the string itself for now.
我现在只是想打印出字符串本身。
So even though this is jumping through way more hoops than just using %s
所以即使这比仅仅使用 %s 跳了很多圈
and print the whole thing at once, it's again, just demonstrating how we can,
并直接打印整个内容，但这又一次证明了我们如何可以，
at a lower level, manipulate these strings.
在更底层上，操纵这些字符串。
So let me do make addresses, dot slash addresses.
所以让我做 make addresses，点斜杠 addresses。
And yet again, we see, somewhat stupidly, one
再一次，我们看到，有点愚蠢的是，一行一个
per line, H-I exclamation point.
H-I 感叹号。
I can, of course fix that by getting rid of this.
当然，我可以通过去掉这个来解决它。
I can get rid of this, and I can leave the last backslash n.
我可以去掉这个，留下最后一个反斜杠 n。
So let's just make it a look a little prettier.
让我们让它看起来更漂亮一些。
Make addresses, dot slash addresses, enter,
创建地址，点斜杠地址，回车，
and I can print it out all on one line.
我就可以在一行上打印出来。
But now using pointer notation, it turns out
但是现在使用指针符号，结果发现
we can do one other thing, which admittedly, for now,
我们可以做另外一件事，诚然，目前来说，
is going to feel like unnecessary complexity.
会让人觉得不必要的复杂。
But it's actually a really helpful tool to add to our toolkit, so to speak,
但实际上，它是一个非常有用的工具，可以添加到我们的工具箱中，这么说吧，
whereby I could instead do this.
我可以这样做。
To print out the first character in s, yes, I can treat it as an array
要打印出 s 中的第一个字符，是的，我可以将其视为一个数组
and get the zeroth index.
并获取第零个索引。
However, what is s? s is just the address of a string.
然而，s 是什么呢？s 只是字符串的地址。
What does that mean? s is the address of the first char in the string.
这意味着什么呢？s 是字符串中第一个字符的地址。
So if I do star s, what's that going to print?
所以如果我用星号表示 s，会打印什么呢？
Presumably h, right?
应该是 h，对吧？
Because if the first character in s is h, then star s will go to that address
因为如果 s 中的第一个字符是 h，那么星号表示的 s 将会指向该地址
and show me what's actually there.
并向我展示那里实际上的内容。
And let me go ahead and do this again.
让我继续这样做。
Let me copy paste twice and then tweak this a little bit.
让我复制粘贴两次，然后稍微调整一下。
I want to go to the next byte over.
我想去下一个字节。
Well, I could do s bracket one.
好吧，我可以使用 s 中括号 1。
All right, but I could instead go to s plus one.
好的，但我可以用 s 加 1 来代替。
And I could instead go to s plus two, thereby
我还可以使用 s 加 2 来代替，从而
doing what we're calling pointer arithmetic, math on addresses.
执行我们称之为指针算术的操作，对地址进行数学运算。
And now, if I go ahead and rerun make addresses, dot slash addresses, voila.
现在，如果我继续运行创建地址，点斜杠地址，瞧！
Whoops, I forgot my backslash n.
哎呀，我忘记了反斜杠 n。
Let's fix that just to be tidy.
让我们修正一下，使其整洁。
Dot slash addresses, voila.
点斜杠地址，瞧！
There is our "HI".
这就是我们的“HI”。
Now, this is not how a normal person would print out a string,
现在，这并不是普通人打印字符串的方式，
but it does go to show you that there's not really been any magic.
但这确实表明，这里并没有什么魔法。
Like, these characters are just where we predicted they would be.
就像，这些字符正好在我们预测的地方。
And now that you have this star notation, the dereference operator,
现在你有了这个星号符号，解除引用运算符，
which means go there, you have the ability to access individual values.
这意味着去那里，你可以访问单个值。
You even have the ability to ask where those things are by using ampersands,
你甚至可以使用取地址符来询问这些东西在哪里，
as well.
也是。
But it turns out that the reason that we introduced the array syntax first
但事实证明，我们首先引入数组语法的原因是
is that the array syntax is what the world would
因为数组语法是世界
call syntactic sugar for exactly this.
称之为对这种语法糖的语法糖。
When you say s bracket zero, the compiler is essentially doing star s
当你使用 s 中括号零时，编译器本质上是在执行星号表示的 s
and saving you the trouble.
并为你节省麻烦。
When you do s bracket one, the compiler is essentially
当你使用 s 中括号 1 时，编译器本质上是
saving you the trouble of doing star, in parentheses, s plus one,
为你节省使用星号、括号、s 加 1 的麻烦，
and same for the third char, as well.
第三个字符也是一样的。
So all this time, pointers have been there underneath the hood.
所以一直以来，指针都隐藏在幕后。
They are what allow us to go to very specific memory locations.
它们使我们能够访问非常具体的内存位置。
They are going to be what allow us soon to start manipulating files,
它们将很快使我们能够开始操作文件，
whether it's photographs of stress balls, or CSI style content.
无论是压力球的照片，还是 CSI 风格的内容。
But for now, I think we should take our 10 minute break where whoopie pies will
但现在，我认为我们应该休息 10 分钟，谁派将在
now be served in the transept.
现在在过道里供应。
See you in 10.
10 分钟后见。
All right.
好的。
So we are back, and we've clearly drawn too much attention to the stress balls
所以我们回来了，我们显然对减压球给予了太多关注
today because now we're all out of these and whoopie pies.
今天，因为现在我们这些和谁派都没有了。
But more next week.
但下周会有更多。
In the meantime, though, we thought we'd now
与此同时，我们认为我们现在应该
use some of these new building blocks, this idea of being able to manipulate
使用一些新的构建块，这个想法能够操纵
underlying addresses, to revisit a couple of problems
底层地址，重新审视几个问题
that we kind of swept under the rug previously
我们之前把它暂时搁置了
by avoiding these problems altogether.
通过完全避免这些问题。
So by that, I mean this.
所以，我的意思是这个。
Let me go over to VS Code.
让我去 VS Code。
And let me create another example called compare.c,
让我创建一个名为 compare.c 的另一个示例，
whose purpose in life in a moment is going to be to compare values
它存在的目的，在接下来的一刻，将会是比较值
in kind of a very weak one way, too.
以一种非常薄弱的单向方式。
So let me go ahead and include CS50.h.
所以让我继续包含 CS50.h。
Let me go ahead and include standard io.h.
让我继续包含 standard io.h。
Let me do int main void, no command line arguments.
让我做 int main void，没有命令行参数。
And in here, let me just get two integers using getint as follows.
在这里，让我使用 getint 获取两个整数，如下所示。
So getint, and we'll ask for i.
所以 getint，我们将请求 i。
Let's go ahead and get int and ask for j,
让我们继续获取 int 并请求 j，
just so that we have two things to compare.
这样我们就有两件事可以比较了。
And then I'm going to do something super simple.
然后我要做一些超级简单的事情。
So if i equals, equals j, then let's print out,
所以如果 i 等于等于 j，那么让我们打印出来，
as we actually did in the past, same backslash n.
就像我们过去所做的那样，相同的反斜杠 n。
Else, if they're not the same, let's of course, print out, for instance,
否则，如果它们不一样，让我们当然，打印出来，例如，
different.
不同。
So super simple program that we used the first time around, really,
这是一个超级简单的程序，我们在第一次使用时，真的
just to demonstrate conditionals.
只是为了演示条件语句。
But now, we'll use it to tease apart some subtleties.
但是现在，我们将用它来揭示一些细微之处。
So let me go ahead and compile this with make compare.
所以让我继续使用 make compare 来编译它。
Dot slash compare.
点斜杠 compare。
And we'll compare one and one for i and j respectively.
我们将分别比较 i 和 j 的 1 和 1。
Those are, of course, the same.
它们当然是一样的。
Let's compare one and two.
让我们比较 1 和 2。
Those are, of course, different.
它们当然是不一样的。
So long story short, this program seems to work,
所以长话短说，这个程序似乎可以工作，
and we won't dwell much further on it.
我们不会进一步深入讨论它。
But let's consider for a moment what's going on inside of the computer's
但让我们花一点时间考虑一下计算机内部发生的事情
memory when that code is executed.
内存，当该代码被执行时。
So here's my canvas of memory.
所以这是我的内存画布。
Maybe i ends up over here.
也许 i 最终在这里。
Maybe j ends up over here.
也许 j 最终在这里。
Each of them I've drawn as four squares because integers are typically
我将它们中的每一个都画成了四个方块，因为整数通常
four bytes, or 32 bits.
四个字节，或 32 位。
So i has the value 50 here. i has the value 50.
所以 i 这里的值是 50。 i 的值是 50。
So I accidentally typed one and one, but assume
所以我不小心输入了 1 和 1，但假设
that I had typed 50 in both cases.
我在这两种情况下都输入了 50。
They both live at these two separate locations.
它们都住在这两个不同的位置。
All right.
好的。
So that's all fine and good.
所以这一切都很好。
And when we compare them, of course, 50 and 50, or one and one
当然，当我们比较它们时，50 和 50，或者 1 和 1
are, in fact, the exact same.
实际上是完全相同的。
But what if we actually compare different types of values?
但如果我们比较不同类型的值呢？
Let me go back into VS Code here.
让我回到这里的 VS Code 中。
And instead of integers, let's still, using the CS50 library,
我们仍然使用 CS50 库，而不是整数，
maybe use some strings instead.
也许使用一些字符串。
So let me go ahead and change my i and j to maybe s and t, respectively.
所以，让我继续将我的 i 和 j 分别改为 s 和 t。
So string s equals getstring.
所以字符串 s 等于 getstring。
And I'll ask for s, quote unquote.
我会要求 s，引号，引号。
And then string t equals getstring.
然后字符串 t 等于 getstring。
And then I'll ask for t, quote unquote.
然后我会要求 t，引号，引号。
And then down here, I'll compare s equals, equals t.
然后在下面，我会比较 s 等于，等于 t。
So here's the code, almost the same logically.
所以这是代码，逻辑上几乎相同。
I'm just getting different data types instead, still using the CS50 library.
我只是获得不同的数据类型，仍然使用 CS50 库。
So let's do make compare again, dot slash compare.
所以让我们再次执行 make compare，点斜杠 compare。
And let's type in something like "HI" exclamation point,
让我们输入类似于“HI”感叹号的东西，
"HI" exclamation point.
“HI”感叹号。
And that's interesting.
这很有趣。
All right, let's maybe try it again.
好吧，让我们再试一次。
So maybe lowercase "hi", "hi".
所以可能是小写“hi”，“hi”。
No, those are different.
不，这些是不同的。
Let's do it one more time, like "hi", "bye".
让我们再做一次，比如“hi”，“bye”。
OK, so it half works.
好的，所以它有一半有效。
But it seems to be saying different no matter what.
但无论如何，它似乎都在说不同。
Well, why might that be?
为什么是这样呢？
Well, let me first just peel back a layer.
好吧，让我先剥开一层。
We already know that strings don't technically exist.
我们已经知道字符串在技术上并不存在。
They're really char star.
它们实际上是 char star。
And string here is char star.
而这里的字符串是 char star。
So does this reveal, perhaps implicitly, why
那么，这是否隐含地揭示了为什么
s and t are being thought to be different, even though I literally
s 和 t 被认为是不同的，即使我确实是
typed "hi" twice?
两次输入“hi”？
Yeah, on line nine here, I'm really just comparing
是的，在这第 9 行，我只是在比较
the addresses that are in s and t, and that's why I changed it to char star,
s 和 t 中的地址，这就是我将其更改为 char star 的原因，
just not to change anything, but to make it even clearer
只是为了不改变任何东西，而是让它更加清楚
that s and t are, in fact, addresses.
s 和 t 实际上是地址。
They're not strings, per se.
它们不是字符串本身。
They're the address of the first character in those strings.
它们是这些字符串中第一个字符的地址。
And even though they happen to be the same words that I typed in,
即使它们碰巧是我输入的相同词语，
it would seem to imply that they're ending up in different places.
似乎意味着它们最终会出现在不同的位置。
So here's another canvas of memory for this program.
所以这是该程序的另一个内存画布。
And here, for instance, might be s with enough room
例如，这里可能会有足够的空间容纳 s
for eight bytes up here as a pointer.
作为指针，这里有 8 个字节。
Here maybe is where "hi" ended up for this particular story.
这里可能是“hi”在这个特定故事中最终出现的地方。
Well, what's actually going in s?
那么，s 里面实际上是什么？
Well, if h is at OX123, i is at OX124, and so forth, what's going in
那么，如果 h 在 OX123，i 在 OX124，等等，那么 s 里面有什么
s is OX123.
s 是 OX123。
But when I use get string a second time and type in "hi"
但是当我第二次使用 get string 并输入 "hi"
exclamation point, even the exact same way, uppercase or lowercase,
感叹号，即使使用完全相同的方式，大写或小写，
t is ending up, presumably, somewhere else in memory.
t 很可能最终存储在内存中的其他地方。
So it's maybe using these eight bytes over here.
所以它可能正在使用这些八个字节。
The same letters, coincidentally, by nature of how getstring works,
巧合的是，由于 getstring 的工作原理，相同的字母
are ending up in the computer's memory, maybe down there, bottom right
最终存储在计算机的内存中，可能在下方，右下角
hand corner.
角落。
Those are presumably different addresses, OX456, 457, 458, 459.
这些很可能是不同的地址，OX456，457，458，459。
So what's going to go in t as its value?
那么，t 的值将是什么？
OX456, according to this example.
根据这个例子，是 OX456。
And so when you literally compare s equals,
所以当你直接比较 s 等于
equals t, no, they're not the same.
等于 t 时，不，它们并不相同。
They are, in fact, different, even if what they're pointing at
事实上，它们是不同的，即使它们指向的是
happens to be the same.
相同的内容。
So the computer's taking us literally.
所以计算机是按照字面意思来理解我们的。
If you compare s and t respectively, it's
如果你分别比较 s 和 t，它
going to compare what their values actually are.
将比较它们的实际值。
And their values are the addresses of the first letter
而它们的值是第一个字母的地址
of this string, and the first letter of this string, respectively.
这个字符串，以及这个字符串的第一个字母。
And if those addresses differ, which they clearly do,
如果这些地址不同，很明显它们确实不同，
they're going to be deemed different.
它们将被认为是不同的。
Now, you might wonder, well, this just seems stupidly inefficient.
现在，你可能会想，好吧，这看起来真的很低效。
Why put the same string in two different places?
为什么要把相同的字符串放在两个不同的位置？
Well, maybe the string needs to be changed later on,
好吧，也许该字符串需要稍后更改，
and we might want to have two different versions thereof.
我们可能想要拥有两个不同的版本。
And frankly, the first time you call getstring, it does its thing.
坦率地说，你第一次调用 getstring 时，它会执行它的操作。
The second time you call getstring, it does its own thing.
你第二次调用 getstring 时，它会执行它自己的操作。
It doesn't necessarily know how many times it's been called in the past.
它不一定知道它过去被调用了多少次。
And so maybe there's no communication between those calls.
所以可能这些调用之间没有通信。
And so surely, it's going to do the simple thing
所以当然，它会做简单的事情
and just create more memory, create more memory for each of those strings,
并为每个字符串创建更多内存，创建更多内存，
duplicates though they may seem to be.
即使它们看起来像是重复的。
So what does this imply?
那么这意味着什么？
Well, you might recall that we avoided this problem altogether
好吧，你可能还记得，我们完全避免了这个问题
just a week ago by using what solution on line nine?
就在一周前，通过在第九行使用什么解决方案？
I did not compare two strings using equals, equals last time.
上次我没有使用 equals，equals 比较两个字符串。
Exactly.
没错。
We used the strcompare function, which is in string.h very deliberately
我们使用了 strcompare 函数，它在 string.h 中，当时我非常谨慎地使用了它
at the time, because I didn't want to trip over this mistake at the time
因为我当时不想在这个错误上犯错
until we were sort of ready and had the vocabulary to discuss it.
直到我们准备好并且拥有讨论它的词汇。
But I did not do s equals, equals t, even though, logically, that's
但我没有使用 s 等于，等于 t，即使从逻辑上来说，那就是
what you're trying to do, compare for equality.
你想要做的，比较是否相等。
But if you know now what a string is, it's
但是，如果你现在知道字符串是什么，它
an array of characters starting at some address.
是一个从某个地址开始的字符数组。
You really need someone something to do the heavy lifting
你真的需要有人或某事来完成繁重的工作
of comparing every one of those chars from left to right.
比较所有这些字符，从左到右。
We did it ourselves last time by just implementing it in code two weeks ago.
我们上次在两周前通过代码实现来完成的。
But strcompare compare does it for us.
但 strcompare compare 可以帮我们完成。
So strcompare, s comma t actually weirdly returns three possible values,
所以，strcompare，s 逗号 t 实际上奇怪地返回了三个可能的值，
zero if they're the same, a positive number if one comes before the other,
如果它们相同则返回零，如果一个在另一个前面则返回一个正数，
or a negative number if the opposite is true.
或者如果相反则返回一个负数。
So strcomp, remember, can be used for alphabetizing
所以 strcomp，记住，可以用来进行字母排序
things, or ascii-betizing things, based on those Ascii values.
事物，或者根据这些 ASCII 值进行 ASCII 排序。
So this version, if I open my terminal window now and do make compare,
所以这个版本，如果我现在打开我的终端窗口并执行 make compare，
dot slash compare, and type in "hi" and "hi", now, in fact,
点斜杠 compare，然后输入“hi”和“hi”，现在实际上，
they're the same because strcomp is doing the work
它们是相同的，因为 strcomp 正在进行工作
of comparing them char by char.
逐字符地比较它们。
And if I do "hi" and "bye", those are now, in fact, different.
如果我执行“hi”和“bye”，它们实际上现在不同了。
So we avoided the problem last time for this very reason that simply using
所以我们上次避免了这个问题，正是因为这个原因，简单地使用
equals, equals would not have worked.
等于，等于将不起作用。
Yes.
是的。
AUDIENCE: Using those values?
听众：使用这些值？
Is it like one minus one, or one, two, three,
就像一减一，还是一、二、三，
depending how different they are?
取决于它们有多不同？
SPEAKER 1: Oh, good question.
演讲者 1：哦，好问题。
So when using strcompare, the documentation
所以在使用 strcompare 时，文档
says that it will return zero, or a positive number, or a negative number.
说它将返回零，或一个正数，或一个负数。
It doesn't tell you a specific number.
它没有告诉你一个具体的数字。
So the magnitude of the integer that comes back actually has no meaning.
所以返回的整数的量级实际上没有意义。
It might very well be one, zero, and negative one, but there's no guarantee.
它很可能是 1、0 和 -1，但没有保证。
And so you can check for equality equals, equals,
所以你可以检查是否等于，等于，
or you should check for greater than or less
或者你应该检查是否大于或小于
than, but not specific to a certain number.
于，但不是针对特定数字。
So it just gives you relative ordering.
所以它只是给你相对排序。
It doesn't give you any more detail than that.
它没有给你更多细节。
All right.
好的。
So if we were to now take this lesson a step further,
所以，如果我们现在要进一步学习，
just to hammer home this point, whereby these strings s and t must clearly
只是为了强调这一点，即这些字符串 s 和 t 必须明确地
live at different addresses, let's actually try to see this in code.
存在于不同的地址，让我们实际尝试在代码中查看这一点。
So let me go back to VS Code here.
所以让我回到 VS Code 这里。
Let me go ahead and just remove all of the conditional code,
让我继续并将所有条件代码删除，
and instead do something old school, like print out %s backslash n and print
而是做一些老方法，比如打印输出 %s 反斜杠 n 并打印
out s.
输出 s。
Then Let's go ahead and print out %s again, but print out t,
然后让我们继续打印输出 %s，但打印输出 t，
just to see the two strings as being duplicative.
只是为了看到这两个字符串是重复的。
So here I go.
所以我开始做。
Make compare dot slash compare, "hi" exclamation point,
执行 make compare 点斜杠 compare，“hi”感叹号，
"hi" exclamation point.
“hi”感叹号。
And of course, they're actually the same.
当然，它们实际上是一样的。
But if I actually want to see where s and t are,
但如果我实际上想看看 s 和 t 在哪里，
I can change the % s to what?
我可以将 %s 更改为？
%p, %p here.
%p，%p 在这里。
And I don't need to use an ampersand before the s or the t
并且我不需要在 s 或 t 之前使用一个与号
because they are already addresses.
因为它们已经是地址了。
That was today's big reveal.
这就是今天的重大揭示。
And it turns out that printf is smart enough when you use s,
事实证明，当你使用 s 时，printf 足够智能，
and you give it an address of s, or the address in t, to just go there for you.
并且你给它一个 s 的地址，或者 t 中的地址，它就会直接为你转到那里。
So printf has been doing all of that for us with %s.
所以 printf 一直在用 %s 为我们做这一切。
But %p is actually going to print out those raw addresses.
但是 %p 实际上会打印出这些原始地址。
So let me do make compare, dot slash compare, "hi" once, "hi" twice.
所以让我做一下 make compare，点斜杠 compare，"hi" 一次，"hi" 两次。
And here now, we should see the addresses at which "hi" lives.
现在我们应该可以看到 "hi" 所在的地址。
And it's not going to be as simplistic as OX123 and OX456.
并且它不会像 OX123 和 OX456 那样简单。
But if I go back to my terminal and hit enter,
但是如果我回到我的终端并按下回车键，
indeed, I get two different hexadecimal values
实际上，我得到两个不同的十六进制值
that makes clear that, if I were to naively compare them with equals,
这清楚地表明，如果我天真地用等于号比较它们，
equals, they're always going to be different,
等于号，它们总是会不同，
even if I typed in the same words.
即使我输入了相同的单词。
So there's implications now of this, especially if we want
因此，这现在有了一些影响，特别是如果我们想要
to start changing things in memory.
开始更改内存中的内容。
So for instance, let me create a new program called copy.c.
例如，让我创建一个名为 copy.c 的新程序。
And in here, we'll start somewhat similarly with CS5o.h.
这里，我们将以与 CS5o.h 相似的方式开始。
We'll start with standard io.h.
我们将从 standard io.h 开始。
And preemptively, I'm going to go ahead and include string.h, as well.
并且，我将提前包含 string.h。
I'm going to declare main as not taking any command line arguments.
我将声明 main 不接受任何命令行参数。
And this time, I'm just going to get one string s with getstring,
这一次，我将只使用 getstring 获取一个字符串 s，
and I'll prompt the user for s.
然后我将提示用户输入 s。
And now, let me go ahead and naively say this.
现在，让我天真地说一下。
Let me give myself a new string called t and just set it equal to s,
让我给自己一个名为 t 的新字符串，并将其设置为等于 s，
my instinct being this is how I've copied integers before.
我的直觉是，这是我以前复制整数的方式。
This is how I've copied floating point values before.
这是我以前复制浮点数的方式。
This surely is how I copy strings, using the assignment operator as usual.
这肯定是我复制字符串的方式，使用通常的赋值运算符。
Let me now for the sake of discussion propose
现在，为了讨论起见，让我提议
that I want to capitalize the first letter in t,
我想将 t 中的第一个字母大写，
but not the first letter in s.
但不要将 s 中的第一个字母大写。
So logically, based on week two syntax, I'm going to go into the t string,
所以，从逻辑上讲，根据第二周的语法，我将进入 t 字符串，
go to location zero, and set it equal to upper of t bracket zero.
转到位置 0，并将其设置为 t 方括号 0 的 upper。
So recall, we introduced two upper.
所以，回想一下，我们引入了两个 upper。
It's just a handy function for capitalizing things.
它只是一个用于将事物大写的便捷函数。
There's two lower, and there's a bunch of others, as well.
还有两个 lower，以及一堆其他的。
I didn't include the header file yet, though, so I'm going to go back
不过，我还没有包含头文件，所以我将返回
and include--
并包含 --
anyone remember where these are?
有人记得这些在哪里吗？
Yeah, ctype.h.
是的，ctype.h。
And it's fine to look that up in the menu if you ever need it.
如果你需要的话，在菜单中查找它就可以了。
So here, I am, a little naively, capitalizing the first letter in t.
所以在这里，我天真地将 t 中的第一个字母大写。
Technically speaking, I should check what the length of t
从技术上讲，我应该检查 t 的长度
is first, because if there's no characters there, if it has zero chars,
是第一个，因为如果那里没有字符，如果它有 0 个字符，
there's nothing to uppercase.
就没有东西需要大写。
But for now, I'm going to keep it simple and just blindly do that there.
但现在，我会保持简单，并盲目地在那里做。
Now, let me go ahead and print out with %s the value of s.
现在，让我们继续使用 %s 打印 s 的值。
Now, let me go ahead and print out with %s value of t.
现在，让我们继续使用 %s 打印 t 的值。
And I should see one lowercase s and one capitalized T. All right, here we go.
我应该看到一个是小写的 s，另一个是大写的 T。好了，我们开始吧。
Make copy, dot slash copy.
运行 copy 文件，在 copy 目录下。
And I'm going to deliberately type it in lowercase.
我将故意用小写字母输入。
"hi" exclamation point, and we should see now they're both capitalized,
“hi” 加一个感叹号，现在我们应该看到它们都变成了大写，
it would seem.
看起来是这样的。
Intuitively, why might that be?
直观上，为什么会出现这种情况呢？
Exactly, the addresses are the same.
没错，地址是相同的。
So if I do use the assignment operator and just do t equals s semicolon,
所以如果我使用赋值运算符，并且执行 t 等于 s，并以分号结尾，
it's going to take me literally and copy the address in s over to t,
它将直接把 s 中的地址复制到 t 中，
so that effectively, they're pointing at the same thing.
这样，实际上它们指向的是同一个东西。
So if we draw another picture here, for instance, here maybe is s,
所以如果我们在这里画另外一张图，比如，这里可能是 s，
and here maybe is the lowercase "hi" that I first type
这里可能是第一次输入的小写字母“hi”
in down here in memory.
在内存中的下方。
Maybe that's at OX123 again, and therefore that's what's in s.
也许它位于 OX123，因此这就是 s 中的内容。
When I then create the variable t by declaring it to be a string,
然后我通过声明 t 是一个字符串来创建变量 t，
as well, that gives me another variable here called t.
同样，这给了我另一个叫做 t 的变量。
But I'm just setting it equal to s.
但我只是把它设置为等于 s。
I'm not calling getstring again in this version of copy.
在这个版本的 copy 中，我没有再次调用 getstring。
That was in compare.
那是 compare 中的代码。
In copy, I'm just literally copying s into t.
在 copy 中，我只是直接把 s 复制到 t 中。
So that literally just changes the value to OX123, also.
所以这直接将值也更改为 OX123。
And if we abstract away all of these addresses,
如果我们将所有这些地址抽象出来，
that's essentially like s and t both pointing to the same place.
这实际上就像 s 和 t 都指向同一个地方。
So if I use s bracket zero, or t bracket zero, they are one and the same.
所以，如果我使用 s 方括号零，或者 t 方括号零，它们就是同一个。
So when I use t bracket zero to use uppercase,
所以，当我使用 t 方括号零来使用大写字母时，
it's changing that lowercase h to capital H.
它将小写字母 h 更改为大写字母 H。
But again, both strings, both pointers are pointing at the same value.
但同样地，两个字符串，两个指针都指向同一个值。
And again, this should be even clearer as of today.
同样地，从今天开始，这一点应该更加清楚。
If I go back into VS Code and, indeed, take these training wheels off,
如果我回到 VS Code 中，并且确实摘掉了这些辅助轮，
and treat string as what it is, char star, which indicates that both s and t
并且将字符串视为它本身，即字符星，这表明 s 和 t 都是
are just addresses, which makes even clearer, syntactically,
地址，这在语法上更加清晰地表明，
that this is probably the picture that's going on underneath the hood.
这可能是引擎盖下正在发生的事情。
Now, just to make the code a little more robust,
现在，为了使代码更健壮，
let me at least be a little careful here.
至少让我在这里小心一点。
If the string length of t is greater than zero, then and only then,
如果 t 的字符串长度大于零，当且仅当，
should I really blindly index into the string and go to location zero.
我才应该真正地盲目地索引到字符串中并转到位置零。
That doesn't really solve the fundamental problem,
但这并没有真正解决根本问题，
but it at least avoids a situation where maybe the user just hits enter,
但至少它避免了一种情况，即用户可能只是按下了回车键，
gives me no characters, and I try to blindly
没有输入任何字符，而我试图盲目地
uppercase something that's not there.
将不存在的东西转换为大写。
But there's still a bug.
但仍然存在错误。
There's still a bug.
仍然存在错误。
So how do I actually solve this?
那么，我该如何真正地解决这个问题呢？
Well, it turns out we need two other functions
事实证明，我们需要另外两个函数。
that we haven't had occasion to use.
我们还没有机会使用。
But these are perhaps the most powerful, and they're
但这些可能是最强大的，而且它们是
going to allow us to solve even grander problems next week when
将会让我们在下周解决更宏大的问题，当
we discuss all the more, things called data structures.
我们讨论更多被称为数据结构的东西时。
But for now, let's very simply solve this idea of copying a string.
但现在，让我们简单地解决这个复制字符串的想法。
Let me go back into VS Code here, and let me give myself one more header file
让我回到 VS Code，再给自己添加一个头文件
that's called standard lib for standard library.
它叫做 standard lib，代表标准库。
So include standard lib dot h, in which both of these functions,
所以包含 standard lib 点 h，其中这两个函数
malloc and free, are declared for me.
malloc 和 free，都已为我声明。
And now, in my code, I'm going to behave a little bit differently here.
现在，在我的代码中，我将采取一些不同的行为。
Clearly, I got into trouble by just blindly copying the addresses.
很明显，我只是盲目地复制地址，导致了麻烦。
What I really want to do when I copy strings, presumably, and then
我真正想做的是，当我复制字符串，假设，然后
uppercase one of them, is I want to create
将其中一个字符串大写，我想创建一个
a duplicate string, a second array that is identical,
一个重复的字符串，一个完全相同的第二个数组，
but is elsewhere in memory.
但它位于内存中的其他位置。
So the way to do this might be as follows.
所以，这样做的方法可能是这样。
Instead of just setting t equal to s, I should really
而不是简单地将 t 设置为 s，我应该真正
call this brand new function called malloc,
调用这个全新的函数叫做 malloc，
which stands for memory allocate, and it takes a single argument,
它代表内存分配，它需要一个参数，
which is just the number of bytes you would like the operating system
它只是你想让操作系统分配给你的字节数。
to allocate for you.
分配给你。
So whether you're using this on Windows, Mac OS, or Linux in our case,
所以无论你是把它用在 Windows、Mac OS 还是 Linux 上，就我们而言，
this is a way I can literally ask the operating system,
这是一种方法，我可以直接问操作系统，
please find for me some number of bytes in the computer's memory
请为我在计算机的内存中找到一些字节
that I can now use for my own purposes.
现在可以用来满足我自己的需求。
So malloc here, I technically need at least three bytes,
所以这里的 malloc，我技术上至少需要三个字节，
but that's not going to be enough because I
但这还不够，因为我
need a fourth for the null character.
还需要一个字节来存放空字符。
So I could put four here.
所以我可以在此处放四个字节。
But that's stupid.
但这很愚蠢。
I shouldn't just hardcode a number like this we've seen.
我应该避免像这样直接硬编码数字，我们已经看到过。
So I could probably do strlen of s to dynamically figure out
所以，我可能可以使用 strlen 函数动态计算
how many bytes I want for the copy.
我想要复制多少字节。
But that, too, is not enough because string length
但这也不够，因为字符串长度
returns the human readable length, so H-I exclamation point.
返回的是人类可读的长度，所以是 H-I 感叹号。
So I think I want a plus one in there, too.
所以，我想在这里加一。
So that just means get the length of whatever the human typed in,
所以，这意味着获取人类输入的长度，
add one for the null character to make sure that we're not undercounting.
加上一个字节来存放空字符，以确保我们没有少算。
Now, what can I then do?
现在，我还能做什么呢？
Unfortunately, I need to do a bit of work here.
不幸的是，我需要在这里做一些工作。
So let me actually go ahead now and do something like this.
所以，让我现在继续做这样的事情。
For int i equals zero, I is less than the string length of s, i plus, plus.
对于 int i 等于零，i 小于 s 的字符串长度，i 加加。
And then inside of this loop, I could copy into the ith location of t,
然后在这个循环中，我可以将 s 的第 i 个位置的内容复制到 t 的第 i 个位置。
whatever is in the ith location of s.
无论 s 的第 i 个位置是什么。
Now, this is a little buggy.
现在，这有点小问题。
One, this is inefficient to keep asking this question.
首先，不断地问这个问题效率低下。
We talked about this in the context of design.
我们之前在设计方面讨论过这个问题。
I should probably improve this by giving myself a variable like n,
我应该通过给自己一个像 n 这样的变量来改进它，
set that equal to the string length, and then do i is less than n
将它设置为字符串长度，然后做 i 小于 n
again, and again, just so I'm not stupidly
一遍又一遍，这样我就不会愚蠢地
calling string length four different times, or three different times.
四次或三次调用字符串长度。
But this, too, is slightly buggy, and this one's very subtle.
但这也有点错误，而且这个错误非常微妙。
This does not fully copy s into t.
这并没有完全将 s 复制到 t 中。
Does anyone see the very subtle bug that I've introduced?
有人看到我引入的非常微妙的错误吗？
Sorry?
什么？
Yeah, I'm forgetting the backslash zero.
是的，我忘记了反斜杠零。
So even though I'm copying H-I exclamation point,
所以即使我复制了 H-I 感叹号，
or whatever the human typed in, I need to go one step further deliberately
或者人类输入的任何内容，我需要故意再走一步
to make sure I also copy the backslash zero,
以确保我也复制了反斜杠零，
or at least manually put it in myself.
或者至少手动把它自己放进去。
So I could solve this by, either doing this up to and through n,
所以我可以通过以下方法解决这个问题，要么一直做到 n，
i is less than or equal to n, or I could plus one here.
i 小于等于 n，或者我可以在此处加 1。
That, too, would be fine.
那也行。
Or if I really want, I could do this, like t bracket
或者如果我真的想要，我可以这样做，比如 t 方括号
three equals, quote unquote, backslash zero.
三个等于号，引号引号，反斜杠零。
But again, I shouldn't get into the habit of hard coding things.
但同样，我不应该养成硬编码的习惯。
I could do string length of s, and that would give me the last location in s,
我可以做 s 的字符串长度，这将给我 s 中的最后一个位置，
which would also work.
这也能奏效。
But that, too, is stupid.
但那也是愚蠢的。
I might as well--
我也可以——
or just unnecessarily complex.
或者只是不必要地复杂。
Let's just do this, change one symbol, and boom.
让我们就这样做，改变一个符号，砰的一声。
Now we're copying all three, and the fourth character, as well.
现在我们正在复制所有三个，以及第四个字符。
All right, so with this said, let's go ahead now
好了，话说到此，现在让我们继续
and make sure that t is indeed of length at least greater than zero.
并确保 t 的长度至少大于零。
Then let's go ahead and capitalize t as before and print out the results.
然后，让我们继续像以前一样将 t 大写，并打印出结果。
So let me go ahead and open my terminal window, make copy, dot slash copy,
所以，让我打开我的终端窗口，制作副本，点斜杠副本，
and I'm going to deliberately type "hi" in lowercase.
我将故意用小写输入“hi”。
And now we should see disparate s and t.
现在我们应该看到不同的 s 和 t。
s is now still lowercase, and T is now capitalized.
s 现在仍然是小写，而 T 现在是大写的。
But why is that exactly?
但为什么正是这样呢？
Well, let me actually go into, say, my computer's memory
好吧，让我实际进入，比如说，我的计算机的内存
again and propose that, if what I had before
再次提出，如果我之前有
was this situation, where s is pointing at this chunk of memory,
是这种情况，s 指向这块内存，
and t was accidentally pointing in that same chunk of memory, what we really
而 t 意外地指向同一块内存，我们真正
want to do is have t point at a new chunk of memory.
想要做的是让 t 指向一块新的内存。
And malloc is what gives us this chunk of memory.
而 malloc 就是给我们这块内存的。
And then using that for loop, can I copy the H, the I, the exclamation point,
然后使用那个 for 循环，我可以复制 H、I、感叹号，
and even the backslash zero.
甚至反斜杠零。
So now, this is a little subtle, but malloc is what gives me
所以现在，这有点微妙，但 malloc 就是给我
access to this new chunk of memory.
访问这块新的内存。
Malloc takes one argument, the number of bytes that you want it to find for you.
Malloc 接受一个参数，即你希望它为你找到的字节数。
Take a guess.
猜猜看。
What value is malloc returning?
malloc 函数返回什么值？
Conceptually, it's returning a chunk of memory, but that's kind of handwavy.
从概念上来说，它返回的是一块内存，但这有点笼统。
What might malloc actually be returning?
malloc 函数实际上可能返回什么？
AUDIENCE: Maybe the pointer to the first character?
观众：可能是指向第一个字符的指针？
SPEAKER 1: Perfect.
演讲者 1：完美。
malloc is returning the address of that chunk of memory, not the last address.
malloc 函数返回的是那块内存的地址，而不是最后一个地址。
The first address.
第一个地址。
And here's a difference with strings.
这里与字符串不同。
This chunk of memory is not magically terminated with null for you.
这块内存不会自动为你以空字符结尾。
I had to do that with for loop. malloc, and in turn, your operating system,
我必须用循环来做。malloc 函数，以及你的操作系统，
does keep track of how big these chunks of memory are.
会跟踪这些内存块的大小。
So even though it's only returning the address
所以即使它只返回
of the first byte of that memory, the operating system
该内存第一个字节的地址，操作系统
is going to know that it used up four bytes here, four bytes here.
会知道它在这里使用了四个字节，这里也使用了四个字节。
And it will keep track of that so that it
它会跟踪这些信息，以便它
doesn't give you an overlapping address in the future
将来不会给你一个重叠的地址
because that would be bad.
因为那会很糟糕。
Your data would get corrupted.
你的数据会损坏。
But you, similarly, have to remember or figure out how many bytes are available
但你，同样，必须记住或计算出有多少字节可用
thereafter.
以后。
It's up to you to manage it, as by putting a null character there
这取决于你来管理，就像在那里添加一个空字符一样
yourself.
你自己。
So if I go back to my code now, let me actually
所以现在我回到我的代码，让我实际
harden this code just a little bit more as follows,
增强一下这段代码，如下所示，
whereby I can do this a little better.
这样我就可以做得更好一点。
If I go back to VS Code here, it turns out, if something goes wrong
如果我回到这里的 VS Code，事实证明，如果出现错误
and I'm out of memory, maybe I've got an old computer,
而且我内存不足，也许我的电脑太旧了，
or maybe I'm typing something way bigger than three characters in,
或者我输入的内容远不止三个字符，
like three billion characters, and the computer
比如三十亿个字符，而电脑
might genuinely run out of memory.
可能真的内存不足。
I actually should be in the habit of doing this.
实际上我应该养成这样的习惯。
If t equals, equals a special symbol called null with two Ls,
如果 t 等于一个特殊的符号，叫做 null，有两个 L，
and I promised this would eventually exist,
我承诺这个符号最终会存在，
I should just return one now, or return two, return negative one,
我现在应该返回 1，或者返回 2，返回负 1，
return any value other than zero, and just abort the program early.
返回任何非零值，然后立即中止程序。
That means, if malloc returns null, there's not enough memory available.
也就是说，如果 malloc 返回 null，说明没有足够的可用内存。
And it turns out, all this time, I'm going to do one other crazy thing,
而且事实证明，一直以来，我还要做一件疯狂的事情，
even though we've not expected you to do this thus far.
即使我们之前并没有要求你这么做。
Technically, when using getstring, getstring,
严格来说，使用 getstring 函数时，
if you read the documentation, the manual, it too can return null.
如果你阅读文档，手册，它也可以返回 null。
Because if you type in a crazy long string,
因为如果你输入一个超长的字符串，
and the computer can't fit it in its memory,
而电脑无法将其放入内存，
getstring needs to signal that to you somehow.
getstring 函数需要以某种方式通知你这一点。
And the documentation actually says that, if getstring returns null,
文档中实际上说明，如果 getstring 返回 null，
then you too should not trust what's in it.
那么你也不能相信其中的内容。
You should just exit the program immediately, in this case.
在这种情况下，你应该立即退出程序。
But there's one other improvement we can make here.
但是，这里还有另外一项改进。
And even though this is making the code seem way longer than it is,
尽管这使得代码看起来比实际长很多，
most of this I've just added is just error checking,
但我添加的大部分内容只是错误检查，
just mindless error checking to make sure that I don't treat s as being
只是无脑的错误检查，以确保我不将 s 视为
valid, or t as being valid when it isn't.
有效的，或者将 t 视为有效的，而实际上它不是。
It turns out this is stupid.
事实证明，这很蠢。
I don't need to reinvent this wheel.
我不需要重新发明轮子。
Certainly, for decades, people have been copying strings, even in C.
当然，几十年来，人们一直在复制字符串，即使在 C 语言中也是如此。
So it turns out there's another fun function called strcopy, wonderfully
事实证明，还有一个有趣的函数叫做 strcopy，非常棒地
enough, that takes the destination as its first argument,
足以，它将目标作为它的第一个参数，
the source as its second argument.
将源作为它的第二个参数。
And that will for me copy s into t, respectively.
它将分别为我将 s 复制到 t 中。
So that does the equivalent of that for loop, including the backslash zero.
因此，它相当于那个 for 循环，包括反斜杠零。
However, there's one other function recall that was on our cheat sheet
然而，还有一点要记住，在我们的备忘单上
a moment ago, whereby malloc is accompanied
刚才，malloc 伴随着
by one other function called Free.
另一个名为 Free 的函数。
So Free is the opposite of malloc.
所以 Free 是 malloc 的反义词。
When you're done with your computer's memory,
当你使用完计算机的内存后，
you're supposed to give it back to Windows, to Mac OS, to Linux
你应该将它归还给 Windows，Mac OS 或 Linux，
so it can reuse it for something else.
以便它可以将其用于其他用途。
And frankly, if you've ever been using your computer for hours
坦率地说，如果你曾经连续使用你的计算机几个小时
on end, days on end, and maybe it's getting slower, and slower,
甚至连续几天，也许它变得越来越慢，
maybe it's Photoshop, maybe it's a really big document, generally,
可能是 Photoshop，可能是非常大的文档，一般来说，
really big files consume lots and lots of memory.
非常大的文件会消耗大量的内存。
If the humans who wrote that software, be it Photoshop or something else,
如果编写该软件的人类，无论是 Photoshop 还是其他软件，
wrote buggy code and kept using malloc, malloc, malloc, malloc, asking
编写了有错误的代码，并不断使用 malloc，malloc，malloc，malloc，要求
for more and more memory, but they never call the opposite function, Free,
获取越来越多的内存，但他们从未调用相反的函数 Free，
your computer might actually run out of memory.
你的计算机可能真的会内存不足。
And typically, the symptom is that it gets so darn
通常，症状是它变得非常糟糕
slow it becomes annoying to use.
缓慢，以至于变得令人讨厌使用。
And frankly, the mouse starts moving very slowly, maybe the thing freezes
坦率地说，鼠标开始移动非常缓慢，也许它会完全冻结
altogether, the computer crashes.
在一起，计算机崩溃。
Bad things happen when you run out of memory.
内存不足时会发生不好的事情。
So in my case here, if I go back to VS Code,
所以在我的例子中，如果我回到 VS Code，
it's actually on me in this language called C to actually manage
实际上，在这门名为 C 的语言中，由我来管理
the memory myself so that, when I have called malloc,
我自己使用的内存，这样，当我调用 malloc 时，
thereafter, I had better free that same memory.
之后，我最好释放相同的内存。
Now, I don't want to free it right away.
现在，我不想立即释放它。
I want to free it when I'm done with it.
我想在完成使用后释放它。
So frankly, the very last thing I'm going to do in my program
所以，坦率地说，在我的程序中，我要做的最后一件事
here is called Free on t because t is what I malloced up here.
在这里是调用 Free 在 t 上，因为 t 是我在这里分配的。
So at the very bottom of my program, I should free t.
所以，在我的程序的底部，我应该释放 t。
And then just to be super nitpicky, let me return zero just
然后，为了过于挑剔，让我返回零，只是
to signify success at this point.
为了表示在此处成功。
Now, there's a slight asymmetry, which is a little inconsistent here.
现在，这里存在轻微的不对称，这有点不一致。
Even though getstring, I'm going to imply,
即使 getstring 会为我分配内存，它实际上确实使用了 malloc。
is still allocating memory for me, it actually does use malloc.
getstring and CS50's other functions are special.
getstring 和 CS50 的其他函数很特殊。
They manage memory for you, so you do not and should not free
它们会为你管理内存，所以你不应该也不需要释放
memory that getstring returns to you.
getstring 返回给你的内存。
We handle all of that for you.
我们会为你处理所有这些。
But that's a training wheel that's going to be taken off as of this week
但这只是一个辅助工具，本周起就要被拿掉了
anyway, so it's kind of moot.
所以它有点无关紧要。
So not to worry.
所以不用担心。
But I'm only freeing memory that malloced.
但我只释放 malloc 分配的内存。
All right.
好的。
Null, then, means the--
那么，null 表示——
what is null?
什么是 null？
It is just an address, and it's literally the address zero.
它只是一个地址，实际上就是地址零。
So there's this theme.
所以有一个主题。
N-U-L recall, was the terminating symbol,
N-U-L，还记得吗？是终止符，
which just means the string ends here.
这意味着字符串在这里结束。
N-U-L-L, which is not greatly named, but it's what humans went with years ago,
N-U-L-L，名字不太好，但这是人类几年前选择的，
just means that this is the address zero.
只是意味着这是地址零。
And what your computer does is, even though I've been playfully saying that,
而你的电脑所做的就是，尽管我一直戏谑地说，
oh, in the top left is address zero, and then one, and then two, and then three,
哦，左上角是地址零，然后是一，然后是二，然后是三，
the address zero is hands off.
地址零是不能使用的。
It's kind of a wasted byte that your computer should never
它是一个浪费的字节，你的电脑永远不应该
use because the computer uses zero as a special sentinel value, null,
使用，因为电脑使用零作为特殊的哨兵值，null，
to signify error.
来表示错误。
So we're spending one byte out of billions nowadays just to make sure
所以我们现在从数十亿字节中花费一个字节，只是为了确保
that there's a special symbol that's coming back that can
有一个特殊的符号会返回，它可以
indicate when something has gone wrong.
指示何时出现错误。
All right.
好的。
That was a mouthful.
这可真是一大口。
Any questions on this copying of strings, this malloc-ing,
关于字符串的复制、malloc 分配、
or this freeing?
或者释放，有什么问题吗？
Oh, all right.
哦，好的。
So let me give you a tool with which to make some of this stuff easier,
所以让我给你一个工具，让你更容易地完成一些这些工作，
so that when you make mistakes or have bugs, as you invariably will,
这样当你犯错误或出现 bug 时，因为你肯定会犯，
you can chase them down without having to raise your hand,
你可以追查它们，而不用举手，
without having to ask the duck.
不用去问鸭子。
You actually have more technical tools with which
你实际上拥有更多技术工具，可以
to diagnose the problem yourself.
自己诊断问题。
And there's this new tool that we'll introduce today called valgrind.
我们今天将介绍一个新工具，叫做 valgrind。
And valgrind's purpose in life is to check your usage of memory for you.
valgrind 的作用是为你检查你的内存使用情况。
Admittedly, it's an older program.
诚然，它是一个比较旧的程序。
It's pretty arcane in terms of its interface,
它的界面非常神秘，
and there's just going to be a mess of output on the screen.
屏幕上只会出现一大堆输出。
But there's going to be certain patterns of mistakes that you'll notice,
但你将会注意到某些错误模式，
and I'll demonstrate a couple of them now so you can
现在我会演示几个，这样你就可以
see where and how you might go wrong.
看看你在哪里以及如何犯错误。
So I'm going to go over to VS Code here.
所以我将转到 VS Code 这里。
I'm going to create a program called memory.c that is deliberately buggy,
我将创建一个名为 memory.c 的程序，它故意包含 bug，
but it's not going to be obviously buggy at first.
但它一开始不会明显地出现错误。
So by that I mean this.
我的意思是。
Let me do include standard io.h.
让我包含标准io.h。
Let me also include proactively standard lib.h so I can use malloc.
让我主动包含标准lib.h，这样我就可以使用malloc。
Let me declare main with no command line arguments,
让我声明一个没有命令行参数的main函数。
and let me do something very simple.
让我做一些非常简单的事情。
Instead of just declaring an int called X, let me be a little crazy
而不是仅仅声明一个名为X的int，让我有点疯狂
and manually allocate this memory myself.
并自己手动分配这块内存。
So int X just gives me an integer, and it has since week one.
所以 int X 只是给了我一个整数，从第一周开始就是这样。
But now that I have malloc, I can kind of take control over this process.
但现在我有malloc了，我可以控制这个过程。
So let me declare, not an int, but an int star called X. So
所以让我声明，不是一个int，而是一个叫做X的int指针。所以
give me the address of an integer, and let
给我一个整数的地址，并让我
me store there the return value of malloc by asking malloc for, let's say,
将malloc的返回值存储在那里，让malloc给我，比如，
four bytes.
四个字节。
So I know that ints are four bytes.
我知道int是四个字节。
If I want four bytes, I just tell malloc, give me four bytes.
如果我想要四个字节，我只需要告诉malloc，给我四个字节。
Now, frankly, this is a little stupid.
坦白说，这有点愚蠢。
I shouldn't just assume that the int is always
我不应该假设int总是
going to be four bytes on everyone's computer.
在每个人的计算机上都是四个字节。
So there's this function you can start using called sizeof, or this operator,
所以有一个你可以开始使用的函数叫做sizeof，或者说是一个运算符，
technically, where you can say sizeof int.
严格来说，你可以说sizeof int。
And even if you're on an older computer, for instance, really old at this point,
即使你使用的是一台老式电脑，比如，现在真的很老了，
sizeof int will return the correct value, no matter what.
sizeof int 无论如何都会返回正确的值。
You don't have to assume that it's, in fact, four.
你不必假设它实际上是四个。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
I'd actually like more than this number of ints.
我实际上想要比这个数字更多的int。
Let me actually treat X as an array of integers.
让我实际上将X视为一个整数数组。
So actually, if I want an array of integers, I could do this.
所以实际上，如果我想要一个整数数组，我可以这样做。
Give me three integers.
给我三个整数。
But no, no.
但不行，不行。
Let me not do week two syntax.
让我不要使用第二周的语法。
Let me do this myself as follows.
让我自己这样做。
Let me treat this as three times the size of an int.
让我把它当作一个int大小的三倍。
So that's technically going to give me 12 bytes.
所以这在技术上会给我12个字节。
But this makes X effectively an array.
但这使得X实际上成为一个数组。
And this is kind of deliberate now because if an array is
现在这有点故意，因为如果一个数组是
just contiguous memory, and malloc returns to you
仅仅是连续的内存，而malloc会返回给你
a chunk of contiguous memory, you can treat what comes back from malloc
一块连续的内存，你可以将malloc返回的结果
as an array.
视为一个数组。
And indeed, that's what we're doing as strings.
实际上，我们就是这样处理字符串的。
We're treating chunks of memory as arrays of chars.
我们把内存块当作字符数组。
So let me do something arbitrary here.
所以让我在这里做一些任意的事情。
Let me go to X bracket one and set it equal to 72.
让我去X方括号1，并将它设置为72。
X bracket two, set it equal to 73.
X方括号2，设置为73。
X bracket three, set it equal to 33.
X方括号3，设置为33。
And we did this a couple of weeks ago.
我们几周前就做过了。
That's "hi" but in Ascii code.
这是“hi”，但使用的是ASCII码。
Let me go ahead and make memory, and it seems to work fine.
让我继续创建内存，看起来工作正常。
Let me do dot slash memory, and no problem.
让我执行点斜杠内存，没问题。
There's no error messages from the compiler.
编译器没有报错信息。
There's no runtime errors when I actually run the code.
当我实际运行代码时，没有运行时错误。
But does anyone see any of the bugs thus far?
但是有人看到目前为止的任何错误吗？
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
Let me look a little in the back.
让我稍微往后看一看。
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: Does it not know when the array ends?
观众：它不知道数组什么时候结束吗？
SPEAKER 1: It doesn't seem to know when the array ends.
演讲者 1：它似乎不知道数组什么时候结束。
Or more specifically, I'm not respecting when
更具体地说，我没有遵守什么时候
the array ends because I'm sort of stupidly
数组结束，因为我有点愚蠢地
starting at one, then two then three.
从 1 开始，然后是 2，然后是 3。
But technically, if I asked for three of these things,
但从技术上讲，如果我要求这三样东西，
I should have done bracket zero, bracket one, bracket two.
我应该做方括号 0，方括号 1，方括号 2。
And there's a second more subtle bug that you would only know from today.
还有一个更微妙的错误，你只有今天才知道。
Yeah.
是的。
OK, I don't necessarily know when one integer ends and the next one begins.
好的，我不一定知道一个整数什么时候结束，下一个整数什么时候开始。
That's actually not a problem, because on a given system,
这实际上不是问题，因为在给定系统上，
integers are always the same size.
整数始终是相同的大小。
So the computer can be smart enough to go from here, four bytes this way,
所以计算机可以足够智能，从这里开始，四个字节这样，
four bytes this way, four bytes this way.
四个字节这样，四个字节这样。
That's OK.
这没问题。
Strings are problematic because who knows how big the sentence was
字符串存在问题，因为谁知道人类输入的句子有多大
that the human typed in.
人类输入的句子有多大。
But there's a more subtle bug.
但还有一个更微妙的错误。
What have I not done?
我还没有做什么？
I didn't call free.
我没有调用 free。
So I didn't practice what I just preached.
所以我没有实践我刚刚宣讲的内容。
Anytime I malloc, I call free.
每次我调用 malloc，我都会调用 free。
But again, per my terminal window, neither of these bugs seem obvious.
但是，根据我的终端窗口，这两个错误似乎都不明显。
You might submit this code, or deploy it to your software,
你可能会提交此代码，或将其部署到你的软件中，
and be none the wiser.
而且浑然不觉。
But a tool like valgrind can actually help you find these things.
但是像 valgrind 这样的工具实际上可以帮助你找到这些东西。
So let me increase the size of my terminal window.
所以让我增加我的终端窗口的大小。
Let me run this command valgrind on my program.
让我在我的程序上运行这个命令 valgrind。
So dot slash memory is how I ran it a moment ago.
所以点斜杠 memory 是我刚才运行它的方式。
Just like debug50, you type before the name of your program.
就像 debug50 一样，你在程序名称前面输入。
Valgrind, you type before the name of your program.
Valgrind，你在程序名称前面输入。
And the output is going to look crazy, but this is useful.
并且输出看起来会很疯狂，但这是有用的。
Why?
为什么？
So notice at the very top of this, we're just seeing what version of valgrind
所以注意这里的最上面，我们只是看到了 valgrind 的版本
we're using and what command we ran.
我们正在使用，以及我们运行了什么命令。
But this starts to get juicy, and I'll highlight this here.
但这里开始变得有趣，我将在这里突出显示。
Invalid write of size four invalid write.
大小为 4 的无效写入 无效写入。
So writing means changing information, like setting a value or assigning it a.
所以写入意味着更改信息，例如设置一个值或为其分配一个。
Value and this is useful here.
值，这里很有用。
The problem is in memory.c at line nine.
问题出在 memory.c 的第 9 行。
So colon nine means line nine.
所以冒号 9 表示第 9 行。
All right, so let me go back to my code, look at line nine, and oh, interesting.
好的，让我回到我的代码，看看第 9 行，哦，有意思。
So invalid write of size four.
所以大小为 4 的无效写入。
So it's cryptic, but size four I know is the size of an integer.
所以它很神秘，但我知道大小 4 是一个整数的大小。
So I'm probably doing something stupid on line nine involving
所以，我可能在第九行做了一些愚蠢的事情，涉及到
changing an integer.
更改一个整数。
And sure enough, even though it's not super obvious, X bracket three,
果然，尽管并不明显，X 方括号 3，
oh, obviously, this doesn't exist.
哦，显然，这不存在。
So I have to change the problem.
所以我必须改变问题。
One and two were OK, even though it's logically the wrong thing.
1 和 2 还可以，尽管逻辑上是错误的。
Now I think this will get rid of this error.
现在我认为这会消除这个错误。
So let me actually clear my terminal window and make it bigger again.
所以，让我实际清除我的终端窗口，并再次将其放大。
Let me recompile my code because I made a change.
让我重新编译我的代码，因为我做了一些更改。
Let me rerun valgrind of dot slash memory.
让我重新运行 valgrind 的点斜杠内存。
And now, that error went away.
现在，那个错误消失了。
There's a mess of output here, but that error went away.
这里有一堆输出，但那个错误消失了。
But this is interesting here now.
但现在这里很有趣。
12 bytes in one blocks are definitely lost in loss record one of one.
在一个块中的 12 个字节肯定在第一个损失记录中丢失了。
So unnecessarily verbose, but the hint here
所以，不必要的冗长，但这里的提示
is that I somehow lost some bytes, otherwise known as a memory leak.
是我不知何故丢失了一些字节，也就是所谓的内存泄漏。
So earlier, when I described an imaginary bad programmer
所以，早些时候，当我描述一个想象中的糟糕程序员时
who kept calling malloc, malloc, malloc, and never freeing,
他不断调用 malloc，malloc，malloc，但从未释放，
that's what's called a memory leak, where
这就是所谓的内存泄漏，在这种情况下，
you're sort of losing track of your memory and never freeing it again.
你有点失去了对内存的跟踪，并且再也没有释放它。
So I've definitely lost 12 bytes in one block, whatever a block is,
所以，我肯定在一个块中丢失了 12 个字节，无论一个块是什么，
in this case.
在这种情况下。
This is a little less obvious.
这不太明显。
It's up to us to notice that, OK, wait a minute, memory.c line six is somehow
我们要注意到这一点，好吧，等等，memory.c 的第六行不知何故
germane.
相关。
Let me go back to--
让我回到——
oh, this is where I called malloc.
哦，这是我调用 malloc 的地方。
And valgrind doesn't necessarily know when I should free the memory.
而 valgrind 并不一定知道我应该什么时候释放内存。
That's up to me, but I should probably free it at the end of my function
这取决于我，但我可能应该在我的函数结束时释放它，因为一旦你释放了内存，
when I'm definitely done with it, because once you free your memory,
当我真正完成时，因为一旦你释放了你的内存，
you should not touch that variable again, unless you actually
你就不要再触碰那个变量了，除非你真正地
change what its value is.
改变它的值。
So now, as I've done this, and this program to be clear
所以，现在，当我这样做时，这个程序明确地说
does nothing useful.
没有做任何有用的事情。
This is just an intellectual exercise, not anything productive.
这只是一个智力练习，不是任何有成效的事情。
Let me do make memory one last time.
让我最后一次运行 make memory。
Let's do valgrind, dot slash memory.
让我们运行 valgrind，点斜杠内存。
And let me grow my terminal window again and hit enter.
让我再次扩大我的终端窗口，然后按回车键。
And even though it's still kind of output,
尽管它仍然是某种输出，
it's still kind of cryptic, at least it says no leaks are possible.
它仍然有点神秘，至少它说没有泄漏的可能性。
So now this is my own sort of teaching assistant telling me
所以，现在，这是我自己的教学助手告诉我
before I submit the code, or before I deploy it
在我提交代码之前，或者在我部署它之前
to production in real software, that at least there
到真正的软件生产中，至少在那里
seem to be no memory related errors.
似乎没有与内存相关的错误。
So valgrind is not for logical bugs.
所以 valgrind 不是用于逻辑错误。
It's not for syntax errors.
它不是用于语法错误。
It's for memory related bugs, as of today.
它是用于与内存相关的错误，截至目前。
Questions on any of that?
对此有任何问题吗？
No?
不？
OK, so what else can go wrong?
好吧，还有什么可能出错？
We mentioned these in the past.
我们之前提到了这些。
It turns out that garbage values are a thing.
事实证明，垃圾值确实存在。
And recall that, if you declare a variable
请记住，如果你声明一个变量
but don't give it a value with an equal sign,
但没有用等号赋予它一个值，
and you just blindly start using it, like printing it out, or doing math
你只是盲目地开始使用它，比如打印它或进行数学运算
on it, you might be manipulating a garbage value, which
你可能正在操作一个垃圾值，它
is some number that's essentially remnants of your computer
本质上是你的计算机剩余的一些数字
having been on for a while.
运行了一段时间。
Because if you're using this canvas and reusing it again,
因为如果你使用这个画布，并且再次使用它，
and again, surely there's going to be patterns of zeros and ones
一次又一次地，肯定会有零和一的模式
there that you didn't put there yourself, at least in the moment.
在那里，至少在那一刻，你不是自己放的。
They might be remnants of the past.
它们可能是过去的残留。
So garbage values are values of variables that you did not proactively
所以垃圾值是你没有主动设置的变量的值
set yourself as intended.
按预期设置。
So we can actually see this.
所以我们实际上可以看到这一点。
Let me actually go ahead and whip up a really quick program here
让我先快速编写一个程序
after shrinking my terminal window.
缩小我的终端窗口后。
Let me close memory.c.
让我关闭 memory.c。
Let me go ahead and open garbage.c.
让我打开 garbage.c。
And in here, I'll do include.
在这里，我将进行包含。
How about standard io.h?
标准输入输出呢？
Let's include standard lib.h
我们包含标准库。
Actually, we don't even need standard lib.h.
实际上，我们甚至不需要标准库。
Let's go ahead and include standard io.h and then int main void.
我们包含标准输入输出，然后是 int main void。
And then inside of the curly braces, let's
然后在大括号内，让我们
give me a really big array of scores, like 1,024 scores,
给我一个很大的分数数组，比如 1024 个分数，
like if it's a really busy semester.
就像一个非常繁忙的学期。
And then let me go ahead and just blindly iterate from i
然后让我继续盲目地从 i 开始迭代
equals zero on up to i is less than 1,024.
等于 0 直到 i 小于 1024。
And I'm not going to bother with constants.
我不会理会常量。
I'm just going to play around with these numbers for a moment.
我只是想玩玩这些数字。
And, oh, thank you.
哦，谢谢。
Oh, cookies for you.
哦，给你的饼干。
OK.
好的。
OK, here we go.
好的，我们开始吧。
OK, come on up.
好的，上来吧。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Fair is fair.
公平就是公平。
OK.
好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
OK.
好的。
OK, now everyone's really paying attention.
好的，现在每个人都非常认真地听着。
All right.
好的。
So in my loop here, I'm just going to do something stupid,
所以在我的循环中，我将做一些愚蠢的事情，
like print out all of the values in the scores array using percent i,
比如使用百分号 i 打印分数数组中的所有值，
even though I did not put anything in this array.
尽管我没有在这个数组中放任何东西。
So on line five, I'm obviously declaring an array
所以，在第 5 行，我显然声明了一个数组
of size 1,024 for that many ints, but I'm never
大小为 1024，用于存放这些整数，但我永远不会
actually putting values in there myself, or with getint, or any other function.
实际上，我本人在里面放入了值，或者使用 getint 或者其他函数。
So there's garbage values there.
所以这里面都是垃圾值。
There's presumably 1,024 garbage values there,
那里大概有 1024 个垃圾值，
and we can now actually see them.
现在我们可以看到它们了。
Let me make my terminal window bigger.
让我把我的终端窗口放大。
Let me make garbage, no pun intended, dot slash garbage.
让我创建垃圾，没有双关语的意思，点斜杠垃圾。
And there's going to be way more than even fit on the screen.
而且它们的数量远远超过屏幕能显示的。
But who cares?
但是谁在乎呢？
We just need to see a few.
我们只需要看到几个。
There are some of the garbage values in the array.
这些是数组中的部分垃圾值。
So make super clear that when you create variables of your own,
所以要非常清楚，当你创建自己的变量时，
you do not give them values of your own.
不要给他们赋予自己的值。
Who knows what may be there?
谁知道那里会有什么？
In some cases, it gets automatically initialized for you to all zeros,
在某些情况下，它会自动初始化为全零，
but that is not always the case.
但并非总是如此。
And in general, distrust the variable unless you yourself
一般来说，不要信任变量，除非你自己
have put a value there.
给它赋予了一个值。
So how now might we leverage this to--
那么，我们现在如何利用它来 -
how now might we think about potential problems?
我们现在如何思考潜在问题？
Well, consider this code here, which this program, too,
好吧，考虑一下这里面的代码，这个程序也是一样，
is more for discussion than actual utility, where at the top of it,
它更适合讨论，而不是实际应用，在代码的顶部，
I declare a variable called x and a variable called y,
我声明了一个名为 x 的变量和一个名为 y 的变量，
both of type pointer.
它们都是指针类型。
So x and y are supposed to be the addresses of two integers.
所以 x 和 y 应该分别是两个整数的地址。
malloc, the size of an int, and stored in x.
用 malloc 分配一个 int 的大小，然后存储到 x 中。
So I'm giving myself space for x, even though, obviously, I
所以我给自己分配了 x 的空间，虽然很明显，我
could have done this weeks ago by just not using the star,
几周前我就可以通过不使用星号来做到这一点，
and just say give me an int x.
直接说给我一个 int x。
Now I'm doing it the low level way, malloc-ing the x for myself.
现在我正在用低级方式来做，自己用 malloc 分配 x。
I'm then saying go to x, go to that address in memory,
然后我说去 x，去内存中的那个地址，
and put the number 42 there.
然后把数字 42 放到那里。
I'm then saying go to y and put the unlucky number 13 there.
然后我说去 y，把不吉利的数字 13 放到那里。
But what's worrisome about this line here?
但是这里这行代码有什么令人担忧的地方呢？
After this line, this line, this line, something's bad, I think.
在这行代码之后，这行代码之后，这行代码之后，我想有些地方不对劲。
Yeah, I never allocated memory for y.
是的，我从来都没有为 y 分配内存。
So specifically, I never assigned y a value,
所以具体来说，我从未给 y 赋值，
which means it's a garbage value, which is still a number.
这意味着它是一个垃圾值，它仍然是一个数字。
Maybe it's zero.
也许它是零。
Maybe it's a big number.
也许它是一个大数字。
Maybe it's a negative number.
也许它是一个负数。
And if it's a positive number, it could be an actual address
如果它是一个正数，它可能是一个真实的地址
somewhere in the computer's memory.
在计算机内存中的某个地方。
But star y means go there.
但是星号 y 意味着去那里。
Who knows what memory I'm touching?
谁知道我碰到了什么内存？
That's how computers crash if you touch memory that you're not supposed to.
这就是如果你触碰了不应该触碰的内存，计算机就会崩溃的原因。
So let me pretend that I didn't at least do this and let me just forge ahead
所以让我假装我至少没有这样做，让我继续前进
and set y equal to x so they're the same.
把 y 设置为等于 x，这样它们就一样了。
And I think what that would mean is now, if I do star y
我认为这意味着，现在，如果我使用星号 y
and go to the address, that's the same thing as going to the address in x.
然后去那个地址，这和去 x 中的地址是一样的。
And I think this will have the effect of changing the 42 to 13.
我认为这将改变42到13。
So this code is correct, so long as I don't blindly dereference y
所以这段代码是正确的，只要我不盲目地解除对y的引用
by using star y notation.
使用星号y表示法。
So this gets a little abstract, even though this is just an exercise here.
所以这有点抽象，尽管这只是一个练习。
And our friend Nick Parlante, a professor at Stanford,
我们的朋友Nick Parlante，斯坦福大学教授，
wonderfully put together a little claymation
非常棒地制作了一个小粘土动画
that's fun to take a look at, whereby if I go ahead and open up this file,
很有趣，如果我继续打开这个文件，
we'll be introduced to someone who's a little famous
我们会认识一个在计算机领域小有名气的人
in the world of computing named Binky, if we could dim the lights
名叫Binky，如果我们能调暗灯光
and take a look at what bad things can happen if you
看看如果你没有正确管理内存会发生什么坏事。
don't manage your memory properly.
不要正确地管理内存。
SPEAKER 5: Hey, Binky.
说话者5：嘿，Binky。
Wake up.
醒醒。
It's time for pointer fun.
现在是玩指针的时候了。
SPEAKER 6: What's that?
说话者6：什么？
Learn about pointers?
学习指针？
Oh, goody.
哦，太好了。
SPEAKER 5: Well, to get started, I guess we're going to need a couple pointers.
说话者5：好吧，要开始，我想我们需要几个指针。
SPEAKER 6: OK.
说话者6：好的。
This code allocates two pointers, which can point to integers.
这段代码分配了两个指针，它们可以指向整数。
SPEAKER 5: OK.
说话者5：好的。
Well, I see the two pointers, but they don't seem to be pointing to anything.
好吧，我看到这两个指针，但它们似乎没有指向任何东西。
SPEAKER 6: That's right.
说话者6：没错。
Initially, pointers don't point to anything.
最初，指针不指向任何东西。
The things they point to are called pointees, and setting them up
它们指向的东西叫做被指向物，设置它们
is a separate step.
是一个单独的步骤。
SPEAKER 5: Oh, right, right.
说话者5：哦，对，对。
I knew that.
我知道。
The pointees are separate.
被指向物是分开的。
So how do you allocate a pointee?
那么如何分配一个被指向物呢？
SPEAKER 6: OK.
说话者6：好的。
Well, this code allocates a new integer pointee,
好吧，这段代码分配了一个新的整数被指向物，
and this part sets x to point to it.
这部分将x设置为指向它。
SPEAKER 5: Hey, that looks better.
说话者5：嘿，看起来好多了。
So make it do something.
所以让它做点什么。
SPEAKER 6: OK, I'll dereference the pointer x to store the number
说话者6：好的，我将解除对指针x的引用以将数字
42 into its pointee.
42存储到它的被指向物中。
For this trick, I'll need my magic wand of dereferencing.
为了这个技巧，我需要我的解引用魔杖。
SPEAKER 5: Your magic wand of dereferencing?
说话者5：你的解引用魔杖？
That's great.
太棒了。
SPEAKER 6: This is what the code looks like.
说话者6：这就是代码的样子。
I'll just set up the number and--
我只要设置数字，然后——
SPEAKER 5: Hey, look.
说话者5：嘿，看。
There it goes.
它开始了。
So doing a dereference on x follows the arrow
所以对x进行解引用会沿着箭头
to access its pointee, in this case, to store 42 in there.
访问它的被指向物，在这种情况下，将42存储在那里。
Hey, try using it to store the number 13 through the other pointer, y.
嘿，试试用另一个指针y存储数字13。
SPEAKER 6: OK.
说话者6：好的。
I'll just go over here to y and get the number 13 set up,
我只要到y这里去，设置好数字13，
and then take the wand of dereferencing, and just--
然后拿起解引用魔杖，然后——
whoa.
哇。
SPEAKER 5: Oh, hey, that didn't work.
说话者 5：哦，嘿，那没起作用。
Say, Binky, I don't think dereferencing y
Binky，我认为对 y 进行解引用不是一个好主意
is a good idea because setting up the pointee is a separate step,
因为设置指针所指向的对象是一个单独的步骤，
and I don't think we ever did it.
而且我认为我们从未这样做过。
SPEAKER 6: Good point.
说话者 6：说得有道理。
SPEAKER 5: Yeah, we allocated the pointer y,
说话者 5：是的，我们分配了指针 y，
but we never set it to point to a pointee.
但我们从未将其设置为指向一个指针所指向的对象。
SPEAKER 6: Very observant.
说话者 6：观察力敏锐。
SPEAKER 5: Hey, you're looking good there, Binky.
说话者 5：嘿，Binky，你看起来很棒。
Can you fix it so that y points to the same pointee as x?
你能修复一下，让 y 指向与 x 相同的指针所指向的对象吗？
SPEAKER 6: Sure.
说话者 6：当然。
I'll use my magic wand of pointer assignment.
我会使用我的指针分配魔杖。
SPEAKER 5: Is that going to be a problem like before?
说话者 5：会像之前一样出现问题吗？
SPEAKER 6: No, this doesn't touch the pointees.
说话者 6：不，这不会影响指针所指向的对象。
It just changes one pointer to point to the same thing as another.
它只是改变了一个指针，使其指向与另一个指针相同的内容。
SPEAKER 5: Oh, I see.
说话者 5：哦，我明白了。
Now y points to the same place as x.
现在 y 指向与 x 相同的位置。
So wait.
所以等等。
Now y is fixed.
现在 y 被修复了。
It has a pointee, so you can try the wand of dereferencing again
它有一个指针所指向的对象，所以你可以再次尝试解引用魔杖
to send the 13 over.
将 13 传递过去。
SPEAKER 6: OK.
说话者 6：好的。
Here it goes.
开始了。
SPEAKER 5: Hey, look at that.
说话者 5：嘿，看看吧。
Now dereferencing works on y.
现在对 y 进行解引用起作用了。
And because the pointers are sharing that one pointee, they both see the 13.
由于指针共享一个指针所指向的对象，因此它们都看到了 13。
SPEAKER 6: Yeah, sharing.
说话者 6：是的，共享。
Whatever.
随便啦。
So are we going to switch places now?
所以我们现在要交换位置了吗？
SPEAKER 5: Oh, look.
说话者 5：哦，看。
We're out of time.
时间到了。
SPEAKER 6: But--
说话者 6：但是--
SPEAKER 1: All right.
说话者 1：好的。
So our thanks to Nick.
所以感谢尼克。
I can only imagine how many hours he spent making that happen.
我只能想象他花了多少时间才让这一切发生。
But hopefully, it gives you more of a visual as to what's happening when
但希望这能让你对以下情况有一个更直观的了解
we're dereferencing these addresses, and going to them, and assigning values,
我们正在对这些地址进行解引用，然后访问它们，并为其赋值，
and as per Binky's explosion there, what happens when you dereference values you
以及正如 Binky 那里的爆炸所示，当你对不应该解引用的值进行解引用时会发生什么，
shouldn't.
不应该。
So related thereto, let me do this.
所以与之相关的是，让我来做这个。
Let me go over to VS Code and open up now a program
让我去 VS Code 并打开一个程序
I wrote in advance called swap.c.
我提前编写了一个名为 swap.c 的程序。
And the purpose of this program is just to swap the value of two variables.
该程序的目的是交换两个变量的值。
So let me walk over to the code here and point out that, in main, I've got
所以让我走到这里的代码并指出，在 main 中，我有
two variables, x and y.
两个变量，x 和 y。
No pointers, no magic there.
没有指针，没有魔法。
Just x and y are one and two respectively.
只有 x 和 y 分别是 1 和 2。
I've got a couple of printfs here saying x is %i, y is %i, passing in x and y,
我在这里有几个 printf 语句，分别输出 x 是 %i，y 是 %i，并将 x 和 y 传递进去，
just so we can see that x and y are indeed one and two.
这样我们就能看到 x 和 y 确实是 1 和 2。
I'm then calling a function called swap, which
我随后调用了一个叫做 swap 的函数，它
presumably, should swap the two values.
应该可以交换这两个值。
And then I'm just printing the exact same thing again,
然后我又打印了完全相同的内容，
my hoping that it's first going to say one, two,
希望它会先说一，二，
then it's going to say two, one, thus achieving the idea of swapping here.
然后会说二，一，从而实现这里的交换想法。
And here's swap.
这就是 swap 函数。
Swap takes in two integers, a and b, though I
swap 函数接收两个整数，a 和 b，尽管我
could have called them whatever I want.
可以随心所欲地命名它们。
It temporarily puts a in temp.
它暂时将 a 存储到 temp 中。
It then changes a to b.
然后它将 a 更改为 b。
It then changes b to temp, and then that's it.
然后它将 b 更改为 temp，然后就完成了。
It's a void function, so it doesn't return anything,
它是一个 void 函数，所以它不返回任何值，
but it does all of the mathematical work in here.
但它在这里完成了所有的数学运算。
So this is curious, though, because when it runs,
所以这很有趣，因为当它运行时，
let me open up my terminal window here.
让我打开我的终端窗口。
Make swap, dot slash swap, I should see one, two, and then two, one.
执行 make swap，然后 ./swap，我应该看到一，二，然后二，一。
But no, even though I do think this is logically correct.
但是没有，虽然我认为这是逻辑上正确的。
And actually, we're almost out of stock, but we do have another box of cookies
实际上，我们的库存快没了，但我们还有一盒饼干
here.
在这里。
Can we get one volunteer to come on up here maybe?
我们可以找一个志愿者上来吗？
OK, how about you?
好吧，你怎么样？
Yes, in the pink, come on up.
是的，穿粉衣服的，上来吧。
A round of applause, though, really, it's about the cookies now, I know.
来点掌声吧，不过，说实话，现在主要是关于饼干，我知道。
OK.
好的。
And what is your name?
你叫什么名字？
SPEAKER 7: My name is Caleb, and I'm a first year concentrating
发言者 7：我叫 Caleb，我是一年级学生，主修
in computer science.
计算机科学。
SPEAKER 1: All right, welcome.
发言者 1：好的，欢迎。
Please stand behind the desk here.
请站在桌子后面。
No, you can stand.
不用，你可以站着。
It's fine.
没关系。
SPEAKER 7: OK.
发言者 7：好的。
SPEAKER 1: We have two glasses of water, colored, blue,
发言者 1：我们有两杯水，分别是蓝色的
and orange, respectively.
和橙色的。
And I would like you to swap the values of these two variables
我希望你交换这两个变量的值
so that the orange liquid goes in the blue glass,
这样橙色的液体就可以倒入蓝色的杯子中，
and the blue liquid goes in the orange glass.
蓝色的液体就倒入橙色的杯子中。
SPEAKER 7: Seems like a bad idea.
发言者 7：这似乎不是一个好主意。
SPEAKER 1: Why is that?
发言者 1：为什么？
SPEAKER 7: Because I can't get one out to put the other one in because there's
发言者 7：因为我无法把一种液体倒出来，然后把另一种液体倒进去，因为没有
no third glass.
第三个杯子。
SPEAKER 1: OK correct because we do have what we generally
发言者 1：好的，你说得对，因为我们通常
call a temporary variable here.
称之为临时变量。
So here, let me give you a variable called temp.
所以，这里，我给你一个叫做 temp 的变量。
And if I give you this, how does that change things?
如果你有了它，会改变什么？
SPEAKER 7: Well, now, I can take one.
发言者 7：好吧，现在我可以拿一个。
SPEAKER 1: OK.
发言者 1：好的。
SPEAKER 7: Very carefully.
发言者 7：要非常小心。
SPEAKER 1: Nice.
发言者 1：不错。
SPEAKER 7: I'm trying.
发言者 7：我正在尝试。
SPEAKER 1: OK.
说话者 1：好的。
SPEAKER 7: There we go.
说话者 7：好了。
SPEAKER 1: And now you can put b into a, if you will.
说话者 1：现在你可以把 b 放进 a 中，如果你愿意的话。
Nice.
不错。
And now temp goes back into that one.
现在 temp 回到那个里面了。
All right.
好的。
That was very well done.
做得很好。
Maybe round of applause.
也许可以鼓掌。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So this was just a cookie based way of making clear
所以这只是一个基于饼干的方式来澄清
that the code on the screen seems to work.
屏幕上的代码似乎可以工作。
If I scroll back down to the swap function,
如果我向下滚动到交换函数，
it seems to do exactly what you just did there, whereby the temporary glass is
它似乎做了你刚才在那里做的事情，即临时玻璃是
where we put a, then we changed a to contain b,
我们把 a 放的地方，然后我们把 a 改成包含 b，
then we changed b to contain what was originally an a,
然后我们把 b 改成包含最初的 a，
but is now in the temporary glass.
但现在在临时玻璃里。
And now we're done.
现在我们完成了。
So it did achieve the stated goal, and yet when I ran this code a moment ago,
所以它确实实现了既定的目标，然而当我刚才运行这段代码时，
it was one, two, and then one, two again.
它是 1，2，然后又是 1，2。
So why might that actually be?
那么，为什么实际上会这样呢？
Well, here we can go back to some of today's fundamentals
好吧，我们可以回到今天的一些基本原理
to consider what it is that's going wrong.
来考虑一下哪里出了问题。
And in this case, it's actually related to a concept
在这种情况下，它实际上与一个概念有关
we introduced some time ago, whereby there seems to be an issue of scope,
我们之前介绍过，即似乎存在一个范围问题，
whereby sometimes when you're manipulating variables inside
即有时当你在花括号内操作变量时，
of curly braces, thus defining their scope, it has no effect on values
从而定义它们的范围，它对其他地方的值没有影响
elsewhere.
其他地方。
The variables might not even exist elsewhere, as we saw in the past.
正如我们过去所见，这些变量可能甚至不存在于其他地方。
So what do I mean by this?
那么，我这是什么意思呢？
Well, with matters of scope, it turns out that in this case, the way
好吧，就范围问题而言，事实证明，在这种情况下，我的做法
I've implemented the swap function, I'm doing something
实现交换函数的方式，我在做一些
a programmer would call passing by value.
程序员所说的按值传递。
I'm literally passing in x and y by their values, one and two.
我实际上是按值传递 x 和 y，分别是 1 和 2。
Another way of putting this is passing by copy.
另一种说法是按副本传递。
So when I pass x and y into the swap function,
所以当我把 x 和 y 传递给交换函数时，
it turns out swap is actually getting copies thereof.
事实证明，交换函数实际上得到了它们的副本。
Now, what do I mean by this?
现在，我这是什么意思呢？
Well, let's go back again to this picture
好吧，让我们再回到这张图片
of memory representative of what's in your Mac, your PC, or your phone.
内存代表你 Mac、PC 或手机中的东西。
And if we zoom in on this chip and we treat
如果我们放大这个芯片，并把它看作
it more abstractly as this canvas, get rid of the actual hardware,
更抽象地作为画布，去掉实际的硬件，
and consider what's going on inside of the computer,
并考虑计算机内部发生的事情，
it turns out that there are conventions of how computers use this memory.
事实证明，计算机使用内存的方式存在一些约定。
And it's worth having a general sense of what goes where.
了解一下哪些东西放在哪里是值得的。
So generally speaking, if this is a big rectangular region of memory,
一般来说，如果这是一个大的矩形内存区域，
even though this is just an artist's depiction thereof,
即使这只是一个艺术家的描述，
it turns out that the top of your memory, so to speak,
事实证明，你的内存顶部，可以这么说，
is where machine code goes.
是机器码所在的地方。
The zeros and ones that you compile get loaded into here.
你编译的 0 和 1 会被加载到这里。
So when you do dot slash something, or on a Mac or PC, when you double click,
当您执行点斜杠某个东西，或在 Mac 或 PC 上双击时，
or on a phone, when you single tap, that loads your program's machine code,
或者在手机上，当您单击时，会加载您的程序的机器码，
the app's machine code to the top of your computer's memory.
将应用程序的机器码加载到计算机内存的顶部。
Strictly speaking, it doesn't have to be the top.
严格地说，它不必位于顶部。
But for our sake, it's in this region here.
但为了我们的方便，它位于该区域。
That's how the computer can access all of those zeros and ones quickly.
这就是计算机可以快速访问所有这些零和一的方式。
Below that, so to speak, are where global variables go.
在它下面，可以这么说，是全局变量所在的地方。
We haven't had many occasions to use these.
我们还没有很多机会使用它们。
But if you define a variable outside of main,
但是，如果您在 main 函数之外定义一个变量，
and outside of every other function in C,
并且在 C 中的任何其他函数之外，
it's what's called a global variable.
它被称为全局变量。
So those get tucked especially up at the top
因此，它们被特别放置在顶部
so that they're accessible everywhere else in your program.
以便它们可以在您的程序中的任何其他地方被访问。
Then there's something called the heap.
然后是堆。
More on that in a moment.
稍后会详细讲解。
And it grows downward, so you have a lot of memory available to you
它向下增长，因此您拥有大量可用的内存
here in the heap, and you can keep getting more, and more,
在堆中，并且您可以继续获得更多，更多，
and more available to you.
更多可供您使用。
But at the bottom of this memory is what's called the stack.
但是，在这段内存的底部是堆栈。
And the stack actually grows, curiously, in the other direction, up, and up,
有趣的是，堆栈实际上在另一个方向上增长，向上，向上，
and up.
向上。
And it turns out, when you use malloc and ask the computer for memory,
事实证明，当您使用 malloc 并向计算机请求内存时，
it comes from this heap region, specifically.
它来自这个堆区域，具体来说。
When you use functions with variables and arguments,
当您使用带有变量和参数的函数时，
you're using stack memory.
您使用的是堆栈内存。
Now, the astute viewer will notice that this does not seem like a good thing
现在，敏锐的观众会注意到，这似乎不是一件好事
if they're about to collide eventually.
如果它们最终会发生冲突。
And bad things can and will happen when one overflows the other, but more
当一方溢出另一方时，会发生不好的事情，但更多
on that, too, in a moment.
稍后会详细讲解。
But let's focus for the moment on a stack
但让我们暂时关注堆栈
when we do something like this swap function.
当我们执行这样的交换函数时。
So for instance, when we had code like this, which was bad,
例如，当我们有这样的代码，它是错误的，
it did not allow us to permanently change the values of x and y.
它不允许我们永久改变 x 和 y 的值。
Why?
为什么？
No pun intended.
不是有意玩弄文字。
Here on the stack is where the very first function
这里，在堆栈上是第一个函数所在的地方
goes in your computer's memory.
进入计算机内存。
So main, if you have any variables, they go
因此，main，如果您有任何变量，它们会
at the bottom of the computer's memory once you've loaded that program.
在您加载该程序后，位于计算机内存的底部。
So what do I mean by that?
那么，我的意思是什么？
Well, if you think back to the code a moment ago, it was things like x and y,
好吧，如果您回忆起刚才的代码，它就像 x 和 y 这样的东西，
and so forth.
等等。
When main calls swap, swap goes above it on the stack, so to speak.
当 main 调用 swap 时，swap 可以说是位于堆栈之上。
And each of these rectangles, the technical term is frame.
每个矩形，其技术术语为帧。
So this is a stack frame.
所以，这是一个堆栈帧。
This is a stack frame.
这是一个堆栈帧。
And if swap called another function, another frame
如果 swap 调用另一个函数，另一个帧
would go on the stack this way.
将以这种方式进入堆栈。
And then as soon as swap returns, though,
然后，一旦swap返回，
that memory essentially goes away, or the computer
该内存实际上就消失了，或者说计算机
forgets about it, even though the bits are obviously still there.
忘记了它，即使位显然还在那里。
You still have the hardware, but it's forgotten.
你仍然拥有硬件，但它被忘记了。
And main remains until main finishes and exits your program.
而main则一直存在，直到main完成并退出你的程序。
But let's consider what's going inside of these stack frames.
但让我们考虑一下这些栈帧内部发生了什么。
So here's main at the bottom, and it had two variables, x and y.
所以这里是底部的main，它有两个变量，x和y。
Those variables were one and two, respectively.
这些变量分别是1和2。
Main called swap, which had two arguments, a and b,
main调用了swap，它有两个参数，a和b，
also integers, which are effectively local variables, also,
也是整数，实际上也是局部变量，
even though you're declaring them in the signature,
即使你在函数签名中声明它们，
the prototype of the function.
函数的原型。
So when swap is called, swap is using its frame of memory as follows.
所以当调用swap时，swap使用其内存帧如下。
Room for a, room for b, room for temp.
为a留出空间，为b留出空间，为temp留出空间。
Not necessarily to scale.
不一定按比例。
I just wanted everything to be a pretty rectangle.
我只是想让一切都成为一个漂亮的矩形。
What's going where?
什么在什么地方？
Well, because functions in C pass by value, that is, copy, a is a copy of x,
因为C语言中的函数按值传递，也就是复制，a是x的副本，
and b is a copy of y.
而b是y的副本。
But they're separate bytes.
但它们是独立的字节。
This is a different memory location than this.
这个内存位置与这个不同。
So we're just copying the patterns of bits from one to the other.
所以我们只是将位模式从一个复制到另一个。
This is passing by value, a.k.a.
这就是按值传递，也称为
Passing by copy.
按副本传递。
So what then happens?
那么接下来会发生什么？
Just like our demonstration, we used temp cleverly,
就像我们的演示一样，我们巧妙地使用了temp，
whereby with this code here, we copied the value of a into temp.
通过这里的代码，我们将a的值复制到temp中。
So that puts the number one here, too.
这样这里也有数字1了。
We then changed a to equal b.
然后我们将a的值改为b。
So that's what happened here.
这就是这里发生的事情。
We then changed b to equal temp, so that changed the value there.
然后我们将b的值改为temp，从而改变了那里的值。
But then swap returned.
但随后swap返回了。
You went back to your seat, leaving a and b swapped, yes.
你回到了你的座位，留下了a和b交换了，是的。
But what was not swapped was x and y.
但没有交换的是x和y。
You did all of this work correctly, but in the wrong scope.
你做的一切都正确，但在错误的范围内。
You operated on copies thereof.
你对它们的副本进行了操作。
So this swap function, while logically correct,
因此，这个swap函数，虽然逻辑上是正确的，
will never solve this problem correctly as written
但按照目前的写法，永远无法正确地解决这个问题
because we've been passing by value.
因为我们一直是按值传递的。
So today, we introduce a technique, whereby
所以今天，我们介绍一种技术，通过这种技术，
you can pass by reference instead, pass by pointer instead,
你可以按引用传递，而不是按指针传递，
because instead of just passing in copies,
因为不是简单地传递副本，
what if we actually tell swap where x is and where y is, not what it is
如果我们实际上告诉swap x在哪里，y在哪里，而不是它们是什么
and what it is, but where each is?
以及它是什么，而是它们分别在哪里？
Then swap can follow the proverbial treasure map, go to those locations,
那么swap就可以遵循谚语中的藏宝图，去到那些地方，
and change them permanently.
并永久地改变它们。
So this was the bad code in red, and this
所以这是用红色标出的错误代码，而这个
is going to escalate quickly visually.
将很快在视觉上升级。
But it's just an application of today's ideas.
但这仅仅是今天理念的应用。
This is the correct solution now.
现在，这是正确的解决方案。
So let me do before.
所以，让我先做一下。
In red is bad.
红色代表错误。
Green, after, is correct.
绿色，之后，是正确的。
Why?
为什么？
The way you specify pass by reference or pointer
指定传递引用或指针的方式
instead is you change swap to take, not two integers, per se,
而是将swap修改为接收两个整数的地址，而不是两个整数本身，
but two addresses of integers.
而是两个整数的地址。
And the syntax for that today is just to add the star.
而今天的语法只是添加星号。
So int star, and int star.
所以int星号，和int星号。
Meanwhile, the code down here has to change.
同时，下面的代码需要改变。
Temp does not have to change.
Temp不需要改变。
Temp is still just a variable that's ready for some value.
Temp仍然只是一个准备接受值的变量。
But the a and the b, and the b need to be rewritten as follows.
但a和b需要按照如下方式重写。
So star a means go to the address a, and get its value,
所以星号a表示，去到地址a，获取其值，
and put it in temp, just like you reached for one of the glasses
并将其放入temp，就像你伸手去拿其中一个杯子
and poured it in.
并将其倒入。
Star b means, go to the value in b and grab it.
星号b表示，去到b中的值，并获取它。
And then go to the value at a and change it to be that at b.
然后去到a中的值，并将其修改为b中的值。
And then lastly, this is not now sweat.
最后，这不再是汗水。
This is now colored liquid.
现在是彩色的液体。
This last line is go to the address b, and put temp there instead.
最后一行表示，去到地址b，并将temp放到那里。
So the picture now is fundamentally different.
所以，现在的画面从根本上不同了。
Main looks the same still.
Main看起来仍然相同。
But when swap is called, effectively, and we won't bother with OX123 or 456.
但当swap被调用时，实际上，我们不会理会OX123或456。
Let's just do it with arrows pointing at things.
让我们用指向事物的箭头来做。
a is a pointer to x, b is a pointer to y.
a是指向x的指针，b是指向y的指针。
So what do those lines of code tell us to do?
那么，这些代码行告诉我们做什么？
Go to a.
去到a。
So that means this, kind of like the old chutes and ladders game,
这意味着，就像老式的滑梯和梯子游戏一样，
if you ever played.
如果你玩过的话。
Follow the arrow, and that leads you to the number one, and store it in temp.
沿着箭头走，它会带你到数字1，并将它存储在temp中。
So that one was straightforward.
所以，那个很简单。
Go to the value in b.
去到b中的值。
So follow the arrow.
所以，沿着箭头走。
That gives us two, and put it at the location
这给了我们2，并将它放在位置
in a, which means put the two there.
在a中，这意味着将2放到那里。
The very last line of code now means get temp, which is obviously there,
最后一行代码现在表示，获取temp，它显然在那里，
and go to the address b, and change it to one.
并去到地址b，将其修改为1。
So now, even though we've not changed a and b at all, per se,
所以现在，尽管我们并没有改变a和b本身，
we've used them as little breadcrumbs to lead us
我们使用它们作为面包屑来引导我们
to the right location in the computer's memory.
到计算机内存中的正确位置。
So when swap returns this time, even though it's a void function,
所以，当swap这次返回时，即使它是一个void函数，
it has made a difference.
它已经产生了影响。
And it's had this effect of swapping the actual original values of x and y.
而且它已经产生了交换x和y的原始值的效果。
The code, admittedly, is cryptic looking.
诚然，代码看起来很神秘。
It's not the most user friendly syntax, but this ability
它不是最友好的语法，但这种能力
now to go to locations in memory and change
现在可以去到内存中的位置并改变
what is actually there is what we've been given today
实际存在的东西，是我们今天得到的。
with this new syntax of the star operator, and occasionally as needed,
使用星号运算符的新语法，以及在必要时偶尔使用
the ampersand one, as well.
符号运算符。
Questions on this technique, which is, admittedly, the most sophisticated
对这种技术有什么问题吗？它确实是最复杂的
of the examples thus far, and we'll probably take time to get used to.
示例，我们可能需要花点时间来适应。
Yeah.
是的。
Say that again.
再说一遍。
Will this work if--
如果这样做可以吗？
AUDIENCE: Will this work if you're swapping the value
观众：如果交换两个字符串的值
of two strings instead of ints?
而不是两个整数，这样做可以吗？
SPEAKER 1: Ah, good question.
演讲者 1：啊，问得好。
Will this work if you're swapping the values
如果交换两个字符串的值
of two strings instead of two ints?
而不是两个整数，这样做可以吗？
Yes, if you go to the address that the string represents and change maybe
可以，如果你去字符串代表的地址，并且可能使用
with a loop all of the characters one at a time.
循环一个一个地更改所有字符。
So it's going to be more complicated than this in green because you're
所以它会比绿色部分更复杂，因为你需要
going to have to change all of the individual characters,
更改所有单个字符，
probably reusing a temporary char, instead of a temporary integer.
可能需要重用一个临时字符，而不是一个临时整数。
But you could.
但是可以这样做。
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众： [听不清]
SPEAKER 1: Since integers have a fixed number of bits,
演讲者 1：由于整数具有固定数量的位，
can you ever run into a situation where you run out of memory?
你是否会遇到内存不足的情况？
Absolutely.
当然。
Your phone, your laptop, your desktop can only do so much,
你的手机、你的笔记本电脑、你的台式机只能做这么多，
can only count so high because of these physical limitations.
因为这些物理限制，只能计算到这么高的数字。
And hopefully, it's just never reach that limit.
希望它永远不会达到这个限制。
But we'll talk in a couple of weeks time when we transition to web programming
但我们将在几周后，当我们过渡到网页编程时
and databases, and the Metas, the Microsofts,
和数据库，以及 Meta、微软，
the Googles of the world that have crazy large amounts of data.
谷歌等拥有大量数据的公司。
The number of bits we use in those contexts
我们在这些情况下使用的位数
is actually going to matter for exactly that reason.
实际上会因为这个原因而变得重要。
If business is booming, and if you've got
如果生意兴隆，如果你有
lots and lots of data, lots and lots of users,
大量数据，大量用户，
you need to be able to count higher.
你需要能够计算更高的数字。
Just so that you've seen the code actually in operation,
为了让你看到代码的实际运行，
here is, of course, my swap function down below.
当然，我的交换函数就在下面。
And if I go ahead and change its prototype
如果我继续更改它的原型
to take in pointers to a and b, and similarly change the prototype up here.
使它接收指向 a 和 b 的指针，并且类似地更改上面的原型。
And if I go in and change a here to be star a to dereference it, star
如果我进入并更改这里的 a 使其成为星号 a 以取消引用它，星号
b to dereference it, star a to dereference it,
b 以取消引用它，星号 a 以取消引用它，
and star b to dereference it, I claim now that this version of the code
和星号 b 以取消引用它，我现在声称这个版本的代码
should now work.
现在应该可以工作了。
In fact, let me go ahead and do make swap.
实际上，让我继续做 make swap。
It didn't compile.
它没有编译。
So why might that be?
所以为什么会出现这种情况？
Well, let me scroll up to see what the message is.
好吧，让我向上滚动查看消息。
Incompatible integer to pointer conversion
整数到指针转换不兼容
passing in parameter of type int star.
传入类型为 int star 的参数。
That's a lot to absorb.
信息量很大。
But clearly, the issue is with how I'm calling swap.
但很明显，问题在于我调用 swap 的方式。
So why is this?
为什么呢？
Well, notice that now that my swap function expects as arguments pointers
好的，请注意，现在我的 swap 函数期望传入指针作为参数
to integers, I can't just blindly pass in x and y, which are integers.
给整数，我不能直接传入 x 和 y，它们都是整数。
Instead, I do need to use our friend, the new ampersand operator to pass
相反，我需要使用我们的老朋友取地址运算符来传入
in the address of x and the address of y.
x 和 y 的地址。
So now, if I reopen my terminal window, run make swap, and do dot slash swap,
所以现在，如果我重新打开我的终端窗口，运行 make swap，并执行点斜杠 swap，
now I see one, two, and then two, one.
现在我看到了 1，2，然后 2，1。
So the code changes in this way.
所以代码就这样改变了。
And maybe this example more so than others
也许这个例子比其他例子更能说明
makes clear why the star operator lets us go somewhere,
清楚地说明为什么星号运算符能让我们去某个地方，
but the ampersand effectively does the opposite and figures out
而取地址运算符实际上做了相反的事情，它计算出
what the address of something now is.
某个东西的地址是什么。
All right.
好的。
So what about these other locations in memory?
那么，内存中的其他位置呢？
Well, it turns out that, indeed, the stack, as we've described it,
事实证明，确实，正如我们所描述的那样，栈
grows up, and up, and up.
向上增长，向上增长，向上增长。
And recall that stack here in this sense is
回想一下，这里栈的概念
kind of like the stack of trays and the cafeteria or any of the dining halls.
就像自助餐厅或任何餐厅里的托盘堆一样。
There's one tray, another tray, another tray, another tray.
一个托盘，另一个托盘，另一个托盘，另一个托盘。
But then you start removing them from top down.
但随后，你开始从上往下移除它们。
So there's an ordering to them that we'll actually revisit next week.
因此它们是有序的，我们下周会重新讨论这一点。
But this is not a good design, in general.
但总的来说，这不是一个好的设计。
You shouldn't be doing things like two trains on the tracks barreling together
你不应该做像两列火车在轨道上迎面冲撞那样的事情
toward each other in this way.
相互迎面冲撞。
But honestly, it's kind of the only way, because if you've only
但说实话，这几乎是唯一的方法，因为如果你只有
got a finite amount of memory, OK, sure, you
有限的内存，好的，当然，你可以
can have them both grow in the same direction.
让它们都朝同一个方向增长。
But they're still going to hit some impasse eventually.
但最终它们仍然会遇到僵局。
You're still going to run out of space.
你仍然会耗尽空间。
So the way computers were designed years ago is they use memory in this way,
所以几年前计算机的设计方式就是用这种方式使用内存，
even though bad things can happen, if you use too much stack space,
即使会发生不好的事情，如果你使用了太多的栈空间，
or too much heap space.
或太多的堆空间。
So what do I mean by that?
那么我的意思是什么呢？
Our example a moment ago just had us call main and then swap
我们刚才的例子只是让我们调用 main 然后调用 swap
and that was it.
就这样。
So it's like two frames no big deal.
所以就像两帧，没什么大不了。
But if you call many functions again, and again,
但如果你一遍又一遍地调用很多函数，
and again, if you do something recursively, where you call yourself,
一遍又一遍地，如果你做了递归操作，你调用了自己，
you're going to pile, pile, pile stack frames potentially.
你可能会堆叠很多栈帧。
So you could start to hit the so-called heap area.
所以你可能开始触及所谓的堆区域。
Meanwhile, if you call malloc too many times,
与此同时，如果你多次调用 malloc，
you might be growing down, down, down, down, down,
你可能会向下增长，向下增长，向下增长，向下增长，向下增长，
and then overrun some of the stack memory, as well.
然后也可能会覆盖一些栈内存。
So bad things can happen when you overrun either of these.
所以当你覆盖其中任何一个的时候，都会发生不好的事情。
And those of you maybe with prior programming experience
也许你们中有一些人有之前的编程经验
might have heard at least one of these terms, heap overflow, or more
可能听说过至少一个术语，堆溢出，或者更多
popularly, stack overflow.
最受欢迎的是堆栈溢出。
Super popular website for questions and answers about programming.
一个超级受欢迎的网站，专门用来回答有关编程的问题。
The etymology thereof is exactly this idea of overflowing the stack
这个词的词源正是这个概念，即堆栈溢出
and touching memory that you should not, whether it's
并访问了你不应该访问的内存，无论是
memory down here, or even worse, memory over here,
下面的内存，或者更糟的是，这边的内存，
as by something called heap overflow.
就像由一种叫做堆溢出的东西所导致的。
And these are specific examples of what we'll start calling buffer overflows.
这些是我们将开始称为缓冲区溢出的特定例子。
Buffer is just a chunk of memory.
缓冲区只是一块内存。
And buffer overflows means overflowing, using too much of that memory.
缓冲区溢出意味着溢出，使用过多的内存。
And buffers are everywhere.
缓冲区无处不在。
In fact, if you've used YouTube recently,
事实上，如果你最近使用过 YouTube，
and maybe it's just kind of paused and spinning, and spinning, and spinning,
也许它只是暂停了，并且在旋转，旋转，旋转，
maybe you're on a really bad connection.
也许你的网络连接很糟糕。
There's no more bytes in your buffer.
你的缓冲区中没有更多字节了。
There's no more video footage in the buffer
缓冲区中没有更多视频片段了
because maybe you have such a bad connection.
因为也许你的网络连接很糟糕。
But if Google were to make mistakes and try
但如果谷歌犯了错误，并且试图
to download too many bytes at a time, they too could overflow a buffer.
一次下载太多字节，他们也会导致缓冲区溢出。
And if YouTube or similar apps have ever crashed,
如果 YouTube 或类似的应用程序曾经崩溃过，
it could be because they're trying to use more memory than they actually
这可能是因为它们试图使用比实际需要的更多的内存
should be.
应该使用的内存。
So these things are sort of everywhere.
所以这些事情无处不在。
Now, as for these training wheels, we sort of took away
现在，对于这些辅助轮，我们已经把
the mystery of what a string is.
字符串是什么的神秘面纱揭开了。
But what about all of these other functions we've been
但是，我们一直在使用的所有其他函数呢？
taking for granted now for a few weeks?
我们已经使用了几周了？
You can and should still use them to solve some problems because, frankly, C
你仍然可以并且应该使用它们来解决一些问题，因为坦白地说，C
does not make it easy to get user input safely, like, period, full stop.
并不容易安全地获取用户输入，就像，句号，句号。
It is very non-trivial to get user input without running
在不冒缓冲区溢出的风险的情况下获取用户输入非常不容易。
the risk of overflowing a buffer.
缓冲区溢出的风险。
Why?
为什么？
Well, you're the programmer.
嗯，你是程序员。
How do you possibly know in advance how big of a string
你怎么可能提前知道人类明天、下周或下天可能输入的字符串有多长？
a human might type in tomorrow, or the next week, or the next day?
有多长？
You could try to be safe and allocate a million bytes all at once.
你可以尝试安全地一次性分配一百万字节。
But what if they type in 1,000,001 characters,
但如果他们输入了 1,000,001 个字符，
or use copy paste so much that they similarly overflow?
或者使用复制粘贴太多以至于它们也溢出？
So getting user input is a hard problem.
所以获取用户输入是一个难题。
So let's introduce you to what the alternative would be
所以让我们来介绍一下替代方案是什么
and given an appreciation for what libraries like CS50's and others
并感谢像 CS50 这样的库和其他库
like it are actually doing for you.
像这样的库实际上为你做了什么。
Let me go ahead and create our own version of getint and getstring
让我继续创建我们自己的 getint 和 getstring 版本
without using the CS50 library, but using a standard C
不使用 CS50 库，而是使用标准的 C
function called scanf.
函数 scanf。
And to do that, let me go over to VS Code.
为了做到这一点，让我去 VS Code。
Let me create a new file called, for instance, get.c.
让我创建一个新的文件，比如 get.c。
And then in get.c, let's make a very simple program
然后在 get.c 中，让我们编写一个非常简单的程序。
first that just gets an integer, but again, without using the CS50 library.
首先，这将得到一个整数，但是再次说明，不使用CS50库。
So let me go ahead and include the standard io library.
所以让我继续包含标准io库。
Let me go ahead and declare main as int main void.
让我继续声明main为int main void。
And then inside of main, let me go ahead and declare an integer n
然后在main内部，让我继续声明一个整数n
so that we have some place to put the integer that we're
这样我们就可以把我们获取的整数放到某个地方。
getting from the user.
从用户那里获取。
Then let me go ahead and just prompt the user
然后让我继续提示用户
for a value for n, so n colon space, for instance.
输入n的值，例如，n冒号空格。
Because again, I'm not using getint, so I can't just
因为再次说明，我没有使用getint，所以我不能仅仅
call it to present the user with a prompt.
调用它来向用户展示一个提示。
So I'm going to use printf to create my own prompt.
所以我将使用printf来创建我自己的提示。
And now, let me use this function scanf as follows.
现在，让我使用这个函数scanf，如下所示。
I'm going to call scanf, and then I'm going to pass to scanf,
我将调用scanf，然后我将传递给scanf，
similar in spirit to printf, a format code, like %i,
类似于printf，一个格式代码，比如%i，
effectively telling scanf that what I want it to scan, so to speak,
实际上告诉scanf，我想要它扫描的东西，可以这么说，
from the user's keyboard is in fact a single integer.
来自用户的键盘实际上是一个单一的整数。
Now, I'm going to close quotes, and I don't need a new line because I'm not
现在，我将关闭引号，我不需要换行，因为我没有
trying to print anything.
试图打印任何东西。
I'm trying to get something from the user using scanf.
我试图使用scanf从用户那里获取一些东西。
But I do need to tell scanf where to put this integer.
但我确实需要告诉scanf把这个整数放在哪里。
Now, if I want to put this integer in the variable n,
现在，如果我想把这个整数放在变量n中，
it's not quite as simple as just passing n
它并不像直接传递n那样简单
in because recall how variables are passed.
因为回想一下变量是如何传递的。
This variable n is going to be passed by value.
这个变量n将通过值传递。
Effectively, a copy is going to go into scanf,
实际上，一个副本将进入scanf，
and so scanf is not going to have the ability to change that value.
因此，scanf将无法改变该值。
But if you think back to how we swapped two values
但是如果你回想一下我们是如何交换两个值的
and passed two values into that swap function in C,
并将两个值传递给C中的那个交换函数，
well, if we pass those two values in by their addresses,
那么，如果我们通过它们的地址传递这两个值，
so passing by reference, so to speak, then the function,
所以通过引用传递，可以这么说，然后这个函数，
swap in that case, scanf in this case, can actually go to that address
在本例中是交换，在本例中是scanf，实际上可以进入该地址
and change the value.
并改变值。
So to summarize, I'm going to pass the scanf one argument, which is a format
总之，我将传递给scanf一个参数，它是一个格式
code, and a second argument, which is the address of an integer into which
代码，第二个参数是整数的地址，我们将把
to put the user's value.
用户的值放入其中。
After that, I'm just going to go ahead and print out what's happened.
之后，我将继续打印出发生的事情。
So I'm going to go ahead and print out the value of n followed by a colon,
所以，我将继续打印出n的值，后面跟着一个冒号，
followed by an actual placeholder, %i backslash n.
后面跟着一个占位符，%i反斜杠n。
And I'm going to pass in now to printf the value n.
现在，我将传递给printf值n。
So to be clear, I'm still passing n into printf, just like we've
所以，明确地说，我仍然将n传递给printf，就像我们已经
been doing since week one, but I'm passing to scanf the address of n,
从第一周开始一直在做的那样，但我正在传递给scanf n的地址，
so that scanf can actually go to that address and change the value of n.
这样，scanf就可以实际进入该地址，并改变n的值。
So I think this is actually going to work,
所以，我认为这实际上会起作用，
even though I've not used getint or any of the CS50 library.
尽管我没有使用getint或任何CS50库。
Let me go into my terminal, run make get.
让我进入我的终端，运行 make get。
Seems to compile OK.
看起来编译正常。
Let me do dot shalsh get, and let me type in a value like 50 for n.
让我运行 dot shalsh get，并在其中输入一个像 50 这样的值给 n。
And indeed, I should see spit back at me that the value I got was 50.
实际上，我应该看到它反馈给我，我获得的值是 50。
So it turns out that getting an integer from users
因此，从用户那里获取一个整数
is relatively straightforward just using scanf.
使用 scanf 相对来说比较直接。
But of course, to use scanf, you need to know a little something about pointers
当然，要使用 scanf，你需要了解一点关于指针的知识
or addresses, more generally.
或者更一般地来说，地址。
That was not knowledge we had in week one.
这在第一周我们还没有学过。
And so we do, indeed, use those training wheels
所以我们确实使用了这些辅助工具
of the CS50 library for the past few weeks
在过去几周的 CS50 库中
so that we can get integers more easily.
这样我们就可以更容易地获取整数。
And it turns out, if the user types more than a simple integer,
事实证明，如果用户输入的不仅仅是一个简单的整数，
or doesn't even type in an integer, scanf isn't necessarily
或者甚至没有输入一个整数，scanf 不一定
going to behave as user friendly as getint might.
会像 getint 一样友好地工作。
So in the CS50 library, we do a bit more error handling for you, as well.
所以，在 CS50 库中，我们也会为你做更多的错误处理。
But let's consider now an implementation,
但现在让我们考虑一个实现，
not of getting an integer, but getting a string instead.
不是获取一个整数，而是获取一个字符串。
Let me clear my terminal window, and let me go ahead and erase all of this code,
让我清除我的终端窗口，然后让我继续删除所有这些代码，
and instead focus this time on getting a string.
这次改为关注获取一个字符串。
Well, we know we can't use string anymore, at least if we're not
好吧，我们知道我们不能再使用 string 了，至少如果我们没有
using the CS50 library.
使用 CS50 库。
But not a problem because we know that strings are now char stars.
但这不是问题，因为我们知道字符串现在是 char 星号。
So if I want to get a string from the user, that's like getting,
所以，如果我想从用户那里获取一个字符串，那就像获取，
I think, a char star.
我认为，一个 char 星号。
So let me just call this string s by default.
所以让我默认地称这个字符串为 s。
Let me go ahead therefore and declare a variable s that's
因此，让我继续声明一个变量 s，它
going to store my string.
将存储我的字符串。
Let me go ahead next, as before, and prompt the user
接下来，像之前一样，让我继续提示用户
for the value of that variable, just by prompting them with printf.
输入该变量的值，只需用 printf 提示他们即可。
So nothing fancy there.
所以这里没有什么花哨的东西。
And let me try again using scanf to scan this time
让我再试一次，这次使用 scanf 来扫描
a string from the user's keyboard.
用户键盘上的一个字符串。
I'm going to type scanf.
我要输入 scanf。
I'm going to do %s instead of %i because I, indeed,
我要使用 %s 而不是 %i，因为我实际上
want to scan a string in this case.
想要扫描一个字符串。
And then I'm going to go ahead and pass in just s.
然后我将继续传入 s。
And here, at first glance, seems to be an inconsistency because,
这里，乍一看，似乎存在一个不一致，因为
previously, I did ampersand n.
之前，我使用了取地址符 n。
But that's because n was an integer, not the address thereof.
但那是因为 n 是一个整数，而不是它的地址。
But in the world of strings as we now know,
但在我们现在了解的字符串世界中，
a string is just the address of its first byte.
字符串只是它第一个字节的地址。
And so if we declare s to be a char star, a.k.a.
所以，如果我们声明 s 为一个 char 星号，也就是
string, well, s is already in address.
字符串，那么 s 已经在地址中了。
So I can just pass in s in this case to scanf
所以，在这种情况下，我可以直接将 s 传递给 scanf
without actually using an ampersand.
而不需要使用取地址符。
After that, let's go ahead and print out the result. So let's just use printf.
之后，让我们继续打印结果。所以让我们直接使用 printf。
Let's print out a prefix, like s colon again, %s as my placeholder,
让我们打印一个前缀，比如再次使用 s 冒号，%s 作为我的占位符，
and now backslash n because I'm formatting it on the screen.
现在使用反斜杠 n，因为我在屏幕上进行格式化。
And then let's go ahead and pass in s as always to printf.
然后让我们继续像往常一样将 s 传递给 printf。
So s is just a string, so I just pass it into printf like that.
所以 s 只是一个字符串，所以我像这样直接将它传递给 printf。
Well, let me go ahead now, and I'm going to go ahead and compile
好了，我现在就来，我将继续编译
this an old fashioned way because we actually protect you
这种老式的方式，因为我们实际上保护你
from doing something like this.
免受此类操作的困扰。
But I'm going to go ahead and ignore the warnings you would otherwise
但我会忽略你本来会看到的警告
see us make.
我们所做的警告。
And I'm going to go ahead and compile this with clang directly.
我会直接使用 clang 编译它。
So clang-o get, because that's the name of the program I want to output.
所以 clang-o get，因为这是我想要输出的程序的名称。
But I'm also going to specify dash capital W, no, uninitialized, which
但是我也会指定一个大写 W 的破折号，不，未初始化，它
is simply another command line argument that's
只是一个命令行参数，
going to tell clang not to warn us about variables that are not initialized.
会告诉 clang 不要警告我们关于未初始化的变量。
Because case in point on line five, as some of you might have noticed,
因为第五行的例子，正如你们中的一些人可能已经注意到的，
I didn't actually initialize s to anything, even null.
我实际上没有将 s 初始化为任何东西，即使是空值。
But that's OK because I want to forge ahead blindly just to make a point as
但没关系，因为我想盲目地前进，只是为了说明这一点
to what's going on here.
这里发生了什么。
And in fact, let's go ahead and compile this code as follows.
事实上，让我们继续用以下方式编译这段代码。
It does seem to compile, even though make would
它确实似乎可以编译，即使 make 会
have warned us that something's awry.
警告我们有些不对劲。
Let me go ahead now and run dot slash get, and this time, not type in 50.
现在让我继续运行点斜杠 get，这次不要输入 50。
But let me type in something like our familiar "hi"
但我可以输入类似我们熟悉的“hi”
exclamation point, and hit enter.
感叹号，然后按回车键。
I immediately get a segmentation fault, which
我立即得到一个段错误，这
means something has gone wrong related to memory.
意味着内存出现了一些问题。
A segment of memory has been touched that I shouldn't have.
我碰到了不应该碰的内存段。
Well, why, in fact, is this?
好吧，这到底是怎么回事？
Well, let's consider what it is we've been doing.
好吧，让我们看看我们一直在做什么。
If this here is my computer's memory, and in the first case
如果这是我的电脑内存，在第一种情况下
I was just trying to get an integer, that
我只想得到一个整数，
was actually pretty straightforward, because even if this memory is filled
实际上非常简单，因为即使这段内存被填满了
with a whole bunch of garbage values, as personified here
充满了垃圾值，正如这里拟人化所表现的
by Oscar the Grouch, when I declared n to be an integer before,
由奥斯卡·葛鲁奇（垃圾桶怪），当我之前声明 n 为一个整数时，
I just needed, on this machine, four bytes, which
我只需要在这台机器上使用 4 个字节，这
is the typical size for an int.
是 int 的典型大小。
And I put the number 50 there.
然后我在那里放了数字 50。
So it doesn't matter that there were these garbage values.
所以，这些垃圾值并不重要。
I just went to those four bytes after declaring
在声明一个名为 n 的变量之后，我只访问了那 4 个字节
a variable called n and overwrote those bits,
并覆盖了那些位，
with some pattern of bits representing the number 50.
用一些代表数字 50 的位模式。
But strings we now know are sort of fundamentally different.
但我们现在知道字符串在本质上是不同的。
If I go back to that same memory space, and I declare s to be a pointer,
如果我回到相同的内存空间，并且我声明 s 为一个指针，
that is, a char star, well, recall that pointers are generally
也就是说，一个 char 星号，好吧，回忆一下，指针通常
eight bytes on modern systems.
在现代系统上是 8 个字节。
And so that's like taking eight of these bytes from memory and calling it s.
所以这就像从内存中取出这八个字节，并将其称为 s。
But the catch is, if I haven't initialized s to actually
但问题是，如果我没有初始化 s 使其成为一个有效的地址，
be a valid location, as via calling malloc,
比如通过调用 malloc，
there are still garbage values there.
那里仍然存在垃圾值。
That is to say, patterns of bits that maybe
也就是说，可能是之前
have been there always, but from some previous function that got
一直存在的位模式，但它们来自于某个之前被调用的函数，
called, or some other lines of code if this program were actually bigger.
或者如果该程序实际上更大，则来自其他代码行。
So it's just some garbage value is filling that variable s.
所以只是某些垃圾值填充了变量 s。
The problem, though, is that in my code now, when I call scanf
然而，问题在于，在我的代码中，现在当我调用 scanf 时，
and I tell scanf to scan a string from the user and to put it at that location
并告诉 scanf 从用户那里扫描一个字符串并将其放在该位置，
s, well, what is that location s?
s，那么，s 的位置是什么？
It's literally a garbage value.
它就是一个垃圾值。
It's the equivalent of a foam finger pointing there, there, there.
这相当于一个泡沫手指指向那里，那里，那里。
We just don't know because it's not a valid address.
我们只是不知道，因为它不是一个有效的地址。
And so I get that segmentation fault here in my terminal window
因此，我在终端窗口中得到了这个段错误，
because I've not initialized s to be some known value.
因为我没有将 s 初始化为某个已知值。
I get a segmentation fault because, effectively, I've
我得到了一个段错误，因为实际上我
accidentally touched memory that I should not, in fact, have done so.
意外地触碰了我不应该触碰的内存。
So how do we fix this?
那么我们如何解决这个问题呢？
Well clearly, I need s to point at some valid chunk of memory,
很明显，我需要让 s 指向某个有效的内存块，
and I could do that using malloc.
我可以使用 malloc 来实现。
But frankly, in this case, I could do it even more simply
但坦白地说，在这种情况下，我可以用更简单的方法来实现，
by just declaring s to be an array of characters,
只需将 s 声明为一个字符数组，
as we might have in week two.
就像我们在第二周做的那样。
So let me go ahead and clear my terminal window here.
所以，让我来清除一下这里的终端窗口。
Let me go into get.c, and let's simply change what's s is.
让我进入 get.c，让我们简单地更改 s 的内容。
Instead of a char star, which we know is what a string technically is,
而不是一个 char star，我们知道从技术上讲，字符串就是这个，
we can still implement strings as arrays of characters.
我们仍然可以将字符串实现为字符数组。
That's certainly still true.
这当然仍然是正确的。
So let me go ahead and do that, declare s to be
所以，让我来做这件事，将 s 声明为
an array of, say, four characters.
一个包含四个字符的数组。
And in this case, I should have enough room for the H, the I, the exclamation
在这种情况下，我应该有足够的空间容纳 H、I、感叹号
point, and even that null character, the trailing backslash zero.
和那个空字符，结尾的反斜杠零。
So now, let me go ahead and build this.
所以现在，让我来构建它。
Make get.
make get。
And because I'm not, not initializing something this time,
而且这次我没有初始化任何东西，
I can use make as usual without getting yelled at because I'm not yet
我可以像往常一样使用 make，而不会被骂，因为我还没有
doing anything wrong.
做错任何事。
Now let me go ahead and do dot slash get enter.
现在，让我来执行点斜杠 get 回车。
And in this case, it's ready to receive my H-I exclamation point enter,
在这种情况下，它准备接收我的 H-I 感叹号回车，
and all actually seems well.
一切都看起来很正常。
Why?
为什么？
Because in this case, I actually had enough space for s,
因为在这种情况下，我实际上有足够的空间容纳 s，
because if I go back to my memory here, because I've now redeclared s
因为如果我回到我的内存，因为我现在重新声明了 s，
as an actual array of four characters, that's
作为一个包含四个字符的实际数组，这就像
like asking the operating system, for instance, for these four chars here.
比如向操作系统请求这四个字符。
And certainly, I can fit H-I exclamation point and the null character
当然，我可以把 H-I 感叹号和空字符放进去
into those four bytes.
在这四个字节里。
So there's not a problem.
所以没有问题。
But there might be a problem if the I, or the user, more generally,
但是如果 I，或者更一般地说，用户，
types in too many characters.
输入了太多字符。
So let me go ahead and run dot slash get again.
所以让我继续运行点斜杠 get 再次。
Let me type H-I exclamation point.
让我输入 H-I 感叹号。
But just to get a little aggressive, let me highlight that and paste it again,
但为了变得更具侵略性，让我突出显示它并再次粘贴，
again, again, and again, and really type, very excitedly,
一遍又一遍，一遍又一遍，非常兴奋地输入，
a pretty long string that is surely longer than four bytes.
一个相当长的字符串，它肯定比四个字节长。
Well unfortunately, I've only asked the operating system
不幸的是，我只要求操作系统
for an array of four bytes.
一个四个字节的数组。
So what's going to happen with all of those extra hi's, hi's, hi's?
那么，所有这些额外的 hi，hi，hi 会怎样？
They're just going to, by default, remain contiguous from left to right,
它们默认情况下将从左到右保持连续，
top to bottom in the computer's memory.
从上到下在计算机的内存中。
But they're going to end up, some of those characters,
但是它们最终会，其中一些字符，
at locations I didn't ask the operating system for in this array.
在我的这个数组中，我没有向操作系统请求的位置。
So if I go back to VS Code here, I've typed in a very long string, certainly
所以如果我回到这里的 VS Code，我已经输入了一个非常长的字符串，当然
longer than four bytes in total.
总长度超过了四个字节。
Let me hit enter.
让我按回车键。
And darn it.
该死。
There is another segmentation fault. So in short, we,
又出现了段错误。简而言之，我们，
you are going to see these segmentation faults any time
你会在任何时候看到这些段错误
you touch segments of memory, so to speak,
你触摸到内存的片段，可以这么说，
that do not belong to you, that you didn't allocate space for, as
它们不属于你，你没有为它们分配空间，就像
via an array, or even via malloc.
通过数组，甚至通过 malloc。
And this is going to be a fundamental problem with getting strings
这将成为获取字符串的一个基本问题
because I don't in advance how long the string is going to be
因为我事先不知道字符串有多长
that the human's going to type in.
人类要输入。
Maybe it's four.
也许是四个。
Maybe it's fewer characters.
也许是更少的字符。
Maybe it's even more.
也许更多。
So what's the alternative?
那么，还有什么选择呢？
Well, I could go in here maybe and allocate, I don't know,
好吧，我可以在里面分配，我不知道，
4,000 characters for s.
为 s 分配 4,000 个字符。
But what if you type in an even longer string that's 4,001 characters or more?
但如果你输入一个更长的字符串，长度为 4,001 个字符或更多，会怎么样？
I might still have these memory related errors, these segmentation faults.
我可能仍然会遇到这些与内存相关的错误，这些段错误。
So one of the reasons then, too, that we provide you with the CS50 library,
因此，我们向你提供 CS50 库的一个原因是，
and in turn, functions like getstring, is
反过来，像 getstring 这样的函数，就是
that getstring very, very conservatively walks through these user's input
getstring 非常、非常保守地遍历这些用户的输入
byte, by byte, by byte, one character at a time.
一个字节一个字节一个字节，一次一个字符。
And what the CS50 library is doing underneath the hood
CS50 库在幕后所做的是
is, as soon as it realizes, oh, the user gave us another byte, another byte,
就是，一旦它意识到，哦，用户给了我们另一个字节，另一个字节，
we in the CS50 library are constantly allocating and re
我们在 CS50 库中不断地分配和重新分配
allocating more and more memory using malloc for you,
使用 malloc 为你分配越来越多的内存，
and effectively managing the memory required for that string.
并有效地管理该字符串所需的内存。
So even though scanf exists, it's dangerous to use with strings.
所以，即使 scanf 存在，用它处理字符串也很危险。
And even with integers, it turns out it lacks
即使使用整数，事实证明它也缺乏
some of the error handling that the CS50 library has thus far provided.
CS50 库迄今为止提供的一些错误处理功能。
How do we actually go about solving this?
我们实际上如何解决这个问题呢？
The way getstring actually works in the CS50 library is it kind of tiptoes.
getstring 在 CS50 库中的实际工作方式是它有点像踮着脚尖。
It waits.
它等待。
It gets one character from you and then checks if there's another one coming.
它从你那里获取一个字符，然后检查是否还有另一个字符要来。
Then it allocates more space for a second.
然后它为第二个字符分配更多空间。
If there's still a third, it allocates more space, more space, more space.
如果还有第三个字符，它会分配更多空间，更多空间，更多空间。
So essentially, what getstring does is it uses malloc again,
所以本质上，getstring 所做的是它再次使用 malloc，
and again, and again, and it kind of lays the tracks down
一次又一次，它像铺设轨道一样
as you're typing in the keystrokes and hitting enter,
当你输入键击并按下回车键时，
so that we never assume how many characters you're going to type in.
这样我们就永远不会假设你将输入多少个字符。
We dynamically allocate just enough bytes for you, plus one extra,
我们动态地为你分配刚好足够的字节，再加上一个额外的字节，
for the null character.
用于空字符。
And this is sort of a hoop that's just not
而这就像是一个圈，它只是不
fun to jump through when, at the end of the day, all you want to do
有趣，当最终你想要做的
is get input from the user.
是从用户那里获取输入。
So even with the training wheels officially off,
所以即使辅助轮正式卸下，
it's going to be annoying to get strings from users in C.
在 C 语言中从用户获取字符串将是一件很烦人的事。
But it is easy with ints, with floats, with other data types.
但是使用整数、浮点数和其他数据类型就很简单。
And frankly, we'll soon, in two weeks, pivot
坦率地说，我们很快，在两周内，将转向
to Python, which takes care of all of these problems for us
Python，它会为我们解决所有这些问题
and manages our memory.
并管理我们的内存。
But for now, we have one final to do beyond scanf,
但现在，除了 scanf 之外，我们还有最后一个要做的，
which is file IO, which is a fancy way of saying input and output.
那就是文件 I/O，它是一种更花哨的说法，指的是输入和输出。
Because now that we a little bit of hexadecimal,
因为现在我们了解了一些十六进制知识，
now that we know a little bit about pointers,
现在我们了解了一些关于指针的知识，
we actually have some more functions available to us
我们实际上可以使用更多函数
that will let us actually manipulate files on a computer's hard drive,
让我们实际上能够操作计算机硬盘上的文件，
like image files, or text files, or anything else we might want.
例如图像文件、文本文件或我们可能需要的任何其他文件。
Among the most common functions that are related to files are these here.
与文件相关的最常见函数包括这些。
fopen is going to be a function that lets you open a file, doing in code
fopen 将是一个让你打开文件的函数，在代码中执行
what you might otherwise do by going to File, Open in a graphical program.
你可能在图形程序中通过点击文件、打开来执行的操作。
Fclose does the opposite.
Fclose 做相反的操作。
It's the way you, in code, click on an X and close a file.
它是在代码中，点击 X 并关闭文件的方式。
Nothing's going to happen visually, but it's
视觉上不会发生任何变化，但它
how you give access to a program to the contents of a file.
是你让程序访问文件内容的方式。
fprintf, it allows you to print, not to the screen, but to a file.
fprintf 允许你打印，不是到屏幕上，而是到文件中。
fscanf lets you read data, not from the keyboard, but from a file. fread
fscanf 允许你读取数据，不是从键盘上读取，而是从文件中读取。 fread
and fwrite write are similarly used to read and write data from a file,
和 fwrite write 类似地用于从文件中读取和写入数据，
but generally binary data, like images, or something
但通常是二进制数据，比如图像，或者其他
that's not Ascii or Unicode text.
不是 ASCII 或 Unicode 文本的东西。
fseek is a function that lets you move around
fseek 是一个允许你在文件中左右移动的函数，有点像快进
in a file left to right, kind of like fast forwarding
在文件中从左到右移动，有点像快进
or rewinding through Netflix, or similar when
或者在 Netflix 上回放，或者在类似情况下
you want to jump to a different location in a video, or in this case, a file.
你想跳转到视频中的不同位置，或者在本例中，是文件中的不同位置。
And there's bunches of others, as well.
还有很多其他的。
So to give you a sense of what you can do with it when
所以，为了让你了解在
it comes to manipulating files, let's write just a couple of final programs,
谈到操作文件时，我们来编写几个最后的程序，
for instance, that let us manipulate some of this code for us.
例如，让我们可以为我们操作一些代码。
In fact, let me go ahead and open up here in VS Code a new file called,
事实上，让我在 VS Code 中打开一个名为
say, phonebook.c.
比如，phonebook.c 的新文件。
And in phonebook.c, we're going to implement now
在 phonebook.c 中，我们现在将实现
a version of the phonebook like we did in the past.
一个过去我们已经实现过的电话簿版本。
But in this case, we don't actually have a forgetful program that
但在这种情况下，我们实际上没有一个健忘的程序，该程序
prompts the user with getstring for a couple of names and numbers,
使用 getstring 提示用户输入几个姓名和电话号码，
and then just forgets about them altogether.
然后完全忘记它们。
This version of the phonebook is actually
这个版本的电话簿实际上
going to go ahead and save them persistently to a file for us.
将把它们持久地保存到一个文件中。
And for this, let me go ahead and open up just on my other screen here,
为此，让我在我的另一块屏幕上打开它，
without flipping over just yet, let me go ahead and open up--
暂时还没有翻页，让我打开一下——
give me just one moment.
请稍等一下。
So we have this ready to go.
所以我们已经准备好了。
Let me go ahead and create the file, this program as follows.
让我创建这个文件，程序如下。
I'm going to cheat and save time by using the CS50 library because I do not
我将使用 CS50 库来作弊并节省时间，因为我不
want to get into the nuances of getting strings character by character,
想深入探讨逐个字符获取字符串的细微差别，
which itself will escalate too quickly.
这本身会很快升级。
But let me go ahead and include the CS50 library, the standard IO library,
但让我先包含 CS50 库、标准 IO 库，
and lastly, the string library for this particular case.
最后，在本例中包含字符串库。
In my main function now, I'm going to go ahead and open up
在我的主函数中，我将打开
a file called maybe phonebook.csv.
一个名为 phonebook.csv 的文件。
If you've ever used a CSV file, it's like a lightweight spreadsheet
如果你曾经使用过 CSV 文件，它就像一个轻量级的电子表格
that you can open in Apple Numbers, Google Spreadsheets, Microsoft Excel.
它可以在 Apple Numbers、Google Spreadsheets、Microsoft Excel 中打开。
But CSV means that we're going to separate all of the values by commas.
但 CSV 意味着我们将用逗号分隔所有值。
So anywhere we want a new column, we actually use a comma,
所以，只要我们想要一个新列，我们实际上就使用逗号，
as we'll soon see.
我们很快就会看到。
So how do I actually do this?
那么我究竟该如何做呢？
I can open a file called phonebook.csv by literally using fopen phonebook.csv.
我可以通过使用 fopen phonebook.csv 来打开一个名为 phonebook.csv 的文件。
And I have to tell fopen how I want to open it.
而且我必须告诉 fopen 我想要如何打开它。
Do I want to open it for reading with R?
我想要使用 R 以只读方式打开它吗？
Do I want to open it for writing with W?
我想要使用 W 以只写方式打开它吗？
Or do I want to open it with appending, A?
或者我想要使用 A 以追加方式打开它吗？
And for something like a phone book, if I run this program again and again,
对于像电话簿这样的东西，如果我一遍又一遍地运行这个程序，
I'm going to actually do append so that new contacts get added to the file,
我实际上会使用追加方式，这样新的联系人就会被添加到文件中，
and we don't overwrite it with W.
而且我们不会使用 W 来覆盖它。
Now, what is fopen return?
现在，fopen 返回什么？
It technically returns a pointer to a file.
从技术上讲，它返回一个指向文件的指针。
But this one's a little weird.
但这个有点奇怪。
It's all capitalized, but it is a thing in C. File in all caps star file
它全部大写，但它是 C 中的一个东西。全部大写的 FILE 星号 file
is going to be a pointer to that file in memory.
将指向内存中该文件的指针。
So think of fopen as opening the file and returning the address thereof
因此，将 fopen 视为打开文件并返回其地址
in the computer's memory.
在计算机的内存中。
All right.
好的。
What do I want to next do?
接下来我想要做什么？
I want to go ahead and get two strings from the user, like maybe someone's
我想从用户那里获取两个字符串，例如可能是某人的
name, using getstring, again, to keep things simple for now.
姓名，再次使用 getstring，为了现在保持简单。
Let me then go ahead and get another one.
然后我再获取另一个。
How about their number?
他们的号码怎么样？
Using getstring, again, prompting for a number.
再次使用 getstring，提示输入一个数字。
And I don't strictly need these training wheels.
而且我并不严格需要这些辅助工具。
So even though it doesn't really make a difference,
所以尽管它并没有真正改变什么，
I'm going to at least change that to char star, even though I do
我至少要将它改为 char star，尽管我确实
want to keep using getstring conveniently.
想继续方便地使用 getstring。
And now I want to save this person's name and number to that CSV file.
现在我想将这个人的姓名和号码保存到该 CSV 文件中。
So I'm going to use, not printf, but fprintf,
所以我将使用，不是 printf，而是 fprintf，
printing to that file, variable, which is open in the computer's memory.
打印到该文件，变量，该变量在计算机的内存中打开。
Now I'm going to go ahead and print out two strings, %s comma, %s.
现在我要打印两个字符串，%s 逗号，%s。
Then I want to go ahead and print out the name for the first placeholder,
然后我想继续打印出第一个占位符的姓名，
and the number for the second placeholder.
第二个占位符的号码。
And for good measure, I want to move the cursor to the next line in the file,
为了保险起见，我想将光标移动到文件中的下一行，
so I am going to include a backslash n.
因此我将包含一个反斜杠 n。
Then I'm going to go ahead and fclose that same file with fclose.
然后我将继续使用 fclose 关闭同一个文件。
And that's it.
就是这样。
No more printing to the user.
不再向用户打印。
But I claim that I'm going to be changing the file again,
但我声称我将再次更改该文件，
and again, and again.
再次，再次。
So let me try this.
所以让我试试这个。
Make phone book, OK, dot slash phonebook, enter.
创建电话簿，好的，点斜杠 phonebook，回车。
And let's type in David.
让我们输入 David。
And how about +1 617-495-1000?
+1 617-495-1000 怎么样？
Enter.
回车。
OK, hopefully, it worked.
好的，希望它能用。
Let's do it again.
让我们再来一次。
Dot slash phonebook.
点斜杠 phonebook。
Carter, we'll give him the same number as last time.
Carter，我们给他上次的号码。
495-1000.
495-1000。
And let's do, how about just those two?
我们就这样做吧，就这两个怎么样？
So let me go ahead now and reveal that we do have
所以我现在就告诉你，我们确实有
a file in here called phonebook.csv.
一个名为 phonebook.csv 的文件。
So that does exist.
所以确实存在。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续这样做。
Let me open up my file browser over here.
让我打开我这边文件浏览器。
I've got a lot of files I've created.
我已经创建了很多文件。
Here's phonebook.csv.
这是 phonebook.csv。
And if I click on it, there is the file that I just
如果我点击它，就会出现我刚刚创建的文件
created, separated by commas.
创建的，用逗号隔开。
But even more interestingly, let me actually right click or control click
但更有趣的是，让我实际右键单击或控制单击
on this, download it to my Mac's downloads folder.
它，将其下载到我的 Mac 的下载文件夹。
Let me go into my downloads folder just for fun,
为了好玩，让我进入我的下载文件夹，
and I've installed in advance Microsoft Excel.
我已经提前安装了 Microsoft Excel。
If I go into my downloads folder and open up phonebook.csv,
如果我进入我的下载文件夹并打开 phonebook.csv，
we're going to see, oh, Apple Numbers, not Excel, opening up.
我们会看到，哦，是 Apple Numbers 而不是 Excel 打开了。
View my spreadsheets.
查看我的电子表格。
All right, numbers is kind of stupid.
好吧，Numbers 有点蠢。
So there we go.
就是这样。
No, this isn't a Mac versus PC thing.
不，这不是 Mac 对 PC 的问题。
So now we have phonebook.csv rendered in this format here.
所以现在我们以这种格式呈现了 phonebook.csv。
Numbers presumes that the top row should be gray and not white, as well.
Numbers 还假设顶行应该是灰色的而不是白色的。
So the formatting looks a bit off.
所以格式看起来有点不对。
Anyhow, clearly, you could open this same file
无论如何，显然，你可以打开同一个文件
in a spreadsheet program like Microsoft Office, or Apple Numbers,
在像 Microsoft Office 或 Apple Numbers 这样的电子表格程序中，
or of course, something like Google Spreadsheets.
当然，也可以用像 Google Spreadsheets 这样的程序。
But let me do one other thing when it comes to copying files now,
但是，在复制文件方面，我想再做一件事，
whereby besides making a phone book, whereby I clearly have the ability now
除了创建电话簿，现在我显然有能力
to save strings in files.
将字符串保存在文件中。
And actually, just for good measure, let me hammer home the point
实际上，为了保险起见，让我强调一点
that anytime we're dealing with pointers now, something could go wrong.
现在，无论何时我们处理指针，都可能出现问题。
And if you read the documentation for fopen,
如果你阅读 fopen 的文档，
we should also check that file could be null.
我们还应该检查该文件是否为空。
Maybe the file is not found, or something's not working on the server.
也许文件未找到，或者服务器上某些东西无法正常工作。
And so just to be safe, we should return one there.
所以为了安全起见，我们应该在那里返回 1。
So even not just malloc, not just getstring.
所以，不仅仅是 malloc，不仅仅是 getstring。
Any time a function returns a pointer, you
任何时候函数返回一个指针，你
should check if it's null, because if it is, per the documentation,
应该检查它是否为空，因为根据文档，
almost always means something has gone wrong.
几乎总是意味着某些东西出错了。
So you should get out, lest you trust the return value therein.
所以你应该退出，以免你信任其中的返回值。
So let me go ahead and do one other program here.
所以，让我在这里再做另一个程序。
Let me create my own copy program.
让我创建我自己的复制程序。
So up until now, we've used commands like RM, and LS, and CP for copy.
到目前为止，我们一直使用 RM、LS 和 CP 等命令来复制。
I can actually create my own version of Linux's copy program,
我实际上可以创建我自己的 Linux 复制程序版本，
perhaps as follows.
也许如下所示。
Let me actually go into cp.c, in this case.
让我进入 cp.c，在这种情况下。
Let me include some familiar file.
让我包含一些熟悉的文件。
Standard io.h.
标准 io.h。
Let me include, how about one other?
让我再包含一个，怎么样？
Standard int.h for reasons we'll see now,
标准 int.h，原因我们现在就会看到，
because in standard int.h is that uint8_type that I mentioned
因为在标准 int.h 中是那个我提到的 uint8_type
earlier, which just means, give me an eight bit value that's unsigned,
之前，它只是意味着，给我一个无符号的 8 位值，
which means no negative numbers.
这意味着没有负数。
It's just raw data.
它只是原始数据。
It's not an integer in the positive or negative sense.
它不是正数或负数意义上的整数。
And let me just nickname that to byte, just
让我把它简称为 byte，只是
to make clear that I want to manipulate files byte at a time.
为了明确表示我想一次操纵一个字节的文件。
Let me now declare, for the first time today,
现在让我声明，今天第一次，
a version of main that takes in an ergc command, takes in argc,
一个 main 版本，它接受一个 ergc 命令，接受 argc，
and takes in argv, which is for command line arguments.
并接受 argv，它用于命令行参数。
Technically though, I'm not using the CS50 library in this version,
从技术上讲，在这个版本中，我没有使用CS50库，
so even that can now be changed.
因此，即使是这一点现在也可以改变。
And this is the canonical way in C to declare
在C语言中，这是一种标准的声明方式
main when you want to get command line arguments using
main函数，当您想要使用命令行参数时
char star instead of string.
使用字符指针而不是字符串。
So now, I'm going to do two things.
所以现在，我要做两件事。
Remember how copy works.
记住复制是如何工作的。
You specify two files, the file you want to copy,
您指定两个文件：要复制的文件，
and the new name that you want to give to the copy.
以及要给复制文件起的新的名字。
So it would be like CP, space, old name, space, new name at the command line.
所以它就像在命令行中输入：CP、空格、旧文件名、空格、新文件名。
So accordingly, I'm going to do this.
因此，相应地，我要这样做。
I'm going to create one file in memory called source, or SRC for short.
我将在内存中创建一个名为source的文件，简称SRC。
And I'm going to set that equal to whatever is in argv one in read mode.
我将把该文件设置为argv中的第一个参数，并以读模式打开它。
But just to be super specific, I'm going to use read binary mode.
为了更加精确，我将使用二进制读模式。
I don't want to be copying text files.
我不想复制文本文件。
I want binary data, zeros and ones, like images.
我想要二进制数据，零和一，比如图像。
So I'm going to tell fopen to expect binary data.
所以我要告诉fopen函数预期二进制数据。
I'm then going to go ahead and create a second variable
然后我将创建一个第二个变量
called destination, DST for short.
名为destination，简称DST。
And I'm going to open up whatever is in argv two,
我将打开argv中的第二个参数，
the second file name at the command line.
即命令行中的第二个文件名。
But I don't want to read this file.
但我不想读取该文件。
I want to write to it in binary using zeros and ones.
我想使用零和一以二进制形式写入它。
Now, let me do the copying one bite at a time.
现在，让我一次复制一个字节。
It's a little inefficient.
这有点低效。
I should really do bunches of bytes at a time for speed.
为了速度，我应该一次性复制多个字节。
But let me just give myself one byte in a variable called b.
但让我在一个名为b的变量中存储一个字节。
So byte is not a thing in C. It's literally
所以字节在C语言中并不存在，它实际上
a synonym I created just for the sake of discussion
是我为了讨论而创建的同义词
because we'll do this in the future, as well.
因为我们将来也会这样做。
Now, let me go ahead and do this.
现在，让我继续做这件事。
How do you copy a file from old to new?
如何将文件从旧文件复制到新文件？
Well, I think it would suffice to use a loop
我认为使用循环就足够了
and just start at the beginning of the file,
从文件的开头开始，
loop all the way to the end of the file, and within the loop,
循环到文件的末尾，在循环中，
copy one byte from old to new.
将一个字节从旧文件复制到新文件。
So how do I do that?
那么，我该怎么做呢？
I used fprintf last time to write text.
上次我用fprintf函数来写入文本。
This time, I'm going to use a different function as follows.
这次，我将使用以下不同的函数。
While there are bytes to read from the file,
当文件中还有字节可以读取时，
and this one's going to be a mouthful, so let me just type it out
而这行代码很长，所以让我直接打出来
and then I'll explain it.
然后我会解释它。
While that line is true, go ahead and write
当那行代码为真时，继续写入
this line, which is similarly a mouthful, so I'll type it first
这行代码，同样也很长，所以我会先打出来
and then explain what it does.
然后解释它做什么。
Then I'm going to close destination.
然后我将关闭destination。
Whoops.
哎呀。
Then I'm going to close source, and I claim, if I haven't messed anything up,
然后我将关闭source，我声称，如果我没搞错的话，
this will now copy files for me.
这将为我复制文件。
How?
怎么？
So this is indeed a mouthful, but there's a function called fread,
这确实很拗口，但有一个叫做 fread 的函数，
whose purpose in life is to read one or more bytes for you.
它的作用就是为你读取一个或多个字节。
How does it work?
它是怎么工作的？
Well, just like swap, just like scanf, you
嗯，就像 swap，就像 scanf 一样，你需要
have to tell it where to load those bytes in memory.
告诉它在内存中将这些字节加载到哪里。
So if I want to put them in the byte called b,
所以如果我想将它们放到名为 b 的字节中，
I can't just say b because that's passed by value.
我不能只说 b，因为它传递的是值。
I need to pass by reference.
我需要传递引用。
So I say the address of b is where I want you to put
所以我说 b 的地址是我想要你放置的地方
one byte from the file at a time.
每次从文件中读取一个字节。
How big is a byte?
一个字节有多大？
Technically, I could just say one because we all know how big a byte is.
技术上讲，我可以直接说 1，因为我们都知道一个字节有多大。
But I'm just going to be super proper and generalize this as size of b
但我还是想做得严谨一些，并将其概括为 size of b
so it just figures it out for me, just in case we ever
这样它会自动帮我计算，以防我们以后
do more than one bite at a time.
一次读取多个字节。
How many bytes do I want to copy at a time?
我一次想复制多少个字节？
One, just to keep it simple.
一个，为了简单起见。
And where do I want to read those bytes from?
我想从哪里读取这些字节？
The source file.
源文件。
fread, if you read the documentation, just tells you
fread，如果你读过它的文档，就会知道它会告诉你
how many bytes were successfully read.
成功读取了多少个字节。
Logically, it should either be one was read,
逻辑上讲，它应该要么读取了一个字节，
or zero were read, based on what I'm asking it to do.
要么读取了零个字节，这取决于我让它做什么。
I'm asking it to read one at a time, so it's either going to succeed or fail.
我让它一次读取一个字节，所以它要么成功，要么失败。
So I want to do this for as long as it succeeds
所以我想只要它成功，就一直执行
because it's going to succeed until it gets to the end of the file,
因为它会一直成功，直到它到达文件末尾，
and then there's no more bytes to read, at which point it will return zero.
那时就没有更多字节可以读取了，它会返回 0。
So now, I do the opposite with fwrite, and it's almost the same line.
现在，我对 fwrite 做相反的操作，这行代码几乎相同。
Where do I want to write that byte?
我想把那个字节写入哪里？
Well, first, I tell fwrite where to find the byte,
嗯，首先，我告诉 fwrite 到哪里找到那个字节，
go there, and get the byte that was copied.
到那里去，获取被复制的字节。
It's this size, which is going to be one, but I did it generally.
它的大小会是 1，但我用的是通用写法。
One bite at a time, please.
请一次写入一个字节。
And write it to the destination file.
把它写入目标文件。
So if I now open up my terminal window, let me first
所以如果我现在打开我的终端窗口，让我先
make CP to create my own copy program.
创建一个叫做 CP 的程序，用于复制文件。
Let me actually open an image I came with today.
让我打开一张我今天带来的图片。
Here's a happy cat from the internet.
这是一张来自互联网的快乐猫的图片。
And that's going to be my original image.
这将是我的原始图片。
Let me now go ahead and run this.
我现在开始运行它。
Dot slash CP.
./CP
I have to run dot slash because I want my version of CP,
我必须运行 ./CP，因为我想要使用我自己的 CP 版本，
not the one that comes with Linux.
而不是 Linux 自带的版本。
So dot slash CP, cat.jpeg, and let's call it maybe
所以 ./CP cat.jpeg，我们把它命名为
my backup cat, just in case I ever mess up the original.
my backup cat，以防万一我搞乱了原始文件。
Enter.
回车。
Seems to work OK.
看起来工作正常。
When I run now code of backup dot jpeg to open the copy,
我现在运行 backup.jpeg 的代码来打开副本，
there is that same happy cat.
里面是同一只快乐猫。
So it's very low level manipulation, but it all
所以，这是一种非常低级的操作，但这一切
results from my now having the power to express myself
都是因为我现在有了用指针在位置和内存中表达自己的能力，
in terms of locations and memory using pointers, understanding
理解了字符串和现在文件实际上只是这些低级细节之上的抽象概念。
that strings and now files are really just abstractions on top of these lower
从所有这些中，将产生一些非常强大的功能。
level details.
低级细节。
And from all of that is going to come some pretty powerful functionality.
实际上，正如你很快就会看到，你现在可以做的事情之一，
In fact, among the things that you can now do, as you'll soon see,
就是操纵至少简单的文件，被称为位图文件。
is manipulate at least simple files, known as bitmap files.
所以 BMP 是位图文件，它本质上实现了图像，就像我们今天开始的那样，
So BMP is bitmap file, and it essentially implements images exactly
只是一张位图，一个网格，网格的 xy 坐标，
as we began today, as just a map of bits, a grid, xy coordinates of grids,
每个都代表一个像素坐标。
each of which represents a pixel coordinate.
位图是一种文件类型，在计算机上具有点 BMP 文件扩展名
A bitmap is a type of file with a dot BMP file extension on a computer
用于存储图像，就像这样。
that stores images just like that.
现在，你不仅能够以这种方式思考图像，
And now that you have the ability to not only think about images in this way,
而且还能编写操作图像的代码，
but write code that manipulates images, you
你可以在 Instagram、TikTok 和 Snapchat 上做一些强大的事情，
can do powerful things all on Instagram, and TikTok, and Snapchat,
比如现在的滤镜。
like filters nowadays.
例如，这是一张桥的图片，
So for instance, here is an image of the bridge,
横跨河面的 Weeks 桥。
the Weeks Bridge across the river.
这是我们通过编写一些 C 代码应用的黑白滤镜，
Here is a black and white filter that we've applied by writing some C code,
就像你很快就会做到的那样，将它从彩色变成黑白。
as you soon will, to change it from colorful to black and white.
这是你可能每天都会看到的原始图片。
Here's the original that you might see every day.
同时，这是它的倒影。
Here, meanwhile, is a reflection thereof.
如果你曾经在 x 轴上翻转过一张图片，
If you've ever flipped an image around on the x-axis,
实际上它可以旋转图像，即使它是桥的另一侧。
this can actually rotate the image, even though this is the other side
同时，这是一个模糊的版本。
of the bridge over there.
如果看起来有点模糊，那是故意的，
Meanwhile, here is a blurred version.
因为我们基本上模糊了所有值，方法是查看每个像素，
If it looks a little blurry, that's deliberate
向上、向下、向左和向右看，然后模糊
because we've essentially smudged all of the values by looking at every pixel,
效果以获得这里的效果。
looking up, down, left, and right, and kind of blurring
这里称为边缘检测，即
the effect to give it this effect here.
如果你感觉更舒适，你可以
Here is what's called edge detection, whereby
编写查看这些单个像素的代码，
if you're feeling more comfortable, you can
尝试找出边缘在哪里，就像一台高级计算机一样，
write code that looks at these individual pixels,
然后以这种方式着色。
tries to figure out where the edges are, just like a fancy computer might,
你能够做到这一切，因为像这样的图像
and then colorize it in this way, as well.
只是一些具有大量像素的坐标网格。
And you'll be able to do all of that because images like these
所以，现在已经变得非常简单的事情，将成为你
are just grids with coordinates with lots and lots of pixels.
现在完全可以控制的东西，现在我们已经
So what started quite simply now is going to be something
摘掉了这些辅助轮。
you now have complete control over, now that we've
在计算机科学领域，
taken off these training wheels.
理解像这样的极客幽默是件很平常的事。
And it's cultural within computer science
所以，今天我们将做的最后一件事，就是给你
to understand geek humor like this.
留下这个笑话作为结束，无论好坏，现在都应该有意义了。
And so the last thing we'll do today is give you
.
this joke to end on, which for better or for worse, should now make sense.
And those chuckles will suffice.
这些笑声就足够了。
This was CS50.
这就是CS50。